<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 11:27:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A New Podcast: Bookworm]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-new-podcast-bookworm/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-new-podcast-bookworm/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Almost 2 months ago I embarked on a journey of reading a book every two weeks. Although there are a lot of personal benefits to doing this, it is primarily for a new podcast I’m doing with my good friend, Mike Schmitz.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Almost 2 months ago I embarked on a journey of reading a book every two weeks. Although there are a lot of personal benefits to doing this, it is primarily for a new podcast I’m doing with my good friend, <a href="http://mikeschmitz.me/">Mike Schmitz</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Mike and I have done a couple shows together in the past (<a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/podcast/057-joe-buhlig/">The Productivity Show</a> and <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/33/">Whaddya Know Joe</a>) and we each independently came to the conclusion that we wanted start a new show together. After a single call, Bookworm was born and recording commenced.</p>

<p>Bookworm is all about taking action on the words we read. Mike and I read a book, then talk about what it means for our lives. We can read all the books in the world but it’s for naught if we don’t do something with that knowledge.</p>

<p>Today we are revealing our work to the world. You can check it out it at <a href="http://bookworm.fm/">bookworm.fm</a> and find it <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/bookworm/id1132102092">on iTunes here</a>. We also have a Twitter handle for the show, <a href="https://twitter.com/bookwormfm">@bookwormfm</a>.</p>

<p>If you are a reader (or you’re not and want a summary), <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/bookworm/id1132102092">subscribe now</a>. We’re super pumped about it and excited to talk books with you!</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[My Podcasting Setup]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/my-podcasting-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[podcasting]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/my-podcasting-setup/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have detailed my writing process quite a bit lately, but that made me realize I have never pulled all the pieces of my podcasting setup together. Let’s change that.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/my-podcasting-setup.jpeg" /><p>I have detailed <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-science-and-experience-of-analog-writing/">my writing process</a> quite a bit lately, but that made me realize I have never pulled all the pieces of my podcasting setup together. Let’s change that.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="equipment">Equipment</h2>

<p>I did a lot of research on beginners microphones before I started podcasting and although there are better ones out there, I landed on the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-Podcaster-USB-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B000JM46FY/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Podcaster</a>. I have a dream of upgrading to a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Supercardioid-Condenser-Microphone-Applications/dp/B0002BACBO/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Beta 87</a> at some point, but this does a great job for now. Altogether here’s what I’m using:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-Podcaster-USB-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B000JM46FY/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Podcaster</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/RODE-Swivel-Mount-Studio-Microphone/dp/B001D7UYBO/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Boom Stand</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-PSM-1-Shockmount-Podcaster/dp/B000WA8KYG/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Shockmount</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SM6-Shock-Mount-Integrated-Shield/dp/B004DE1K5S/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Popfilter</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/V-MODA-Crossfade-Over-Ear-Noise-Isolating-Headphone/dp/B003BYRGLI/ref=sr_1_8?tag=joebuhlig-20">V-MODA Crossfade Headphones</a></li>
</ul>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/my-podcasting-setup/rode-podcaster.jpeg" /></p>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>I have been a subscriber to the <a href="http://www.adobe.com/creativecloud.html">Adobe Creative Cloud</a> for a while now and really enjoy the power of their tools. They aren’t for everyone, but if you have access to it <a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/audition.html">Audition CC</a> does a great job of editing and recording. When I’m recording with someone else, I use the traditional set of software that most podcasters use:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/audition.html">Adobe Audition CC</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://mutemymic.com/">MuteMyMic</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.skype.com/en/">Skype</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/">Skype Call Recorder</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="hosting">Hosting</h2>

<p>In my opinion, the gold standard for hosting your files is <a href="https://www.libsyn.com/">Libsyn</a>. It just works and I’ve never had an issue with them. My feed is a custom XML file generated with <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. If you are a Jekyll user and want to run a podcast, you can get the <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/Jekyll-Podcast-Feed">source code for this here</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Time For Books]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/time-for-books/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/time-for-books/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In order to read a book every two weeks (and sometimes every week) I have had to make reading a practice that is incorporated throughout my day. Having a single time for reading isn’t enough and it has become a ritual I like to incorporate as many places as I...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/time-for-books.jpeg" /><p>In order to read a book every two weeks (and sometimes every week) I have had to make reading a practice that is incorporated throughout my day. Having a single time for reading isn’t enough and it has become a ritual I like to incorporate as many places as I can.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Each day is different, but I know I can count on a handful of repeated situations that allow me to read consistently.</p>

<h2 id="early-mornings">Early Mornings</h2>

<p>Every morning, I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/why-getting-up-early/">get up at five</a>, grab a shower, and make a hot breakfast for myself. This early breakfast always consists of two eggs fried in a cast iron skillet and a banana. While the skillet is warming up and the eggs are cooking, I read. When they are finished cooking, I read while I eat. This is easily the most reliable time I have for reading. It’s a relaxed, ritualistic, and energizing time that is perfect for creating motivation for the day ahead.</p>

<h2 id="transitions">Transitions</h2>

<p>Whether it’s a few extra minutes before a meeting or a quick break between tasks, the transitional periods throughout the day serve as excellent times to grab a book. It may only be a single page, but one page here and there can add up quickly. The beauty of reclaiming these transitional times comes from what it replaces: social media and email checks. Instead of losing 10 minutes to cruising Twitter, I finish a chapter in my book.</p>

<h2 id="waiting">Waiting</h2>

<p>I have started taking a book with me whenever I leave the house. I’m early to most meetings and often find myself waiting for others to show up. Having a book with me means I can get a few more pages read instead of perusing blog articles or email on my phone.</p>

<h2 id="eob-ritual">EOB Ritual</h2>

<p>At the end of my workday, I go through an End Of Business ritual that helps me unwind and clear my head for spending time with my family. I have tried various tactics during this time, but I have found that learning is the best at hitting the brakes on my mental race car. And what better way to learn than to read? So I’ve made it a habit of reading for about 15 minutes before calling it a day.</p>

<h2 id="bedtime">Bedtime</h2>

<p>The least reliable of my reading times is likely the most consistent for others. I am sporadic at reading before bed, but it is another time that is easy to take advantage of and turn a few pages in a book.</p>

<h2 id="the-pattern">The Pattern?</h2>

<p>When I reflect on each of these scenarios I notice a recurring theme. In every instance, I have historically focused my eyes on a screen instead of a book. It’s easy to check my phone for a few minutes before bed or while I am eating breakfast. But if I pay attention to how I feel afterwards, I always prefer the feeling of accomplishment after having read a book to the feeling of inadequacy that comes from checking a screen.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[42: Deciding On A Medium]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/42/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[mediums]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/42/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[If you create content in any form and have dabbled in multiple mediums, you’re left with a decision about which method of consumption is best for the topic you want to present.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Deciding-On-A-Medium.jpg" /><p>If you create content in any form and have dabbled in multiple mediums, you’re left with a decision about which method of consumption is best for the topic you want to present.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">My Book - Working With OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://pre.workingwithideas.co">My Video Course - Working With Ideas</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Introducing Working With Ideas]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-working-with-ideas/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[course]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-working-with-ideas/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There are times when you realize a project needs to take a hard turn. Your original intent is good, but it doesn’t accomplish your goal as well as it might.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/introducing-working-with-ideas.jpeg" /><p>There are times when you realize a project needs to take a hard turn. Your original intent is good, but it doesn’t accomplish your goal as well as it might.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I find these moments bittersweet. They often result in something much better, but they also bring with them an extensive amount of rework. This was precisely my experience when I took on my second book, <em>Working With Ideas</em>.</p>

<p>I was working on the outline and collecting segments of content when I realized the medium for this content and its delivery system was wrong. It needed to reveal more emotion and story with more camaraderie than an e-book can provide. So I changed direction and turned it into a full video course with a community of idea workers to share the experience with.</p>

<p>I consider this my best work and I’m thrilled to share it with you. I’m so excited about it that I decided to make it possible to <a href="http://pre.workingwithideas.co">get the course for free</a>! To get started, you simply need to <a href="http://pre.workingwithideas.co">sign-up for the launch email</a> (which gets you $12 off by itself).</p>

<p>If you’re interested in learning more about the course, you can check it out here: <a href="https://workingwithideas.co">workingwithideas.co</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[An Open Letter To Productivity]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/an-open-letter-to-productivity/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/an-open-letter-to-productivity/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[My friend,

We’ve come a long way since we met five years ago.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/an-open-letter-to-productivity.jpeg" /><p>My friend,</p>

<p>We’ve come a long way since we met five years ago.<!--more--> And I cannot thank you enough for the clarity and direction you’ve given me through the multiple transitions and big decisions I have faced in recent years. Without the systems and tricks you’ve taught me, I would accomplish much less and fall short of numerous goals. For that, I am grateful.</p>

<p>I know I don’t always stick to the structure you’ve helped me build, but you’re always there when I realize I’ve stepped away. I know that if I trust the guidelines and follow them, my days are efficient and invigorating; and that makes me want to keep going and do more. It reveals my ability to do something great.</p>

<p>But sometimes I need space. I know you want me to be efficient with my calendar but there are periods when I need to blow some time with no expected outcomes. I need a little freedom. I need to be flexible and play once a while.</p>

<p>I think you would agree that margin is beneficial, but you often expect a measurable result when I take a break. I can understand that. We both know that taking time to re-energize can lead to greater gains elsewhere. But that’s my point: I can’t always look for the benefit of an activity. Why must everything have a defined positive outcome? Why not be content with the lack of definition and embrace spontaneity and play?</p>

<p>I want to continue our friendship, but with a different perspective. Let’s focus less on doing more and more on doing right. That likely means fewer projects, but I want them to be <em>better</em> projects. I know you’re with me here. But let’s also invite Play to our meetings. I’m aware of the love-hate relationship between you. Let’s work through that together. Between the three of us, I believe we can accomplish something awesome.</p>

<p>I’ll see you tomorrow.</p>

<p>Joe</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Reading Books On A Schedule]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/reading-books-on-a-schedule/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/reading-books-on-a-schedule/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[For years I have wanted to read more books. Prolific readers rave about the benefits and world-renowned leaders often attribute their ideas and successes to their habit of reading, but to me the benefits of having read a lot of books was secondary to the innate sense that a realm...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/reading-books-on-a-schedule.jpeg" /><p>For years I have wanted to read more books. Prolific readers rave about the benefits and world-renowned leaders often attribute their ideas and successes to their habit of reading, but to me the benefits of having read a lot of books  was secondary to the innate sense that a realm of knowledge and experience was available to me, but I was missing it.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Missing out on something is not inherently bad. It is actually a good thing in many cases. With firehoses of input available at every turn today, we need to decide to miss out on some things. And the more we can cut, the more head space and time we have to expand our minds and work towards our goals in life. I will be the first to say I am bad at this. Resisting the constant pull of potential updates is a war I fight daily.</p>

<p>In time, I have cut back on these overwhelming streams of unnecessary input, but I have only done so successfully with the addition of a replacement habit: reading books. Frankly, I don’t have the self-control to pick up a book instead of my phone when the “just check” bug bites. I rely on staged environmental circumstances to make it happen. I leave my phone out of reach and keep a book readily available. That helps significantly, but taking it another step, I have committed to completing a book every two weeks.</p>

<p>This accomplishes two things. One, I need to read a significant portion of a book each day to hit my mark. Two, it forces me to look for time to read in the day. The combination of these two means I do not have near the time for social media and email as I did previously and instead use that time for books.</p>

<p>But there is a flaw in this design that I discovered early on. My procrastination tendency leads me to back loading the two-week period with higher page counts. This is mostly due to not knowing if I am on track to hit my goal on a daily basis. It appears simple to take the number of pages in the book and divide by 14 to know how far to read each day. But after day three or four, I start to lose track and do not want to continue recalculating where I should be.</p>

<p>Each time I start a new book, I create a new OmniFocus project for it. I have a series of tasks I complete after finishing a book. Since this project already exists, I took it to another level and added a “Read Book” group with subtasks for each day’s reading. With that group flagged, I know what today’s expected page count is by looking at <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-omnifocus-dashboard/">my Dashboard</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/reading-books-on-a-schedule/read-book-group.png" /></p>

<p>But reading a book every two weeks means I create these tasks quite frequently. And you can’t expect me to do that manually every time, can you? A new script was in order.</p>

<p>When run, it asks four questions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>What is the title of the book?</li>
  <li>How many pages are in the book?</li>
  <li>When do you want to start reading?</li>
  <li>When do you want to finish reading?</li>
</ol>

<p>Using these answers, the script breaks the book into the correct number of tasks (one per day), each having the same number of pages to read. It adds these to my OmniFocus inbox so I can copy/paste or move them as I like. It programmatically adds @Read as a context, but the script can be altered as needed to fit your system. <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Read%20Book%20Tasks">This script</a> can be found in my <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts">OFScripts repository on GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>The result of this is a daily view of progress I need to make in order to hit my goal. Knowing the day’s goal forces me to make time and cut back on the less important, trivial actions.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[41: Fountain Pens]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/41/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/41/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m pushing pen addict status. I don’t think I’m there yet, but I do have three fountain pens that I thoroughly enjoy using.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Fountain-Pens.jpg" /><p>I’m pushing pen addict status. I don’t think I’m there yet, but I do have three fountain pens that I thoroughly enjoy using.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-science-and-experience-of-analog-writing/">The Science and Experience of Analog Writing</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Monteverde-Invincia-Chrome-Fountain-MV40065F/dp/B00691RCUK/ref=sr_1_3?tag=joebuhlig-20">Monteverde Invincia</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/">The Goulet Pen Company</a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.gouletpens.com/">Brian Goulet’s Blog</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCPdFDFTd6P1a__tAr8CrpCQ">Brian Goulet’s Videos</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lamy-Safari-Fountain-Extra-Charcoal/dp/B00W30C37S/ref=sr_1_3?tag=joebuhlig-20">Lamy Safari</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Collection-Fountain-91101/dp/B009M3PJFM/ref=sr_1_4?tag=joebuhlig-20">Pilot Metropolitan</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The Deception of Working on a System]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-deception-of-working-on-a-system/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[systems]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-deception-of-working-on-a-system/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It’s a trap so easy to fall for: we find ourselves spending multiple hours fine-tuning, tweaking, and developing the simple structure that will automatically create more time and 3X our daily productivity.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/the-deception-of-working-on-a-system.jpeg" /><p>It’s a trap so easy to fall for: we find ourselves spending multiple hours fine-tuning, tweaking, and developing the simple structure that will automatically create more time and 3X our daily productivity.
<!--more--></p>

<p>If you’re new to productivity or systems, then giving yourself a couple days to put these processes in place may pay off big and be well worth your time. Even if you’re a pro it can be helpful to make adjustments to how you do things with the intent of increasing efficiency, meaning, and output. I make tweaks to my structure frequently. But I need to remind myself of a lie that creeps up when I embark on one of these system alteration endeavors: <em>this is productive.</em></p>

<p>False. It is not productive. It is <em>meta-productive.</em> It feels productive because we are doing something that has meaning; this will make me a better, more efficient person. We are given a sense that we will be able to do more and live a better life, no matter how small the impact, in the future. But it doesn’t inherently make us more productive. It makes it possible, but it won’t make it happen on its own. It simply sets up the environment to be the best it can or should be for us to act on.</p>

<p>This is where the “meta” part comes in. We are completing tasks that allow us to complete tasks more efficiently or effectively. It’s one step removed from the real work to which we’ve committed.</p>

<p>But the deception here is the sense of accomplishment that comes after we have been <em>meta-productive</em>. We’ve done the work necessary to make us better in the future and that gives us the feeling that something important has been completed - even though we haven’t touched one important task the whole time. We get excited about this new or updated system because we’ve made the decisions that will help us accomplish something new or something big. But we haven’t taken an action on the thing itself.</p>

<p>Don’t fall for this feeling of completion after you’ve worked on a system. Don’t celebrate until you’ve worked on the items within it.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Analog Writing Organization]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/analog-writing-organization/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/analog-writing-organization/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When I made the decision to embrace pen and paper, the need for structure quickly showed its face. I wanted my writing to live in a single notebook, but that meant I needed a method of tracking progress on pieces without thumbing through the whole notebook.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/analog-writing-organization.jpeg" /><p>When I made the decision to <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-science-and-experience-of-analog-writing/">embrace pen and paper</a>, the need for structure quickly showed its face. I wanted my writing to live in a single notebook, but that meant I needed a method of tracking progress on pieces without thumbing through the whole notebook.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The logical conclusion here is an index which allows me to see each composition and the headway I’ve made. That progression consists of three steps which need to be incorporated in the indicator. First is the initial draft: the dump of the ideas at the onset. Second is the editing process of the first draft, and the final step is to transcribe the writing to the computer for one last look. Once it is moved from paper to screen, the tracking process is handled digitally.</p>

<p>In practice, this means I need a list of articles augmented with the location within the notebook and the progress I’ve made on it. A simple page number will do for the location, but I wanted an evolving indicator for the progress meter. And since there are only three states to track, I went for the slow build of a star: “/” → “X” → “*”.</p>

<p>When there is no indicator, I know I have made a commitment to the piece but haven’t started writing. The “/” tells me I’ve finished the first draft. The “X” tells me the editing process as been completed. And the final “*” is a picture of completion when the transcription is finished. Altogether, this is what it looks like:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/analog-writing-organization/index.jpeg" /></p>

<p>Now, I can take the first few pages of any notebook to create this index over the life of the notebook. I could also add page numbers to any grouping of paper I feel inclined to use. Throw on top of this my want for good fountain pen paper and I was certain I would need to hack together a custom notebook or make compromises. But that’s not the case.</p>

<p>I found the notebook, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;field-keywords=leuchtturm1917&amp;sprefix=leuchtturm1917%2Caps%2C166&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joebuhlig-20">Leuchtturm</a>, that has all of these features plus a few I didn’t realize I wanted. They have a built-in index as well as page numbers. It’s high-quality paper and has dual bookmark ribbons, one for finding my index and one for the last used page. There’s even a slot in the back that acts as an inbox while I’m out and stickers to help with archiving the notebook. I haven’t made a decision about keeping these when I fill it, but having the ability to easily do so and knowing the quality of the notebook makes me consider long-term storage of my hand-written words. Though storage space will likely make my decision for me.</p>

<p>I’ve chosen their <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Leuchtturm-Master-Notebook-Hardcover-Dotted/dp/B003ENUIKC?tag=joebuhlig-20">Master Dot Grid</a> notebook because it’s larger and keeps my pages clean. The bigger pages allow me to see more of the piece at one time and requires less page turning when dictating the words into a microphone. It also fits nicely into the computer slot in my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Cocoon-Innovations-Backpack-Laptop-MCP3401BK/dp/B00LBYTMOY?tag=joebuhlig-20">backpack</a> which is perfect for writing ventures away from the house. I’m a big fan of the Dot Grid paper because it limits the markings on the page yet gives me a bit of structure to keep my words in line.</p>

<p>If you’re looking to write by hand and need an organizational structure for your writing, take a look at Leuchtturm. Their notebooks fit perfectly.</p>

<p>Note: this article contains affiliate links, but this is <strong>not a sponsored post</strong>. I’m simply a big fan of Leuchtturm and have found their products exceptional to use.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[40: The Problem With Audiobooks]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/40/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/40/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I sometimes listen to books via audio but there are a couple flaws with audiobooks that have me avoiding them when I can.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-Problem-With-Audiobooks.jpg" /><p>I sometimes listen to books via audio but there are a couple flaws with audiobooks that have me avoiding them when I can.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The Overwhelm Inbox]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-overwhelm-inbox/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[inbox]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-overwhelm-inbox/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[The purpose of my inbox consolidation project is to cut back on the number of places I go to make decisions about my “open loops”. Between feeds, social media, and our always-on expectations, it becomes a habit and struggle to keep up with the mass of apps and information thrown...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/the-overwhelm-inbox.jpeg" /><p>The purpose of my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/inbox-consolidation/">inbox consolidation project</a> is to cut back on the number of places I go to make decisions about my “open loops”. Between feeds, social media, and our always-on expectations, it becomes a habit and struggle to keep up with the mass of apps and information thrown at us. My theory was to create an aggregated inbox via email that combines these potentially overwhelming sources of inputs. The hope was to build a system that helps me scale back on the time and impulse to repeatedly process these inboxes.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Using email as a base for this is the simplest solution since it can be connected to almost any service out there. Most systems already have an email notification system built-in. By turning these on, I go from repeatedly checking websites to see if anything is new to processing the important parts at a dedicated time. But not every source of new information has this ability. For me, the outstanding inputs are RSS feeds and social media.</p>

<p>For social media, I had to first be honest with myself. What do I really <em>need</em> to know about? I know that I <em>want</em> to keep up with more than I should so I’m immediately faced with scaling back. For the inputs that make the cut, I use <a href="https://ifttt.com">IFTTT</a> to send me an email about each item. For example, I have a rule that emails me when I am mentioned on Twitter:</p>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/view_embed_recipe/425773-send-twitter-mentions-to-email" target="_blank" class="embed_recipe embed_recipe-l_30" id="embed_recipe-425773"><img src="https://ifttt.com/recipe_embed_img/425773" alt="IFTTT Recipe: Send Twitter mentions to email connects twitter to gmail" width="370px" style="max-width:100%" /></a><script async="" type="text/javascript" src="//ifttt.com/assets/embed_recipe.js"></script></p>

<p>Another set of overwhelming inputs is the huge variety of articles that I want to read. It’s already a habit for me to send these to Pocket from any social media app or browser I’m using at the time. To funnel these from Pocket into my email, I’m again turning to IFTTT:</p>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/view_embed_recipe/425768-send-all-pocket-articles-to-email" target="_blank" class="embed_recipe embed_recipe-l_33" id="embed_recipe-425768"><img src="https://ifttt.com/recipe_embed_img/425768" alt="IFTTT Recipe: Send all Pocket articles to email connects pocket to gmail" width="370px" style="max-width:100%" /></a><script async="" type="text/javascript" src="//ifttt.com/assets/embed_recipe.js"></script></p>

<p>Now for the big one: RSS feeds. You can set up recipes to send new feed items to your email with IFTTT. However, I am subscribed to about 100 RSS feeds. That would require 100 recipes to make it work. No, thank you. Instead, I found a service (<a href="http://feed.informer.com">feed.informer.com</a>) that allows me to create a single RSS feed out of multiple feeds. In my case, I created two of these “digest” feeds that I then used in these recipes, which is a lot more comfortable. This has the added benefit of eliminating an app, Feedly, that I was previously using.</p>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/view_embed_recipe/425763-send-email-from-feed-digest" target="_blank" class="embed_recipe embed_recipe-l_27" id="embed_recipe-425763"><img src="https://ifttt.com/recipe_embed_img/425763" alt="IFTTT Recipe: Send email from feed digest connects feed to gmail" width="370px" style="max-width:100%" /></a><script async="" type="text/javascript" src="//ifttt.com/assets/embed_recipe.js"></script></p>

<p>Of course, it’s easy to see that this leads to a potentially enormous number of emails.  A fair amount of these can be deleted without opening them; I have everything I need to triage them in the subject line. But the key is to clear it out once daily. If I hold to that and avoid the temptation to check more often, I am given the freedom to spend more of my mental energy on important tasks. It also makes it easier to leave my phone somewhere other than my pocket or within reach at my desk.</p>

<p>The other, unintended, benefit of this has been visibility into the sheer volume of tiny bits of data that are available to us. We can easily consume thousands of pointless and potentially detrimental inputs that are better left unnoticed. Pulling all of these into one place provides a picture of information overwhelm that is catered specifically to you. I never realized how many sources of information I’ve tried to keep up with until now. It has led me to ruthlessly curate and cut back in ways I wish I had done sooner.</p>

<p>And as I expected, this is led me to change the purpose - and therefore layout - of my phone’s home screen for the better. But we’ll save that for another day:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-tiny" src="/assets/posts_extra/the-overwhelm-inbox/home_screen.png" /></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Editorial As A Database Viewer]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/editorial-as-a-database-viewer/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/editorial-as-a-database-viewer/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One habit that Evernote taught me was that of creating databases, collections of text and pictures that revolve around a specific topic or item. I’m yet to export my Evernote data into my alternative storage system but I have solved my most glaring issue: searching and viewing these databases on...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/editorial-as-a-database-viewer.jpeg" /><p>One habit that Evernote taught me was that of creating databases, collections of text and pictures that revolve around a specific topic or item. I’m yet to export my Evernote data into my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/">alternative storage system</a> but I have solved my most glaring issue: searching and viewing these databases on iOS.
<!--more--></p>

<p>These consist of three data types: text, documents, and pictures. All text is created in markdown files. The documents are primarily PDFs and the pictures are… well they’re pictures. All of these files have a very simple organizational structure in DropBox. There’s a folder named after the type of database (Drinks), a subfolder if necessary (Coffee), and then the files which are named after the item itself (Caribou Mahogany.jpg). If there are pictures, documents, <em>and</em> text for the same item, they’ll get the same name (but with different file extensions) to make it easy to search.</p>

<p>It’s a very basic structure, which makes it easy to find and interact with these different files from different apps on iOS. My app of choice for text files is <a href="http://omz-software.com/editorial/">Editorial</a>. There’s a lot of power in Editorial that I’ve never utilized but I do know that it’s excellent for editing and reading markdown.</p>

<p>I was typing out a few sentences for an article while waiting for a friend when I accidentally tapped the name for a PDF within Editorial. To my surprise, I was given the ability to “Quick Look” the document within the app. I am not sure why I never tried this before but it singlehandedly changed my methods for interacting with these databases from a multi-app approach to a single point of access.</p>

<p>This means that given a file structure that works for you and a text-heavy implementation of databases, Editorial can act as a user interface similar to these catchall tools like Evernote. Yes, there is the downside of not being able to capture documents and pictures directly into Editorial. The trick is to capture these into DropBox and let Editorial be the viewer instead. But since my databases are primarily text, I’m able to leverage the power of a tool that was designed extensively for text and maintain the majority of my editing needs. Add to that the ability to view the extra files I compile and iOS now has a database interface I didn’t know I wanted.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[39: Morning and Evening Rituals]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/39/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[rituals]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/39/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[What you do for your morning and evening rituals doesn’t have to match what others do. The top 10 things that highly successful people do in the morning may derail your day entirely.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Morning-and-Evening-Rituals.jpg" /><p>What you do for your morning and evening rituals doesn’t have to match what others do. The top 10 things that highly successful people do in the morning may derail your day entirely.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/routine-vs-ritual/">Routine vs. Ritual</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/why-getting-up-early/">The “Why” of Getting Up Early</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/what-to-review/">What To Review</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Checklists in OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/checklists-in-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/checklists-in-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Keeping different types of information in separate apps or systems is sometimes worth the extra infrastructure. But there is also a lot of value and mental freedom in using an existing process for multiple forms of data.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/checklists-in-omnifocus.jpeg" /><p>Keeping different types of information in separate apps or systems is sometimes worth the extra infrastructure. But there is also a lot of value and mental freedom in using an existing process for multiple forms of data.
<!--more--></p>

<p>When you have a tool as flexible and powerful as OmniFocus, it gets easier to combine needs into one database. That is why I originally <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">moved my Someday/Maybe lists</a> into OmniFocus. The simplicity of having a single place for active <em>and</em> potential tasks eliminated a bit of resistance to capturing an idea. This ease was also my rationale for moving my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/recurring-checklists-in-evernote/">checklists from Evernote</a> to OmniFocus.</p>

<p>There are a lot of ways to keep checklists in OmniFocus, but I keep the process as effortless as possible. I manage a single folder that holds all of them. I don’t have so many that I feel the need to subdivide them. They are all together in one list and each checklist has the same settings:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Parallel project set to “Complete when completing last action”</li>
  <li>Repeat set to Defer Again in one minute</li>
</ul>

<p>When I sit down to go through a checklist, I work from the project view so it doesn’t matter if the project is Parallel or Sequential. I see every item on the list regardless. My default for new projects is Parallel so I leave it alone. I want these to autocomplete and recreate themselves when everything is done; the repeat and completion settings make it happen.</p>

<p>I’ve used checklists for packing lists, payroll, and even rituals for quite a while. But during a recent Weekly Review I realized I was putting a handful of checklists elsewhere and treating them differently when I shouldn’t. The lists of steps for all my reviews has been living in my Guidance folder, so I flagged them to display on my Dashboard.</p>

<p>This is a prime example of how fluid a GTD system can be. It needs to fluctuate with how you work and morph as you learn about yourself. I very recently wrote about how I work with my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-omnifocus-dashboard/">OmniFocus Dashboard</a>. And here I am changing its purpose entirely. I realized I had abstracted and complicated these meta-lists unnecessarily. Yes, they are Guidance projects to complete at regular intervals, but those intervals are better placed on the calendar and the checklist put where they belong. By breaking them off into their own category, I was required to maintain another level of the structure. If I can simplify it and uphold my level of productivity while eliminating mental strain (no matter how small), why wouldn’t I reduce the complexity? This is especially true when the work required to pull it off is miniscule.</p>

<p>All of this is to say that I’ve moved my reviews into my checklists folder and pulled them from the Dashboard. I reserve time on my calendar for them and go through the list at that time. It cuts back on the automation going into my daily task list and gives me the freedom to put off a review for a few hours or days if I need to go heads down on a project. It also eliminates some of the overwhelm from seeing a Dashboard with 30+ items on it in the morning.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>