<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 14:15:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[10: Start With Why by Simon Sinek [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/10-start-with-why-by-simon-sinek/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/10-start-with-why-by-simon-sinek/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[This week Mike and Joe talk about the value of finding a “why” in everything we do and what happens when companies start with “how” or “what.”
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>This week Mike and Joe talk about the value of finding a “why” in everything we do and what happens when companies start with “how” or “what.”
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Targeted OmniFocus Templates With Workflow]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/targeted-omnifocus-templates-with-workflow/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/targeted-omnifocus-templates-with-workflow/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve been impressed by the speed of the Omni Group’s release cycles lately. It’s obvious they are hard at work on the automation methods for both iOS and macOS. One of these recent releases introduced the ability to create new projects within a specific folder on iOS.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/targeted-omnifocus-templates-with-workflow.jpg" /><p>I’ve been impressed by the speed of the Omni Group’s release cycles lately. It’s obvious they are hard at work on the automation methods for both iOS and macOS. One of these recent releases introduced the ability to create new projects within a specific folder on iOS.
<!--more--></p>

<p>It’s pretty straight-forward. You use the <code class="highlighter-rouge">/paste</code> URL as before but replace <code class="highlighter-rouge">target=projects</code> with <code class="highlighter-rouge">target=/folder/FOLDERNAME</code>, so you now get something like this:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">omnifocus:///paste?target=/folder/Articles&amp;content=TASKPAPERCONTENT</code></p>

<p>This opens a lot of doors, but I prefer to keep things simple by using a single Workflow. This new Workflow takes a text file in DropBox (containing a taskpaper template), replaces any placeholders (using this format: <code class="highlighter-rouge">«PLACEHOLDER»</code>), and places the new project in the folder you choose from the menu.</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/86f951099b6d40fcacfe7b0e4ab41d65">get this Workflow here</a>.</p>

<p>If you look through the steps, you’ll see an action that looks like this:</p>

<center><img class="post-image-mini" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/targeted-omnifocus-templates-with-workflow/workflow-targets.png" /></center>

<p>These are the selectable targets in the Workflow. You’ll want to alter these to fit your structure. Just pay attention to the text and variable assignment under each choice and be sure to copy that format.</p>

<p>In the end, this allows me to pinpoint where I want my templated projects to land within OmniFocus without needing to manually move it after creation.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using Gmail Permalinks [Video]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gmail-permalinks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[video]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[email]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gmail-permalinks/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Earlier this week, I published an article eluding to my use of Gmail’s permalinks. It sparked a number of unexpected questions about how to get them and how I use them on both macOS and iOS. But rather than write it out, I figured a screencast would help convey the...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/using-gmail-permalinks.jpg" /><p>Earlier this week, I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/forget-third-party-email-apps/">published an article</a> eluding to my use of Gmail’s permalinks. It sparked a number of unexpected questions about how to get them and how I use them on both macOS and iOS. But rather than write it out, I figured a screencast would help convey the process better.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Here are the Workflows I mentioned in the video:</p>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/171d34ef202843ec9882f1cb9fcb6858">Open Gmail Permalink on iOS - Workflow</a></p>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/3295578bd1564f388ff52d5ca1835418">My Altered Workflow</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Forget Third Party Email Apps]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/forget-third-party-email-apps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[email]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/forget-third-party-email-apps/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Folks are quite passionate about the software they use to access their email. I fell in that camp for a while but anymore I just don’t get it. I think that stems from my intent to touch emails only once, keep my inbox as empty as possible, and use a...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/forget-third-party-email-apps.jpeg" /><p>Folks are quite passionate about the software they use to access their email. I fell in that camp for a while but anymore I just don’t get it. I think that stems from my intent to touch emails only once, keep my inbox as empty as possible, and use a single archive folder for all emails I want to keep.
<!--more--></p>

<p>My needs in an email app are just as simple. I need an easy way to move an email to either an archive or the trash. That’s it. And since there’s an internet connection and a Mac with me 99.9% of the times I check email, I do all of it in the browser with Gmail.</p>

<p>That means I have no need for integrations with other apps because I always have a URL to reference an email. I can always grab the link, drop it into a notes field, or save it as part of a reference document. It also means the email is always a click away.</p>

<p>I have no need for fancy folder structures and snoozing mechanisms. They don’t make sense to me. It’s an extra layer of complexity and decision deferment that delays progress on the requests represented in the emails. I don’t want to postpone my action on it for later, I make the decision the first time I see it.</p>

<p>When I read reviews or hear comparisons of new email apps, I’m usually left asking “why?” Why are all these extra features necessary? Why is everyone trying to solve the “email problem?” The extra bells and whistles won’t make your decisions for you. It won’t write your responses for you. That’s up to you.</p>

<p>We all get email. Some of us get a lot more than others. And if you feel you have an email problem, <em>you</em> need to do something about it. The issue isn’t the app. Don’t complicate matters looking for a third party app. Keep it dead simple and own your decisions. You’ll feel a lot better in the end.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Building Systems You Won't Use]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/building-systems-you-wont-use/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[systems]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/building-systems-you-wont-use/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m always looking for a way to automate a process or develop a structure that removes steps from a frequently repeated task. That’s to be expected since I enjoy the world of productivity and do a fair amount of development.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/building-systems-you-wont-use.jpeg" /><p>I’m always looking for a way to automate a process or develop a structure that removes steps from a frequently repeated task. That’s to be expected since I enjoy the world of productivity and do a fair amount of development.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But building new systems to increase efficiency and accomplish new actions used to be relegated to the Mac or PC. You can write scripts and code there that do really sophisticated tasks. The only limit is your imagination and time devoted to it.</p>

<p>With the creation of apps such as <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/workflow-powerful-automation/id915249334?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">Workflow</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/launch-center-pro-shortcut/id532016360?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">Launch Center Pro</a>, and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/editorial/id673907758?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">Editorial</a>, the system building process has more or less made its way onto iOS. And I leverage these heavily in my daily iPhone use.</p>

<p>Although this ability comes with a plethora of benefits, it also comes with a very large downside: <em>time consumption</em>.</p>

<p>My general rule of thumb for development and systems building is “if you can think it, you can build it.” If you have an idea for a script or a new system, you can generally make it happen given enough time and resources. Yes, there are occasions that this assumption falls down, but in my experience it generally holds true.</p>

<p>If you combine this assumption with the flexibility, ease, and novelty of an app like Workflow, it’s easy to find yourself looking for ways to use it. “It has so much power, I should use it for <strong>__</strong><em>__</em>.” And new workflows are fun to build, so you get to “work” on a new process that will help you later.</p>

<p>The trouble is that it’s time-consuming to build these new systems and since we utilize an app just because we can, we end up building things that serve no real purpose in our daily activities. It’s cool that you can turn a series of pictures into a GIF but how often do you need to do that? Is it really necessary to spend time building these out if you’re only going to use it a couple times, if ever?</p>

<p>My point is this: don’t waste time building new systems just because you can or you think there might be a use for it. Determine the need up front and then get to work. Make sure it has a necessary and legitimate use before you spend time creating it.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[9: Daring Greatly by Brené Brown [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/9-daring-greatly-by-brene-brown/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/9-daring-greatly-by-brene-brown/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re trying a different flavor of book this time and discussing our relationships and feelings with Brené Brown’s Daring Greatly.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>We’re trying a different flavor of book this time and discussing our relationships and feelings with Brené Brown’s Daring Greatly.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Creating Drafts Actions In Bulk]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[drafts]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When the Omni Group implemented the new automation methods in OmniFocus for iOS, I was both excited and worried. I had over 30 actions in Drafts that send text to OmniFocus using background emails as an action method. Switching all of those to use URLs was going to take some...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk.jpeg" /><p>When the Omni Group implemented the new <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/implementation-details-for-omnifocus-2-14-automation/24179?u=joebuhlig">automation methods in OmniFocus for iOS</a>, I was both excited and worried. I had over 30 actions in Drafts that send text to OmniFocus using background emails as an action method. Switching all of those to use URLs was going to take some time.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But then I remembered Drafts has its own URL scheme that allows you to import actions. So I embarked on a journey to create my 30+ actions in bulk. I likely spent more time working this out than it would have taken me to just edit each one by hand, but now I have a trick to share with you. You’re welcome.</p>

<h2 id="manually-create-a-template">1. Manually create a template</h2>

<p>You first need a template to work with. Create one action that the rest of your actions will be modeled after. In my case, it looked like this:</p>

<p><img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/template.png" />
<img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/template-steps.png" />
<img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/template-url-step.png" /></p>

<h2 id="copy-the-action">2. Copy the action</h2>

<p>After your template action has been created, open it up and use the Share Sheet to copy it. This copies the import action URL for the Drafts action that we’ll dissect.</p>

<center><img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/template-share-button.png" />
<img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/template-share-sheet.png" /></center>

<p>Here’s a paste of this action so you get an idea of what you should see:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">x-drafts4://x-callback-url/import_action?v=2&amp;tintColor=%5B%0A%20%200.451,%0A%20%200.29,%0A%20%200.553%0A%5D&amp;shouldConfirm=0&amp;logLevel=1&amp;uuid=0E3E5B59-15B5-4010-8E8C-C9A69EE0CA88&amp;disposition=2&amp;actionSteps=%5B%0A%20%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%22actionStepType%22%20:%20%22URL%22,%0A%20%20%20%20%22urlTemplate%22%20:%20%22omnifocus:%5C/%5C/x-callback-url%5C/add?x-success=drafts4:%5C/%5C/&amp;name=%5B%5Btitle%5D%5D&amp;note=%5B%5Bbody%5D%5D&amp;project=Bulk%20Actions%20Template&amp;context=Running&amp;autosave=true%22,%0A%20%20%20%20%22useSafariViewController%22%20:%20false,%0A%20%20%20%20%22encodeTags%22%20:%20true%0A%20%20%7D%0A%5D&amp;description=&amp;modifiedAt=2016-09-07%2012:02:42%20+0000&amp;name=Bulk%20Actions%20Template&amp;iconImageName=429-checkmark2</code></p>

<h2 id="transfer-to-numbers-or-excel">3. Transfer to Numbers or Excel</h2>

<p>You need to get this copied URL into a spreadsheet. I did mine on the Mac so I also needed to transfer it across devices. We’ll use the spreadsheet to create new URLs in bulk.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/spreadsheet.png" alt="Spreadsheet" /></p>

<h2 id="create-a-list-of-new-actions">4. Create a list of new actions</h2>

<p>You need a list of the new actions. Specifically, you need a list of the text that changes in the URLs. This will be used to create the new import links.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/spreadsheet-list.png" alt="Spreadsheet List" /></p>

<h2 id="break-up-the-url-template">5. Break up the URL template</h2>

<p>This really depends on the complexity of your Drafts actions but you need to look through your URL template and break it into the pieces that stay the same across all the new links. You want to remove the text that changes and keep the remaining pieces in separate cells in the spreadsheet. This makes our lives much simpler when we start putting it all back together.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/spreadsheet-url-breakup.png" alt="Spreadsheet Breakup" /></p>

<h2 id="format-the-replacement-text">6. Format the replacement text</h2>

<p>In my case, the URL template used a project name that matched the name of the action. So I created one format to the right of my list that handles both cases. Just pay attention to how your template looks and make sure your new text matches the original format.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/spreadsheet-substitute.png" alt="Spreadsheet Substitute" /></p>

<h2 id="create-the-new-urls">7. Create the new URLs</h2>

<p>Once the template is broken apart and the replacement text has been formatted, we can concatenate all the pieces back together to create our new URLs.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/spreadsheet-new-urls.png" alt="Spreadsheet New URLs" /></p>

<h2 id="transfer-to-ios-and-import">8. Transfer to iOS and import</h2>

<p>Select all those new URLs, copy them, and transfer them to iOS. I just pasted them into a text file that syncs via DropBox and opened it in Editorial. Then it’s just a matter of tapping the link to add each action to Drafts.</p>

<center><img class="post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-drafts-actions-in-bulk/editorial.png" /></center>

<p>I’ll admit this isn’t a clean process, but it gets the job done. And for the spreadsheet wizards, I’m aware that there are more unified ways of creating the new URLs. But if you know those methods, you likely don’t need this tutorial.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[When Deep Work Strikes]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/when-deep-work-strikes/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/when-deep-work-strikes/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There are a plethora of articles promoting and dissecting the tenants and principles proposed by Cal Newport in his book, Deep Work. That’s what led me to picking it for an episode of Bookworm. After implementing my takeaways for about a month, I can see a decided difference in my...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/when-deep-work-strikes.jpeg" /><p>There are a plethora of articles promoting and dissecting the tenants and principles proposed by Cal Newport in his book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Work-Focused-Success-Distracted/dp/1455586692/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Deep Work</a>. That’s what led me to picking it for an <a href="http://bookworm.fm/7/">episode of Bookworm</a>. After implementing my takeaways for about a month, I can see a decided difference in my productivity and effectiveness. It’s what allowed me to release <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">Working With OmniFocus</a> when I did and to develop the depth of detail in those videos.
<!--more--></p>

<p>If you haven’t read Deep Work, I will join the crowds in saying you should. It can change your methods of working and make you rethink the importance of the internet. In my case, it led to alterations in many core routines and habits I maintain.</p>

<p>The biggest change I have successfully implemented is a simple <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/contact">contact form</a> over a blanket email address on this website. Over time I had begun receiving hundreds of emails each day. It’s not possible to keep up with that kind of volume. And as Newport points out, email rarely produces a meaningful result. By putting systems in place to help me cut back on email received and removing expectations that I’ll respond to every one of them, I take back more of my time and free myself to focus on essential projects. Email is still important, but it’s not worth sacrificing my mission in life to answer the requests of others.</p>

<p>Newport talks about the value of a shutdown ritual, which is a way of closing off the work of today, preparing for tomorrow, and transitioning from work to family. I’ve experimented with an “End of Business” ritual before but I have always struggled getting it to stick. Reading Deep Work made me dust off my old checklist and give it another try. The clarity that comes when I follow through with this ritual makes me wonder why it was so hard to make this a habit in the past. I can only assume that a difference in perspective and season of life makes me see a greater value in closing off the day and intentionally shutting down my work mode.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/when-deep-work-strikes/shutdown-ritual.jpg" alt="Shutdown Ritual" /></p>

<p>Easily one of the most valuable action items you can take from the book is scheduling deep work sessions: time when you disconnect from all external inputs and focus on the one task in front of you. This is time spent unplugged and head down on a creative or critical project. And it is paramount that you keep the internet at bay. Its ability to send you down rabbit trails is uncanny and detrimental to the work that matters. To help combat the allure of infinity apps and their addictive tendencies, Newport suggests scheduling time for going online.</p>

<p>On the surface, I love this concept. Only allowing a set amount of time for the web forces you to be intentional with that time and see it as a tool with a purpose. But in practice, it’s been extremely challenging to even put a plan together. I know there are benefits on the other side, but my business is online. It feels irresponsible to limit that time. But taking a cue from <a href="http://www.becomingminimalist.com/">Joshua Becker</a>, I think I’ll have to pick a day and experiment with less time online. My anxiety is likely an indicator of the importance of trying.</p>

<p>To help with this trial, I reviewed a topic on the Discussion site by <a href="http://www.jayblanco.com/">Jay Blanco</a> about <a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/setting-up-your-phone-for-deep-work/245?u=joebuhlig">setting up a deep work phone</a>. The thoughts shared there and my own reflections on the internet-as-a-tool mentality have led me to turning off cellular data and Wi-Fi on my phone.</p>

<p>Deep Work has lead to great progress on projects with a lot of value. I have some ground to cover yet, but the simple understanding of how to engage in deep work and suppress the time and energy devoted to shallow work has exponential benefits over my normal methods of getting things done.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Introducing The New Working With OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Working With OmniFocus has been recreated in video format!  It’s now available on the new dedicated website: workingwithomnifocus.com.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus.jpg" /><p>Working With OmniFocus has been recreated in video format!  It’s now available on the new dedicated website: <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">workingwithomnifocus.com</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Something I didn’t plan on with this project was the expansion of content. By the time I finished the set of videos, I realized there are over four hours of content and an additional 40% in topics covered over the book. And I already have another hour worth of topics in the queue. So it’s easy to say that this is a pretty extensive resource and I’m really excited to share it with you!</p>

<p>Quick note: if you’ve previously purchased the book, check your email. There’s a present waiting for you there. If you haven’t bought the book, you can still get it as part of the video series. I’m keeping it simple and throwing it all into one package.</p>

<p>Go check out <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">the new website</a>! There are a handful of freebies there even if you’re not planning to buy.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[8: The Power of Full Engagement by Jim Loehr, Tony Schwartz [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/8-the-power-of-full-engagement-by-jim-loehr-tony-schwartz/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/8-the-power-of-full-engagement-by-jim-loehr-tony-schwartz/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When you step out beyond time management you land in the world of energy management. It’s a simple concept that is drastically different for everyone embarking on the journey.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>When you step out beyond time management you land in the world of energy management. It’s a simple concept that is drastically different for everyone embarking on the journey.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[7: Deep Work by Cal Newport [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/7-deep-work-by-cal-newport/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/7-deep-work-by-cal-newport/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Mike has a new Apple device despite his minimizing efforts and Joe has finally done something about his email issue.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Mike has a new Apple device despite his minimizing efforts and Joe has finally done something about his email issue.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Year Without Extra Screens]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-year-without-extra-screens/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-year-without-extra-screens/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[For the last year I’ve been running my business from a MacBook Pro  and an iPhone.  No iPad. No Watch. And no external monitors.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/a-year-without-extra-screens.jpeg" /><p>For the last year I’ve been running my business from a MacBook Pro  and an iPhone.  No iPad. No Watch. And no external monitors.
<!--more--></p>

<p>This started out of necessity. I had jumped into bootstrapping my business quicker than I wanted and knew I shouldn’t spend extra dollars on unnecessary gadgets. So I took on the bare essentials.</p>

<p>At first, this was painful. I had done development and data analysis work for quite a while and had been able to use iPads and at least three monitors for years. I could easily argue the validity of multiple monitors for someone doing my line of work. To go from three 27” Thunderbolts and an always-on iPad at my desk to nothing more than a MacBook Pro screen was not fun.</p>

<p>To be honest, the freelance development and online business world isn’t all roses and rainbows. I haven’t felt comfortable spending extra dollars on a nice-to-have that isn’t necessary for me to do my job. So I’ve spent the last year working with the same minimal setup I started with.</p>

<p>Despite the wounds this inflicted at the onset, I’ve discovered some unexpected benefits and learnings from this unwanted experiment. I can’t say everyone will experience these and frankly some will say these are illogical conclusions. Regardless, my feelings on the topic remain.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Multiple screens don’t increase productivity.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>When forced to work from a single, small screen, you find ways to make the process as easy as possible. Instead of designating apps to specific locations on a specific screen, I found a <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/mac-navigation/">way to quickly switch</a> to a screen filling view of an app. With a single keyboard shortcut, I jump from program to program. But that means my need to see multiple things at once is no longer necessary because I can switch about as fast as my eyes can move to another screen and back.</p>

<p>The other aspect at work here is pure willpower to focus. Multiple screens increase the speed at which I can be distracted. Even if the distraction is productive, it still takes me away from my intended task. A single screen forces me to look at the application and task in front of me. I have to make a conscious decision to navigate elsewhere.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Device overlap is detrimental to focus.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>When I owned an iPad, it served two purposes. It was used to read articles and watch videos and it became a dashboard for my task list, outline, or reference material. Without it, I read articles and watch videos on my phone or Mac. But honestly, I do this very little anymore. And from what I can tell, I’m better off scaling this back even further.</p>

<p>The lack of the dashboard has been a different story. It was a big loss initially since I’ve been using an iPad that way for three years or better. I struggled to find an alternative. As expected, I eventually found a combination of tools and techniques to simulate what I was doing previously. But what surprised me was the fact that my “new” methods were already in place. I had been switching between the iPad and my iPhone for a task list. My outlines and references were a shortcut away on the Mac. I had been duplicating the main purpose of the iPad on the Mac and iPhone already.</p>

<p>It’s tricky, but I found there was a split in focus when there were options about which device to use. Because I could choose between devices for a given task, I would have to make an extra decision (iPad or Mac?) about the right one in the moment. Remove the decision (the extra device) and I can get to work quicker and, in most cases, more effectively. Without the choice and the potential overlap in devices, I’m free to focus on the task itself instead of asking which device to use for the task.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Owning every Apple device isn’t logical.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ll say it. I’m an Apple fanboy. Every product with an Apple logo has me looking for an excuse to own it. But each time I consider one, I’ve had to ask myself, “What does this enable me to do that I can’t already do and need to do?”” It’s the last piece of that question that always throws me off. There’s a lot of new and shiny with Apple products, but at the end of the day, I’ve learned that it takes only a couple of them to do what I need and to do it well.</p>

<p>All that said, there are changes I would make and I <em>would</em> increase my screen count by one. But I would only do so in the realm of Macs. Given my work in audio/video lately, I would put in either an iMac or a Mac Pro with a single, large monitor. I’m unsure of the exact hardware needs at the moment. But to allow travel, I would pick up a new MacBook. I can do a light weight machine for this, since it only needs to do email and raw text when I’m away from my office. I wouldn’t buy an iPad and I wouldn’t go for more than a single monitor for the Mac.</p>

<p>When will this happen? I don’t know. But learning how to work with so little has taught me where I want to go.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Information Overwhelm Without The Internet]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I hear people refer to information overwhelm more often than I would expect. The context varies but the idea is the same: finding information on the internet is so easy that the person has a hard time deciphering what is right and what to question. Some even take it as...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet.jpeg" /><p>I hear people refer to information overwhelm more often than I would expect. The context varies but the idea is the same: finding information on the internet is so easy that the person has a hard time deciphering what is right and what to question. Some even take it as far as to suggest <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2008/07/is-google-making-us-stupid/306868/">Google is making us dumb</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The validity of that statement and my opinion of it aren’t important for the context of this article. What is important is the cause of the overwhelm: a broad range of topics at our fingertips. Type a word into any web search tool and you are hit with page after page of words to consume. It boggles your mind when you try to comprehend the complexity of the systems behind the interface that deliver those search results.</p>

<p>And regardless of your opinion on the effects this has on our brains, it’s safe to say that most of the results are surface level articles. In other words, the vast majority of the internet articles out there will focus on the introduction of a topic or dive deep into one small aspect of a broader discipline. When combined and reviewed collectively, it’s possible to ascertain expert levels of knowledge about a given search. But more often than not, it requires a great deal of time and experience in scouring the web to develop that level of expertise from search results.</p>

<p>In most cases, we aren’t going to take the time necessary to understand a topic fully. We would rather skim the headlines we find, get our answer, and move on. This is where the traditional sense of information overwhelm comes in. There are so many potential solutions to our query that we have difficulty discerning which trail to follow. It’s overwhelm due to a wide variety of topics made available to you.</p>

<p>But I’ve recently discovered a different type of overwhelm. Instead of this <em>broad topics overwhelm</em>, there’s also <em>deep topic overwhelm</em>. Both flavors come with two constraints: a lot of information going into your mind in a short time frame. With the broad form, we see a variety of subjects available to us through systems like Google. But the deep form flips the equation and gives us a ton of detail about a single realm of knowledge. In my case, this is revealed through the rapid consumption of business and productivity books.</p>

<p>You could make the argument that given wisdom in writing queries you could create a list of search results that would emulate deep topic overwhelm. But again, you will be presented with a series of webpages that would need to be reviewed collectively and digested over a longer period of time. At that point you no longer fall into the constraint of a short time period, whereas reading multiple longform works on a single subject in short succession does.</p>

<p>A prime example of this difference is the book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity/dp/0143126563/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Getting Things Done</a>. There are countless people, myself included, who discovered the GTD framework through searches and failed to implement it successfully until they broke down and actually read the book. Despite the thousands of articles out there about GTD and, in my case, months of reading them, you’ll never reach a level of full understanding until you read the book.</p>

<p>But if you read a lot of these types of books in a short time, you’ll quickly start to feel this deep topic overwhelm. There’s so much information and an incomprehensible level of rationale behind each author’s arguments that you can’t help but notice numerous aspects of your life and work that you want to change or develop. You have loads of data entering your mind that you want to act on and feel like you can’t keep up.</p>

<p>The logical response is to slow down. Give yourself time to process and adapt. In my case, that’s not possible since my quick reading is a part of <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a>. But I’m convinced I would continue my biweekly pace even without the podcast and accountability. There are two reasons for this:</p>

<p>One, <strong>I’m able to draw correlations and similarities I wouldn’t otherwise have seen</strong>. Given the short timeframe that I consume these books within, I have found that I still have a deep recollection of the last seven to ten that I’ve read. The book I am currently reading ends up being colored by what I’ve learned across thousands of pages I am still intimately familiar with. I find connections across multiple texts that I would normally miss.</p>

<p>Second, <strong>the new information I’m learning becomes motivation to keep moving forward with action items and deepens my rationale for what I’ve learned</strong>. Reading a thought-out reasoning for an author’s belief will encourage you to either develop your own perspective or challenge you to reconsider your existing view. In both cases, you come out better on the other side.</p>

<p>When you have the ability to be both broadly overwhelmed and deeply overwhelmed, through the internet or through books, you can choose between two responses: you can wait to learn until you need a piece of information, or you can take advantage of your good fortune and learn as much as possible right now. I’ll take the latter.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Woodworking Versus Websites]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/woodworking-versus-websites/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[woodworking]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/woodworking-versus-websites/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One of the most difficult aspects of building websites or doing knowledge work full-time is the lack of motivation and pride that typically comes from physically seeing the work of your hands. Yes, it is possible to achieve this sense of accomplishment when working purely with information and computers, but...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/woodworking-versus-websites.jpeg" /><p>One of the most difficult aspects of building websites or doing knowledge work full-time is the lack of motivation and pride that typically comes from physically seeing the work of your hands. Yes, it is possible to achieve this sense of accomplishment when working purely with information and computers, but it’s far from natural.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Looking at my own life, I compare it to woodworking. When I build a piece of furniture I rarely need a to-do list for it. And (given available time) I don’t struggle with getting to work on it like I do a bug-fix. I know that I can go to the woodshop, see my current progress, immediately determine what comes next, and get to work. And when I’m done, there is a innate joy that comes from having built the piece or at least made progress on it.</p>

<p>But when it comes to websites, it’s a different story. I need a list to know where I left off. And I have to develop tricks and rituals to motivate me to get to work. Even after I’m done with the build I need to reflect on my work and put it in perspective to understand its value and develop pride in my work.</p>

<p>The weird part of this is that I really enjoy both. But I do think there’s value in understanding the feelings and mechanics that come with working as a craftsman. If they can be applied to knowledge work, I think there is a drive and enjoyment we can achieve that has typically been reserved for those working with their hands.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Moving OmniFocus Scripts To iOS]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[applescripts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have been hesitant to adopt the new automation methods in OmniFocus for iOS. The abilities of the new URL Scheme are exciting but there’s still quite a bit missing from the structure as it stands.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios.jpeg" /><p>I have been hesitant to adopt the <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/implementation-details-for-omnifocus-2-14-automation/24179?u=joebuhlig">new automation methods in OmniFocus</a> for iOS. The abilities of the new URL Scheme are exciting but there’s still quite a bit missing from the structure as it stands.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The main piece I found missing was the “autosave” parameter to the <code class="highlighter-rouge">/add</code> URL. My current structure uses the <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Auto-Parser">Auto-Parser</a> which allows Drafts to send tasks to the app without the need to confirm or edit an item. Thankfully, the Omni Group introduced this feature recently and I can now add items directly to OmniFocus on iOS and come back to Drafts without any extra steps. Here’s the URL I’m using to add new Blog Post Ideas:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">omnifocus://x-callback-url/add?x-success=drafts4://&amp;name=[[title]]&amp;note=[[body]]&amp;project=Blog%20Post%20Ideas&amp;context=Running&amp;autosave=true</code></p>

<p>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">/paste</code> URL is a different story. Combined with Editorial or Workflow, this thing is awesome! It allows me to port two of the AppleScripts I use over to iOS.</p>

<p>The obvious one here is templates. <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/automation-in-omnifocus-2-14-released-2016-04-26/23985?u=joebuhlig">Ken Case shared an Editorial workflow</a> that takes a template project in Taskpaper format and adds it to OmniFocus. I’m using his workflow unedited and found it really easy to recreate my templates on iOS. Navigate to the project you want to use as a template, tap the Share button, and copy it. In Editorial I simply pasted the project into a new Taskpaper file and I’m set. All I have to do is open the template and run the workflow.</p>

<p>The other script I moved over was the <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/reading-books-on-a-schedule/">“Read Book Tasks” script</a>. This was a complete rebuild of the code in Workflow. Using it on iOS is the same as running the script on a Mac. Run the workflow, answer the prompts, and you get a sub-project for the tasks added to your inbox.</p>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/cece509a6fd6477d8d9e479f3f5df184">OF Book Tasks - Workflow</a></p>

<p>Everything above is about creating new tasks. In the world of data, we often refer to CRUD - Create, Read, Update, Delete. It’s shorthand for the four ways you can work with information. You can make new data - Create. You can get existing data - Read. You can change or edit existing data - Update. And you can destroy the data - Delete. If you have the ability to do all four of these, you are able to do anything you want with the database.</p>

<p>If we overlay those four methods on top of the new OmniFocus URLs, we see only the first (Create) as a possibility. So we’re still limited in what we can do on iOS. It’s also why I’m not able to move <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts">all of my scripts</a> to iOS. It simply isn’t possible. Given the support for AppleScripting that the Omni Group shows, I can imagine it is only a matter of time before the RUD of CRUD makes it to iOS.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>