<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 19:49:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[32: Doing the Task Shuffle]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/32/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[task-management]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/32/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Here’s an update on the new TextExpander pricing and a deep dive into why I wrote a script that shuffles my tasks. That’s right. There’s a big benefit to randomizing a task list.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Doing-the-Task-Shuffle.jpg" /><p>Here’s an update on the new TextExpander pricing and a deep dive into why I wrote a script that shuffles my tasks. That’s right. There’s a big benefit to randomizing a task list.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://smilesoftware.com/textexpander/entry/textexpander-adjustments">TextExpander Adjustments - Smile</a></p>

<p><a href="https://sivers.org/now">What I’m doing now - Derek Sivers</a></p>

<p><a href="http://now.joebuhlig.com">Now - Joe Buhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.relay.fm/mpu/314">Mac Power Users #314: Trials and Tribulations of Katie’s iPad - Relay FM</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Task%20Shuffle">OFScripts - Task Shuffle AppleScript</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The Important (Not Urgent) Projects]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-important-not-urgent-projects/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[projects]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-important-not-urgent-projects/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We all have those projects that we know we should be working on, but without a deadline or someone relying on you it’s hard to keep it going. Things come up and the easy tasks to put off are the ones without urgency pushing them on.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-important-not-urgent-projects.jpg" /><p>We all have those projects that we <em>know</em> we should be working on, but without a deadline or someone relying on you it’s hard to keep it going. Things come up and the easy tasks to put off are the ones without urgency pushing them on.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I have a tendency to pick up a shiny new project and set aside the projects that move me toward my longer term goals. It’s easy to do because those long distance projects have no (noticeable) ramifications when they’re delayed. I can always make up the difference later or move the potential launch date back a bit without anyone noticing.</p>

<p>But that undermines my own mission. If I want to help others get better at their systems and develop a more meaningful life, I need to stay the course and keep working on the projects without a deadline and that have a bigger long-term impact.</p>

<p>I recently spent some time reflecting on these projects, trying to find time for them  each week. I wanted to put my hands to work instead of just thinking or talking, because “It’s the thought that counts” isn’t much of a business model. I thought about dedicating one or two days a week to them, but that would lead to slower progress in the end. What I really need to do is check something off for these projects every single day. They need to move forward every day no matter how small the progress is. Those incremental gains can make a big impact over time.</p>

<p>If I’m going to step up and work on these every day, it makes sense to create a checklist of the projects and tasks I need to complete each day. It also feeds my love of lists.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="/assets/posts_extra/the_important_not_urgent_projects/important-project-list.jpg" /></p>

<p>This shows up on my OmniFocus Dashboard every day and I go through it top to bottom along with everything else I do in the day. This means I set aside more of the “procrastiworking” tasks I tend to work on instead of my key projects, which is a good thing. There are some short-term sacrifices I make to do this but I don’t think anyone would say it’s not worth it.</p>

<p>To get a little more technical on the <em>how</em>, here are the settings I use for the project itself in OmniFocus:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-tiny" src="/assets/posts_extra/the_important_not_urgent_projects/important-project-settings.jpg" /></p>

<p>The idea is to flag the project to add it to my Dashboard (Due and Flagged), have it repeat every day, and mark the project complete after all tasks are completed.</p>

<p>Now I have a daily reminder and checklist that ensures I make progress on these important projects. I don’t care how small it is, but I <em>will</em> move them forward. It’s that small contribution each day that really adds up.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[And Now...]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/and-now/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/and-now/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I ran across this idea when reading an article by Derek Sivers. The premise is simple: creating a frequently updated page to show what the person is currently doing. The concept really resonated with me, and I expanded on it a bit.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/And-Now.jpg" /><p>I ran across this idea when reading an article by <a href="https://sivers.org/">Derek Sivers</a>. The premise is simple: creating a frequently updated page to show what the person is currently doing. The concept really resonated with me, and I expanded on it a bit.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Sivers calls it a <em>Now</em> page and even created <a href="http://nownownow.com/">an index of these pages</a>. I started looking through these pages and loved a lot of the ideas I found. It was a classic case of being unable to make up my mind. So instead of picking one area or one page to keep updated, I built a site that showcases where my time goes, what I’m reading, what I’m currently developing, and a growing portfolio of my work.</p>

<p>In the future, I’d like to add an Apps page that keeps a list of the tools I’m using on my devices, but that’s an extensive addition, so it needs to come at a later time.</p>

<p>So if you’re curious about what I’m up to, go check out <a href="http://now.joebuhlig.com">now.joebuhlig.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[31: Apps, Websites, and TextExpander Pricing]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/31/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[textexpander]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/31/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I go on a rant about building websites instead of apps. That leads me to a subsidiary rant about the polarizing changes to TextExpander.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Apps-Websites-and-TextExpander-Pricing.jpg" /><p>I go on a rant about building websites instead of apps. That leads me to a subsidiary rant about the polarizing changes to TextExpander.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a></p>

<p><a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/discourse-do-need-an-app-here-is-why/41611?u=joebuhlig">Discourse does need an App, here is why</a></p>

<p><a href="https://smilesoftware.com/software-releases/entry/the-new-textexpander">The New TextExpander - Smile</a></p>

<p><a href="https://smilesoftware.com/press/entry/smile-launches-textexpander-com-with-apps-for-mac-iphone-and-windows-beta">Smile Press Release</a></p>

<p><a href="https://blog.agilebits.com/2016/02/16/introducing-1password-for-families/">Introducing 1Password for Families</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mikeschmitz.me/thoughts-on-textexpander-6/">Thoughts on TextExpander 6 - mikeschmitz.me</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Timing Tasks]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/timing-tasks/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/timing-tasks/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In a previous role I spent some time researching project management software and evaluating it for company use. One of the turn-offs that my end users brought up was an extreme distaste for running a stopwatch on the tasks being tracked. I get it. No one wants to be stuck...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Timing-Tasks.jpg" /><p>In a previous role I spent some time researching project management software and evaluating it for company use. One of the turn-offs that my end users brought up was an extreme distaste for running a stopwatch on the tasks being tracked. I get it. No one wants to be stuck to a clock, especially when those reviewing the numbers are your managers.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I didn’t want to go that route either. I’ve always had a resistance to due dates, but some of it was fear that the data would be used against me. It would be hard not to compare my times to that of my coworkers. It wouldn’t matter if I came out better or not, quality of work would no longer be the main consideration if speed took over as the primary indicator.</p>

<p>When I started working for myself, I finally came around to the idea of starting a stopwatch at the beginning of every new task. The data was staying in my own hands. It could help me maximize my time without the potential for negative consequences. So I set up <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/tracking-time-with-launch-center-pro/">a process with Launch Center Pro</a> to help track my time.</p>

<p>My intent was to understand where I spent the most time and look for places to cut back. I was seeking maximum impact for the least amount of time spent since every action I take can directly influence my income. But after timing my work for a while, I found there were more benefits to starting that stopwatch than I expected.</p>

<h2 id="history">History</h2>

<p>The first of these was my original (and only) intent: a record of how much time I spend on tasks. Keeping track of how much time I spend on tasks helps me see if I’m allocating too much of my day to one activity. I can’t say that I had any big <em>aha</em> moments as I’ve looked through the data, but it’s at least interesting to see how much time goes into writing an article or designing and building a website.</p>

<h2 id="estimations">Estimations</h2>

<p>Once I know how long something usually takes, I can estimate how much time to allocate to a task prior to starting. The past is the most accurate indicator of the future. This is why it’s so dangerous (and manipulative) to make even slight changes to history books and data records. If you want to honestly understand where you currently stand and how something will pan out in the future, you can study the past and see how things work out. History is an indicator for our actions in the present. The same is true for the time it takes to complete a task. The more we know about our completed tasks, the better we are at predicting the outcomes of our current and future tasks.</p>

<h2 id="self-competition">Self-Competition</h2>

<p>If we know how much time something usually takes us and we are about to begin a similar task, we have a benchmark to compare against. We have a time to beat. I think this holds the most value if you are the sole owner of the data and want to get better at the task. You can choose to let the time go longer if you’re working to improve the quality or you can work on speed if you’re trying to gain efficiency. In both cases, though, you know and understand your goal.</p>

<h2 id="focus">Focus</h2>

<p>I was caught off-guard by this one. When I start that timer, I know that I’ll be recording the number when I’m done. The time will go into storage and into the broader history of the data I’ve  stored. The last thing I want to do is have that number include tasks outside of what I recorded. It will muddy the waters with false data, and I cannot <em>stand</em> false data. If I spend 10 minutes checking Twitter in the middle of designing a logo and I record it as time spent designing, the record is incorrect. So I take advantage of my loathing for bad data sets and use it to stay focused on the task.</p>

<h2 id="everything">Everything?</h2>

<p>Absolutely not. Don’t be crazy. You should not have a stopwatch running when you’re having coffee with your spouse. Only time the tasks that need a record or that tend to get away from you. Leisure and play should be allowed to roam. Tasks for work or your side projects are likely the primary commitments worth timing. Those are typically the only areas where we strive for efficiency and focus. It doesn’t work to be laser-focused while at the beach on vacation.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Text File Weather Forecast]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-text-file-weather-forecast/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[text-files]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-text-file-weather-forecast/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It never fails. I sit at our kitchen table over breakfast and mention to my wife that it’s going to snow that day. The first question she asks? “How much?” I don’t know! All I know is that my alert says it’s supposed to happen!

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/A-Text-File-Weather-Forececast.jpg" /><p>It never fails. I sit at our kitchen table over breakfast and mention to my wife that it’s going to snow that day. The first question she asks? <em>“How much?”</em> I don’t know! All I know is that my alert says it’s supposed to happen!
<!--more--></p>

<p>After going through this exchange so many times that my wife realized she was driving me crazy <em>then continued to ask because she enjoys taunting me</em>, I gave up and created my own weather forecast. I wanted to know temperatures and precipitation amounts and keep a daily record of each forecast. I figured if I was going to go through the trouble of creating it, I might as well make it possible to search a date and get the forecast from that day. I turned to text files and Google Scripts.</p>

<h2 id="today">Today</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" style="width:40%;" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_text_file_weather_forecast/weather-today.jpg" /></p>

<p>To set this up, you’ll need access to Google Drive and a <a href="http://www.wunderground.com/weather/api?apiref=6977fd0285651b13">developer account with Weather Underground</a>.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Create a new Google Apps Script in Google Drive.</li>
  <li>Paste the code below into the script.</li>
  <li>Replace the _X_s in the script with your Weather Underground API key and change the city/state to your location.</li>
  <li>Set up a trigger to run the function automatically (Resources &gt; Current project’s triggers).</li>
</ol>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_text_file_weather_forecast/app-trigger.jpg" /></p>

<p>Here’s the script you’ll need:</p>

<noscript><pre>function weatherLogger() {
  var url = &quot;http://api.wunderground.com/api/XXXXXXXXXXX/forecast/q/STATE/CITY.json&quot;
  var response = UrlFetchApp.fetch(url);
  var weather = JSON.parse(response);
  var summary = weather.forecast.simpleforecast.forecastday[0];
  var newFileData = summary[&quot;date&quot;][&quot;pretty&quot;] + &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;High temp: &quot; + summary[&quot;high&quot;][&quot;fahrenheit&quot;] + &quot;°F/&quot; + summary[&quot;high&quot;][&quot;celsius&quot;] + &quot;°C&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Low temp: &quot; + summary[&quot;low&quot;][&quot;fahrenheit&quot;] + &quot;°F/&quot; + summary[&quot;low&quot;][&quot;celsius&quot;] + &quot;°C&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Conditions: &quot; + summary[&quot;conditions&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Precipitation: &quot; + summary[&quot;qpf_allday&quot;][&quot;in&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Snow: &quot; + summary[&quot;snow_allday&quot;][&quot;in&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Max Wind Speed: &quot; + summary[&quot;maxwind&quot;][&quot;mph&quot;] + &quot;mph &quot; + summary[&quot;maxwind&quot;][&quot;dir&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Avg Wind Speed: &quot; + summary[&quot;avewind&quot;][&quot;mph&quot;] + &quot;mph &quot; + summary[&quot;avewind&quot;][&quot;dir&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Humidity: &quot; + summary[&quot;avehumidity&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Raw Data:&quot;;
  
  for (var key in summary) {
    var dataToLog = key + &quot;: &quot; + JSON.stringify(summary[key]);
    if (newFileData == &quot;&quot;) {
      newFileData = dataToLog;
    }
    else {
      newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
      newFileData += dataToLog;
    };
  };
  var today = new Date();
  var d = new Date(today);
  var y = d.getFullYear();
  var m = d.getMonth();
  m = m + 1
  m = &quot;00&quot; + m
  m = m.substr(m.length - 2);
  var day = d.getDate();
  day = &quot;00&quot; + day;
  day = day.substr(day.length - 2);
  var dateString = y + m + day;
  DriveApp.createFile(&quot;Weatherx_Todayx_&quot; + dateString + &quot;.txt&quot;, newFileData);
}</pre></noscript>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/joebuhlig/488a95d9072b6c8a1500.js"> </script>

<p>When run, the script will create a text file at the top-level of your Google Drive. From there you can use Hazel to move and rename these files however you like. For example, I use Hazel to rename the files to just the date and move them to DropBox within <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/text-file-setup-and-workflow/">my text file setup</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_text_file_weather_forecast/hazel-rule.jpg" /></p>

<h2 id="yesterday">Yesterday</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" style="width:40%;" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_text_file_weather_forecast/weather-yesterday.jpg" /></p>

<p>Once I had today’s forecast working properly, I took the next step: keeping a history of what actually happened the day before. This was primarily so I could determine how much rain we had yesterday. I grew up on a crop farm. The most common question in a farming community is, “How much rain did you get last night?” That almost instinctual curiosity has never left me, but instead of setting up a rain gauge like most good farmers, I just altered my forecast script to give the data from the day before in the same format.</p>

<p>Everything for this historical record works the same as the forecast. The only difference is the location of the API call and the parsing of the data.</p>

<noscript><pre>function weatherLogger() {
  var url = &quot;http://api.wunderground.com/api/XXXXXXXXXXX/yesterday/q/STATE/CITY.json&quot;
  var response = UrlFetchApp.fetch(url);
  var data = JSON.parse(response);
  var summary = data.history.dailysummary[0];
  var slength = summary.length;
  var newFileData = summary[&quot;date&quot;][&quot;pretty&quot;] + &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;High temp: &quot; + summary[&quot;maxtempi&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Low temp: &quot; + summary[&quot;mintempi&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Avg temp: &quot; + summary[&quot;meantempi&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Rain: &quot; + summary[&quot;rain&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Snow: &quot; + summary[&quot;snow&quot;] + &quot; &quot; + summary[&quot;snowfalli&quot;] + &quot; &quot; + summary[&quot;snowdepthi&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Precipitation: &quot; + summary[&quot;precipi&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Growing Degree Days: &quot; + summary[&quot;gdegreedays&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Max Wind Speed: &quot; + summary[&quot;maxwspdi&quot;] + &quot;mph&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Avg Wind Speed: &quot; + summary[&quot;meanwindspdi&quot;] + &quot;mph &quot; + summary[&quot;meanwdire&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Humidity: &quot; + summary[&quot;humidity&quot;];
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
  newFileData += &quot;Raw Data:&quot;;
  
  for (var key in summary) {
    var dataToLog = key + &quot;: &quot; + JSON.stringify(summary[key]);
    if (newFileData == &quot;&quot;) {
      newFileData = dataToLog;
    }
    else {
      newFileData += &quot;\n&quot;;
      newFileData += dataToLog;
    };
  };
  var today = new Date();
  var d = new Date(today);
  d.setDate(today.getDate() - 1);
  var y = d.getFullYear();
  var m = d.getMonth();
  m = m + 1
  m = &quot;00&quot; + m
  m = m.substr(m.length - 2);
  var day = d.getDate();
  day - 1;
  day = &quot;00&quot; + day;
  day = day.substr(day.length - 2);
  var dateString = y + m + day;
  DriveApp.createFile(&quot;Weatherx_Yesterdayx_&quot; + dateString + &quot;.txt&quot;, newFileData);
}

</pre></noscript>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/joebuhlig/d652e20182ed3c380e15.js"> </script>

<p>The benefit of having both of these in place is the ability to compare the forecast to what actually happened. The only issue with doing this is the result: it shows just how bad forecasts really are at predicting weather. But hey, at least breakfast with my wife is less maddening.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[30: Decision Analysis Paralysis]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/30/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[contexts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[task-management]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/30/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When you have a large amount of data available, it’s easy to be paralyzed in making a decision about how to analyze it. The same is true when you have a lot of tasks and little clarity.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Decision-Analysis-Paralysis.jpg" /><p>When you have a large amount of data available, it’s easy to be paralyzed in making a decision about how to analyze it. The same is true when you have a lot of tasks and little clarity.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis">Analysis paralysis - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.briantracy.com/blog/time-management/the-truth-about-frogs/">The Truth About Frogs</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/tag/reviews/">Articles about Reviews</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_goldstein_the_battle_between_your_present_and_future_self">The battle between your present and future self - TED Talk</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/making-time-contexts/">Making Time for Contexts</a></p>

<p><a href="http://patrickrhone.com/2014/11/11/a-time-for-things/">A Time For Things - Patrick Rhone</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Choosing OmniFocus Settings]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/choosing-omnifocus-settings/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/choosing-omnifocus-settings/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[No application setup is complete without tweaking the settings to your liking. This is the power (and struggle) of OmniFocus. Some of the available options make drastic changes while others lead to subtleties you may not notice.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Choosing-OmniFocus-Settings.jpg" /><p>No application setup is complete without tweaking the settings to your liking. This is the power (and struggle) of OmniFocus. Some of the available options make drastic changes while others lead to subtleties you may not notice.
<!--more--></p>

<div class="callout">
	<div class="callout-book-cover">
		<a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">
			<img class="callout-image" src="/assets/base/WorkingWithOmniFocus-Small.png" />
		</a>
	</div>
	<blockquote style="border: 0px; text-align:center;">Stop searching for the right way to use OmniFocus. There isn’t one.</blockquote>
	<p>If you're interested in more detail about my OmniFocus setup, take a look at <a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">my book on it</a>. I pull back the curtain on the concepts and nuances of OmniFocus and how I work with it.</p>
</div>

<p>I use the Mac version of OmniFocus as the “home base” of my setup. I make most of my changes there and let them sync to iOS. There are a few settings specific to mobile, but the majority of the following options will be dedicated to OmniFocus 2 for Mac.</p>

<h2 id="general">General</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/General_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>One of the most powerful advantages of high resolution screens is the ability to condense information and see the full context of the current task. The more you can see at once the easier it is to understand what’s going on. That’s one thing I love about being able to adjust the text size in OmniFocus. Try to make it as small as possible while still being able to read it. If you can see every task assigned to a project when you’re reviewing it, you can make a clearer decision about it.</p>

<p>It can be painful when vital keyboard shortcuts change on you. Muscle memory is not overcome without a number of frustrating mistakes. There were a number of simple keystrokes in OmniFocus 1 ingrained in my fingers that were changed in OmniFocus 2. You can revert to the old way by using the <em>Classic Mode</em> for outlining, but when applications make changes on this scale, it’s typically for a good reason and I try to bite the bullet and change with them. It’s always possible that the old way will be dropped entirely in the future. To save myself trouble later on, I use the <em>Modern Mode</em> for outlining. And to be honest, after switching it does make a lot of sense.</p>

<p>The <em>Quick Entry Shortcut</em> and the <em>Clippings Shortcut</em> are both settings you should tweak to your liking. I use a combination of the Spacebar and other modifier keys to invoke most blank capture and search mechanisms. So in my case I use Control + Option + Space to pull up the <em>Quick Entry Dialog</em>. If I’m capturing selected text or existing data, I use Command + Shift and a letter to indicate the program I want the data to land in. In this case, I use Command + Shift + O for the <em>Clippings Shortcut</em>.</p>

<h2 id="organization">Organization</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Organization_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>I highly recommend cleaning up items only when they have both a Project and a Context. This means new tasks only leave your inbox when they have both of these assigned; any other scenario leaves the task at risk of not being clearly defined. Even if there needs to be a placeholder context or project, it’s still better than making a partial decision about the task. Let this setting push you to be as clear as you can.</p>

<p>You have an option for doing this cleanup process automatically (as soon as the criteria is met) or when you change views or perspectives. I’ve found that it really depends on how you like to work with tasks. If you like to see completed tasks sitting there with a checkmark, set this to <em>When changing views</em>. But if you’re like me and you want your list to shrink as you check things off, set it to <em>Immediately</em>.</p>

<p>Do you have a tendency to create new projects already thought out with a series of tasks that must be completed in a set order? Or do you tend to add tasks as you think of them and most of your projects don’t follow a set pattern? In the case of the former, you will likely want all your new projects to start off as sequential. I fall into the latter category and prefer them to start as parallel. That allows me to keep adding tasks to the project and have them show up on my context lists immediately.</p>

<p>The last option here is for showing the projects and groups in your context lists. This is mostly preference. If you have a task group assigned to @Computer, that group will show up in your Computer context list. Personally, I feel that this adds clutter to my list, so I leave this unchecked.</p>

<h2 id="layout">Layout</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Layout_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>Remember what I said about data density? I think there’s a lot of value in condensed formats. Seeing as much information as I can at one time helps me understand the situation better. So I prefer to use the <em>Custom Columns</em>  or <em>Fluid</em> layouts. You can see the exact columns I’m using in the screenshot. Those specific columns help me make the best decision on the next task to work on.</p>

<h2 id="dates--times">Dates &amp; Times</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Date_Time_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>When do you want tasks to be marked as “Due Soon?” When you mark a task with a due date, when does that task show a yellow indicator? This really depends on how quickly your tasks come and go and how long it takes to complete them. In my case those combined criteria lead me to a five day lead time. I want an indicator when something is due in five days or less.</p>

<p>The next three settings are about default times. You’ll want to set these in a way that makes sense based on your daily schedule. When I defer a task I want it to show up the morning of the date I set, so I use midnight as the default defer time. I typically go to bed around 9pm, so I make sure tasks are completed by then if they are due. Finally, I want to make sure every project is reviewed weekly. In rare cases, I’ll adjust a project to go further out but the vast majority of my projects need a weekly look.</p>

<h2 id="notifications">Notifications</h2>

<p>In 99% of cases, I turn off notifications from apps on my devices. There are very few alerts important enough to warrant a change in direction, but OmniFocus is an exception. If OmniFocus notifies me, I need to know about it. It is an indicator that I missed something and it needs to be dealt with immediately. I can’t afford to let those slide.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Notification_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>To help with getting my attention, OmniFocus has the ability to use “soft” alerts. These are the dock icon badge and perspective highlights. I use both to indicate when I have tasks that are due soon or flagged. I rely on my phone for these because I prefer a single place for alerts and since my phone is always with me, it makes sense as the central hub.</p>

<p>When I do get alerts, I want them to be important. I avoid due dates on my tasks as much as I can so when I see a badge icon or get a notification, it has some weight behind it. To maintain that importance, I limit alerts to tasks that are due in some way.</p>

<p>I don’t use it on my Mac nearly as much as my phone, but I really like having my Dashboard (flagged and due tasks) in my Today view. It’s nice to see this list with a single swipe.</p>

<p>I’ve never been a big fan of putting my tasks on the calendar. That may work for you, but I’ve never found a way to do that without creating my nemesis: clutter.</p>

<h2 id="synchronization">Synchronization</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Synchronization_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>You can get fancy with how you sync your data but I prefer to trust the Omni Group. They know their data better than I do, so I stick with their service to move the data around.</p>

<h2 id="update">Update</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/choosing_omnifocus_settings/Update_Preferences.jpg" /></p>

<p>It’s good to get new features and bug fixes, so I enable checking for daily updates. I know that some folks prefer not to send information back to companies, and in some cases I might do the same. But the Omni Group has gained my trust and I want to help them continue to build a quality product. So in this case, I opt to send them anonymous data.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Record of Completed Tasks]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-record-of-completed-tasks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[applescripts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[hazel]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[text-files]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-record-of-completed-tasks/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There are times when I want to look back and see what I did on a specific day. This is extremely helpful when I need a record for a client, but no matter the reason, I find myself referring to my task history frequently.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/A-Record-of-Completed-Tasks.jpg" /><p>There are times when I want to look back and see what I did on a specific day. This is extremely helpful when I need a record for a client, but no matter the reason, I find myself referring to my task history frequently.
<!--more--></p>

<p>There are two ways I access these completed tasks: in an OmniFocus perspective and in daily text files.</p>

<h2 id="daily-review">Daily Review</h2>

<p>The OmniFocus  perspective that I use to view my completed tasks is one of the stock perspectives, and doesn’t require a Pro account. Here are the specific settings I’m using:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_record_of_completed_tasks/completed-perspective.jpg" /></p>

<p>Some days it can be a challenge to pick up where I left off the day before. I can look at the upcoming tasks on my Dashboard but that doesn’t give me the context of what I  just finished doing for those projects. So at the end of my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/gaining-perspective-daily-review/">Daily Review</a> I look over this Completed perspective. It’s a quick view of what I’ve been working on and helps me pick up where I left off.</p>

<h2 id="text-files">Text Files</h2>

<p>For longer term storage of completed tasks, I create text files detailing the progress of  tasks and projects that day. Under each project is a list of the completed tasks and their completion date.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_record_of_completed_tasks/task-report.jpg" /></p>

<p>The idea here is to create a historical record of what I did each day. It allows me to go back in time to any day I want and see exactly which projects I was working on and the progress I made.</p>

<h2 id="applescript-and-hazel">AppleScript and Hazel</h2>

<p>These text files are created automatically, because there’s no way I’m going to copy/paste the data into place every day. I wrote an AppleScript that creates them and the script is run by Hazel, so my Mac needs to be turned on to run it; I can’t see the text file for yesterday until my Mac has had a chance to run the script today. I should note that this script is designed to be an external script, not embedded. Here’s what the Hazel rule looks like:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/a_record_of_completed_tasks/hazel-rule.jpg" /></p>

<p>And here’s the external AppleScript used in the rule:</p>

<noscript><pre>on hazelProcessFile(theFile)
	set filePath to &quot;/Users/JoeBuhlig/Dropbox/Text/TaskReports/&quot; -- Where to save the resulting text file (Be sure to add the trailing &quot;/&quot;)
	
	-- Create the new filename as YYYYMMDD.txt
	set todayDate to current date
	set yestDate to todayDate - 1 * days
	set {year:y, month:m, day:d} to yestDate
	set fileName to y * 10000
	set fileName to fileName + (m * 100)
	set fileName to fileName + d
	
	-- Set the starting date of the report
	set startDate to todayDate - 1 * days
	set startDate&#39;s hours to 0
	set startDate&#39;s minutes to 0
	set startDate&#39;s seconds to 0
	
	-- Set the ending date of the report
	set endDate to todayDate - 1 * days
	set endDate&#39;s hours to 23
	set endDate&#39;s minutes to 59
	set endDate&#39;s seconds to 59
	
	-- Create the blank report to build from
	set reportText to &quot;&quot;
	
	tell application &quot;OmniFocus&quot;
		tell front document
			set theProjects to every flattened project where its modification date is greater than startDate and modification date is less than endDate
			repeat with a from 1 to length of theProjects
				set currentProj to item a of theProjects
				set theTasks to (every flattened task of currentProj where its completed = true and completion date is greater than startDate and completion date is less than endDate)
				if theTasks is not equal to {} then
					set reportText to reportText &amp; return &amp; return &amp; &quot;------------------------------&quot; &amp; return &amp; name of currentProj &amp; return
					repeat with b from 1 to length of theTasks
						set currentTask to item b of theTasks
						set completedDate to completion date of currentTask
						set completedTime to time string of completedDate
						set reportText to reportText &amp; return &amp; name of currentTask &amp; &quot; ----- &quot; &amp; completedTime
					end repeat
				end if
			end repeat
			if reportText is equal to &quot;&quot; then
				reportText = &quot;Nothing completed for this day.&quot;
			end if
			set runTime to date string of (todayDate - 1 * days)
			set reportText to runTime &amp; return &amp; return &amp; reportText
			set newFile to open for access filePath &amp; fileName &amp; &quot;.txt&quot; with write permission
			write reportText to newFile
			close access newFile
		end tell -- end tell front document
	end tell -- end tell application &quot;OmniFocus&quot;
end hazelProcessFile</pre></noscript>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/joebuhlig/7e3a15b1d75cc1d745e5.js"> </script>

<h2 id="ios">iOS</h2>

<p>You’ll notice in the script that I’m saving the text files to my DropBox. The most common place for me to search these task reports is from my phone. With them syncing and being stored with the rest of my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/text-file-setup-and-workflow/">text file setup</a>, I can easily search for a task or project in Editorial and determine when I completed it.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[29: Get Started and Iterate]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/29/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/29/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In this episode, I go through the ideas behind agile development and applying them to get a minimum viable product out the door. This is exactly how OmniGroup has now gotten to the point of bringing themes back to OmniFocus. Oh, and I completely missed daylight savings.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Get-Started-and-Iterate.jpg" /><p>In this episode, I go through the ideas behind agile development and applying them to get a minimum viable product out the door. This is exactly how OmniGroup has now gotten to the point of bringing themes back to OmniFocus. Oh, and I completely missed daylight savings.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development">Agile software development - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall_model">Waterfall model - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">Minimum viable product - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="http://people.omnigroup.com/kc/">Ken Case — The Omni Group</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/kcase/status/709491281328603136">Kens tweet about styling</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Minimal Alfred Theme]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/alfred-theme/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[alfred]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/alfred-theme/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve got a bonus for you this week: my Alfred theme. I’ve tweaked the look of Alfred quite a bit over the few years I’ve been using it. I wanted something simple and unobtrusive, but I also wanted it to be compact and cram a lot of data into a...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/A-Minimal-Alfred-Theme.jpg" /><p>I’ve got a bonus for you this week: my Alfred theme. I’ve tweaked the look of Alfred quite a bit over the few years I’ve been using it. I wanted something simple and unobtrusive, but I also wanted it to be compact and cram a lot of data into a small space. If that sounds appealing, give it a try.
<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>You can <a href="/assets/files/mnml.alfredappearance">get the theme here</a>.</strong></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Favorite Alfred Tricks]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/favorite-alfred-tricks/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[alfred]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/favorite-alfred-tricks/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[My Mac is useless without Alfred. That’s no joke. I try to use my wife’s profile once in a while. It’s painful for me and hilarious for her to watch. I keep hitting the Alfred shortcuts and staring at it like it’s broken.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Favorite-Alfred-Tricks.jpg" /><p>My Mac is useless without <a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred</a>. That’s no joke. I try to use my wife’s profile once in a while. It’s painful for me and hilarious for her to watch. I keep hitting the Alfred shortcuts and staring at it like it’s broken.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I didn’t get this dependent overnight. I started using Alfred a few years ago and have slowly built up the number of use cases I have for it. So if you’re just starting out, don’t feel like you need to adopt a whole bunch of things at once. Find one or two that you know you’ll use and build from there. Here are some of the ways I use Alfred.</p>

<h2 id="launching-apps">Launching Apps</h2>

<p>I mentioned this in a <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/mac-navigation/">previous article</a>, but it bears repeating because it’s so important. I rarely use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mission_Control_%28OS_X%29">Mission Control</a> on the Mac. I’d rather jump straight to an app without hunting down the window that looks like the one I want. I set up workflows (Powerpack feature) that allow me to hit a keyboard shortcut and show/hide the app I want. This pulls up the app I want without a misfire.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-show-app-shortcut.jpg" alt="Alfred App Launch" /></p>

<h2 id="clipboard-history">Clipboard History</h2>

<p>I copy text and links all the time, and sometimes I need to copy/paste multiple portions of text at once. Take my weekly <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/newsletter">newsletter</a> for example. It has the title, excerpt, and link for each post that was published that week. I could flip back and forth nine times and get everything copied over, but that’s ridiculous. Instead I pull up each post, copy all the pieces I need, and use the clipboard history in Alfred to paste each piece without flipping between apps.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-clipboard-history.jpg" alt="Alfred Clipboard History" /></p>

<h2 id="email">Email</h2>

<p>I use Google Apps for my email and haven’t found a need for a local client because the web client works so well. This means checking my email requires entering the url for Gmail, and because I run a few different accounts I need to be able to pinpoint the exact email address. Using TextExpander, I set up a snippet that expands to the url for the account I want and presses Enter. Invoking Alfred and entering my snippet abbreviation sends me directly to my email. Though sometimes I wonder if I’ve made this too easy.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="highlighter-rouge">xemp</code> = <code class="highlighter-rouge">https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/#inbox%key:enter%</code></li>
  <li><code class="highlighter-rouge">xemjb</code> = <code class="highlighter-rouge">https://mail.google.com/mail/u/1/#inbox%key:enter%</code></li>
  <li><code class="highlighter-rouge">xemfh</code> = <code class="highlighter-rouge">https://mail.google.com/mail/u/2/#inbox%key:enter%</code></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="searching-files">Searching Files</h2>

<p>This is a pretty standard way to use a launcher like Alfred. And if you’re just getting started with one, it’s a good place to start. If I need to open a file, I rarely go to Finder. I almost always start typing into Alfred.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-file-search.jpg" alt="Alfred File Search" /></p>

<h2 id="font-awesome">Font Awesome</h2>

<p>Because I develop for the web, I use the <a href="https://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/">Font Awesome</a> library of icons a lot. It’s a part of nearly every website I’ve worked with. So when I ran across a <a href="https://github.com/ruedap/alfred2-font-awesome-workflow">workflow</a> for searching and pasting in the classes for every icon, I installed it immediately.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-font-awesome.jpg" alt="Alfred Font Awesome" /></p>

<h2 id="dictionarythesaurus">Dictionary/Thesaurus</h2>

<p>I find myself looking for synonyms and definitions quite a bit, and Alfred makes it really easy on me. It has a built-in mechanism for searching the dictionary for a word and offering synonyms. I did change the keyword needed to search the dictionary from <em>define</em> to <em>def</em>,  just to make it a bit quicker.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-define.jpg" alt="Alfred Define" /></p>

<h2 id="somedaymaybe-lists">Someday/Maybe Lists</h2>

<p>Because I keep so many idea lists, I wanted a quick way to pull them up. So I created a workflow in Alfred that uses the keyword <em>ofsm</em>. It opens a link (copied from OmniFocus) to my folder of Someday/Maybe lists.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts_extra/favorite_alfred_tricks/alfred-someday-maybe.jpg" alt="Alfred Someday Maybe" /></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Text File Setup and Workflow]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/text-file-setup-and-workflow/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[setups]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[text-files]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/text-file-setup-and-workflow/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Now that I’ve moved away from Evernote, the primary way I store information is through text files. It’s taken me a while to get it nailed down but I’ve managed to simplify the number of apps I use and the flow of text across my devices.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Text-File-Setup-and-Workflow.jpg" /><p>Now that I’ve moved <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/">away from Evernote</a>, the primary way I store information is through text files. It’s taken me a while to get it nailed down but I’ve managed to simplify the number of apps I use and the flow of text across my devices.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="file-storage">File Storage</h2>

<p>The back end storage of my text files is DropBox. It’s ubiquitous. If you want to build an app that handles raw text, you have to enable DropBox syncing to get any traction. Inside my DropBox structure is a folder, <em>Text</em> (original, I know). Within that folder are a few subfolders: <em>TaskReports</em>, <em>Weather</em>, and <em>Writing</em>.</p>

<p>The main folder, <em>Text</em>, is where the bulk of my files go.  I use the same naming structure here that I use in many places across my apps and devices: <code class="highlighter-rouge">Tagx_Keywords_YYYYMMDD</code>. The tag is the type of text the file contains. It uses <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/simple-trick-naming-tags/">the “x” trick</a> I adopted from Merlin Mann. I try not to add new tags but sometimes it’s necessary. Here is the current breakout of tags I’m using:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Bookx</strong> - book reviews and notes</li>
  <li><strong>Ideax</strong> - ideas I have for a project or potential business prospect</li>
  <li><strong>Inboxx</strong> - temporary files that need further processing</li>
  <li><strong>Monthlyx</strong> - monthly reflections</li>
  <li><strong>Presentationx</strong> - outlines and notes for presentations</li>
  <li><strong>Recipex</strong> - my personal recipe box</li>
  <li><strong>Thoughtsx</strong> - sometimes I write my thoughts about a concept or big decision</li>
  <li><strong>Topicx</strong> - potential topics for online forums</li>
  <li><strong>URLx</strong> - groups of urls I want to keep</li>
  <li><strong>Weeklyx</strong> - weekly reflections</li>
  <li><strong>Yearlyx</strong> - yearly reflections</li>
</ul>

<p>After the tag are keywords I use to describe the file itself. If I have an idea file for a client website, the title would look like this: <code class="highlighter-rouge">Ideax_clientwebsite.com_20160314</code>. Or if the ideas are for a potential business opportunity: <code class="highlighter-rouge">Ideax_Best solar panel ever_20160314</code>. Having these keywords makes it possible to search the tag and one of the keywords so I can find an exact file. But more often than not, I don’t need to search for the tag itself because typing in the keyword gets me close enough to look through the list of results and see the one I want. The tag helps me make that decision within the filtered list.</p>

<p>The keywords are followed with a date so I know when it was started. I almost never use this, but if I’m trying to put the file in the context of time, it’s invaluable. And because I create <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/textexpander-snippet-nomenclature/">date strings with TextExpander</a> it’s easy to append them to each file.</p>

<h2 id="accessing-files">Accessing Files</h2>

<p>Let’s talk apps. On iOS, I’m using <a href="http://omz-software.com/editorial/">Editorial</a> (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/editorial/id673907758?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">iTunes</a>). It has a lot of power behind it and gives me access to my subfolders. There are a lot of great apps for working with text as Brett Terpstra has <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/ios-text-editors/">helped us see</a>, but I find that the ease of searching for text in Editorial paired with its integration with TextExpander makes it the perfect choice for me. Knowing that I can build workflows for text files is a huge plus as well. It feeds my need to be flexible with my data.</p>

<p>On the Mac, I use <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2013/06/08/nvalt2.2b106/">nvALT</a> and <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a>. If it’s a quick note that doesn’t belong in a subfolder, I use nvALT. The speed of this app is just incredible. And once you learn some of the keyboard shortcuts, you can pick up a lot of speed in navigating your text files.</p>

<p>Any coding or writing that’s article length or longer is opened with Sublime Text, my heavy duty text editor. I always have a Sublime window open to my <em>Writing</em> subfolder of text files. Within that folder are breakouts for the different types of writing I do: Articles, Books, Podcasts, etc. Because these are all in one folder, I always know where to go when it’s time to write. And with the power that comes with Sublime, I have a lot of tools to make text easier to work with.</p>

<h2 id="collecting">Collecting</h2>

<p>Any time I need to write down text on iOS, it starts in <a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts/">Drafts</a> (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/drafts-4/id905337691?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">iTunes</a>). There’s great flexibility in creating custom actions to send that text almost anywhere. The last thing I want to worry about when writing it down is where it should go. I need to get the idea out of my head, not waste time determining where that text should land before it’s written down. If I have to do the latter, there’s a good chance I’ll lose a portion (or all) of the idea.</p>

<p>The vast majority of the time I don’t collect ideas on the Mac. Even when I’m typing away on an article and an idea comes to me, I grab my phone and enter it into Drafts. But if I do collect it on the Mac, I use nvALT. It’s super fast, but to make sure I don’t lose the text in my sea of files, I use TextExpander to name the file with the <em>Inboxx</em> tag so I can find it later.</p>

<h2 id="processing">Processing</h2>

<p>Once the text has been captured I need to get it to the right place with the right name. It’s pretty easy to do that with Drafts. I have a handful of actions to create new next files in DropBox. Choosing the right action dictates the subfolder and name of the file itself. This is the main reason I prefer to type things into my phone over the Mac. It’s a bit weird to say, but sometimes iOS trumps OS X.</p>

<p>Processing on the Mac isn’t anything out of the ordinary. I search nvALT for the <em>Inboxx</em> tag and do the cut/paste/rename routine you would expect. I use TextExpander to make that a bit easier, but I still prefer my phone.</p>

<p>In the end, this system allows me to be extremely flexible with the type of information I write down and gives me a lot of power when editing it later. I’m not locked into any one app or service, and the apps I’m using to interact with the text all have power user features available to create my own custom environment. I guess you could say I’m a control freak with my files, but this system gives me the level of micromanagement I’m looking for.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[28: Why Is Focus So Hard?]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/28/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[focus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/28/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve slowly drifted away from the mission that gets me excited each day. And that’s due to a lack of focus and alignment with my goals.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Why-Is-Focus-So-Hard.jpg" /><p>I’ve slowly drifted away from the mission that gets me excited each day. And that’s due to a lack of focus and alignment with my goals.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Organized-Mind-Thinking-Information/dp/052595418X">The Organized Mind: Thinking Straight in the Age of Information Overload</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Choosing the Right Medium]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/choosing-the-right-medium/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/choosing-the-right-medium/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[You’re reading them right now. And the medium that they arrive in will change their weight. Words. Words in email have less impact than a handwritten letter. And a conversation over coffee has more sway than a phone call.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Choosing-the-Right-Medium.jpg" /><p>You’re reading them right now. And the medium that they arrive in will change their weight. Words. Words in email have less impact than a handwritten letter. And a conversation over coffee has more sway than a phone call.
<!--more--></p>

<p>We use a lot of mediums to share words with each other. We can send written words over iMessage or paper; we can send audible words over Facetime or in person. Each method has its own connotations and perceptions. Add in differing cultures, generational differences, and regional expectations and we now have a mess on our hands.</p>

<p>But if we boil down the options, we see many similarities.  Sending short, typed messages can be done through Twitter, Snapchat, iMessage, or email. Long form text is best sent through a blog post, email, or a handwritten letter. Email can do both, and iMessage can also do audio. Here’s a breakdown of these types of words:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Length</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Mechanism</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Example</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Short</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Visual</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Twitter, Snapchat, iMessage</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Long</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Visual</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Email, Blog Post</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Short</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Analog</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Visual</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Thank You cards, Love notes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Long</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Analog</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Visual</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Letters, journaling</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Short</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Audible</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">iMessage, voice notes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Long</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Audible</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Podcasts, talk radio</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Short</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">A/V</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">FaceTime, Snapchat</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Long</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">A/V</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">FaceTime, podcasts</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Short</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Analog</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">A/V</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Restaurant ordering</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Long</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Analog</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">A/V</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Meeting a friend for coffee</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Deciding which medium to use can be difficult. Some, like Twitter or Snapchat, are more comfortable because they don’t require vulnerability from me. Others, like a conversation over dinner, are a risk because I may say the wrong thing. And once it leaves my mouth it cannot be erased or crumpled up and thrown away.  But there are a number of factors to consider when making the decision, and comfort level isn’t really up for consideration. As long as I consider the medium that is most appropriate regardless of my own preferences, the message will be better conveyed with less chance of misunderstanding.</p>

<h2 id="publicity">Publicity</h2>

<p>Is it appropriate for the whole world to know about it? If yes, then you can use social media or a blog post. Or maybe you hold a press conference to broadcast it. But if it needs to be a private conversation or it’s a sensitive topic, please keep it off of social media and send it directly to the person who needs to hear it. I hope that goes without saying.</p>

<h2 id="length">Length</h2>

<p>If you want to share a thesis regarding your philosophical views on politics, 140 characters on Twitter probably isn’t the best choice. iMessage is great if you just need a quick response about a meeting time. The point here is to make sure the medium you choose has the ability to clearly state your point. You’re trying to convey your thoughts. Make sure you’re able to do so with the mode you choose. And don’t shortchange it just because it’s easier on you. Be clear.</p>

<h2 id="sensitivity">Sensitivity</h2>

<p>I’m never on Facebook. I understand why people use it, but I have a hard time seeing all the inappropriate posts that should have been a phone call or a get-together between friends and family. Facebook can quickly became a way of posting gut reactions to the thoughts of others. I don’t need that kind of trash in my life.</p>

<p>If the words you need to share are sensitive, whether due to political tensions, family problems, misunderstandings, or strategic business matters, consider your medium carefully. Anything typed out and sent digitally has a higher probability of being misunderstood than sitting in front of the other person. The higher the sensitivity, the less margin of error allowed in interpretation.</p>

<h2 id="relationship">Relationship</h2>

<p>How close are you to the other person? The more you know each other, the less you need to say to convey your thoughts. My best friend and I do our best to meet for coffee every Friday. In order to confirm that meeting, we just send a coffee emoji to one another. If I did the same to someone who just started following me on Twitter, they would be dumbfounded. “I know he likes coffee, but what the…?”</p>

<h2 id="availability">Availability</h2>

<p>I don’t think any of us would argue that in-person conversations are the most effective, but sometimes that’s simply not an option. You have to stick with the mediums available to you.</p>

<h2 id="value">Value</h2>

<p>This is likely the most overlooked variable. How much value do you want these words to carry? I can text “I love you” to my wife, but if I write those same words at the end of a love note written on special paper with a fountain pen, they carry more impact. If I say those same words when we end a phone call they have less worth than at the end of a dinner date. There’s nothing you can do to change the value of the medium. It’s implicit in the method itself.</p>

<p>New methods of communication are always being created and trends have us trying new ways to connect at every turn.  It’s not always easy to choose the medium for your words, but the more time I spend writing and sharing words, the more cognizant I am of the value they carry in each medium.</p>

<script src="/assets/js/jquery-tablesorter.js"></script>

<script>
$("table").tablesorter();
</script>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>