<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 12:54:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Woodworker]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Hobbies are great candidates for GTD. With all the commitments we tend to take on, free time to spend on our hobbies can be elusive. That means it’s helpful to have a system in place that keeps track of where we were and what comes next.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Woodworker.jpg" /><p>Hobbies are great candidates for GTD. With all the commitments we tend to take on, free time to spend on our hobbies can be elusive. That means it’s helpful to have a system in place that keeps track of where we were and what comes next.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I enjoy working with my hands after a day of thinking. It shifts my mind from the executive mode to the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Organized-Mind-Thinking-Information/dp/0147516315">mind wandering mode</a> and helps me decompress. The primary way I like to work with my hands is through woodworking and DIY projects. Whether it’s trim in the house or a hutch for my mother-in-law doesn’t matter. I get a chance to create something from a tree - that’s what I love.</p>

<h2 id="longer-projects">Longer Projects</h2>

<p>Sometimes the projects I take on develop over a period of months (hopefully not years) and I need to keep these project plans and supporting materials around for some time. That’s where the reference materials and project goals come in handy. I can step away from it for a period and still come back to where I left off.</p>

<h2 id="thinking-ahead">Thinking Ahead</h2>

<p>For most of my furniture builds, I can lay out what the entire project will look like step-by-step. That’s good because the joinery involved often needs to be cut early on in the project even though I won’t need it for another 20 steps. Once I have a design determined, I work backwards to name every step in the build. This affords me the perspective to see where I need to make specific cuts in the process and ensure the entire project comes out according to plan. It requires me to think through it all up front, which is the point. I have a lot fewer “oops” moments when I’ve taken the time to think it through at the beginning.</p>

<h2 id="research">Research</h2>

<p>In most woodworking projects I try a new technique, either because it’s necessary or because I just want to try a new method. In both, I need to spend some time learning from experts in person or online. When I determine how I want to complete that portion of the build, I keep it in my digital filing structure that allows me to reference it when needed; I make sure I have the material as a link in the notes for that step in the build. The research makes each step a simple process and keeps the build moving much more efficiently than if I tried to do the learning mid-stream.</p>

<p>I hope this series has been helpful. I know it’s taught me more about the GTD process by forcing me to think through how it functions in different arenas. GTD is a life framework and a proactive way to approach our information-heavy culture.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Man]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-man/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-man/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[To be honest, I struggled with this article. I wanted to write it but wasn’t sure how to convey what I was thinking. GTD has helped me as a man more than I realized but the impact has been implicit, not obvious.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Man.jpg" /><p>To be honest, I struggled with this article. I wanted to write it but wasn’t sure how to convey what I was thinking. GTD has helped me as a man more than I realized but the impact has been implicit, not obvious.
<!--more--></p>

<p>How do we quantify what a man is and nail down the tasks that make a man? What activities does a man engage in? Pinpointing those tasks is a challenge in our equality-driven society. We strive for equality between men and women, but at the end of the day we are physically and mentally different, which means we’re each suited best for different types of work. Neither is any more or less important than the other, but they are different.</p>

<p>Knowing my own mind and reading what other respected men have to say on the subject, I think it’s fair to say that there are roles that fit men best. It’s these roles that I want to develop, using the GTD framework to create the freedom and focus I need to do so.</p>

<h2 id="killing-inaction">Killing Inaction</h2>

<p>Atrophy is a real issue. If you stop working with a skill, your ability to use it will diminish over time. I find this to be <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/working-the-focus-muscle/">especially true of focus</a> and being able to stay on task. <a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com">Brett McKay</a> even suggests that <a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2016/02/29/idleness-kills-manliness/">idleness kills manliness</a>. The premise here is that we need to keep moving and continue looking for ways to develop our internal motivation. We need activity to keep us on our toes -  that’s where GTD steps in. We can use the structure of creating projects and choosing tasks to create this motivation. The specific project really depends on you and what you like to do. It also depends on the manly skills you enjoy using.</p>

<h2 id="manly-skills">Manly Skills</h2>

<p>But what are <a href="http://www.orderofman.com/skill-sets/">manly skills</a>? The stereotypical view of this might be swinging an ax or shooting guns and there’s some validity behind that stereotype. But it goes much deeper than that. The traditional view of manly skills can be generalized into skills of physical strength and violence. And those can be great skills to have, provided they are paired with wisdom and discernment (also manly skills). Without the latter, the former becomes dangerous. We need to develop our intellect, relationships, and leadership skills along with our physical abilities. The  tasks we commit to need to include meetings with other men, books that challenge our thinking, regular times for physical activity, and opportunities to lead our families. Choose projects that take you out of that comfort zone we all love.</p>

<h2 id="providing">Providing</h2>

<p>I find that I have a strong desire to be the provider for my family and I know I’m not alone. There are countless men I respect that admitted to feeling inadequate when they were without a job. And I know that when things are going well with my business I have a lot of confidence in what I do. When times are thin, I start to wonder about my ability to put food on the table. But GTD gives me an outlet for storing my ideas and creates a series of potential work that I can always kick off. It also helps me make better decisions about where to spend my time. It gives me a full view of my commitments and allows me to pick between them and stay on track.</p>

<h2 id="mentors">Mentors</h2>

<p>If you don’t have regular time spent with other men, do something about it. The absolute best way I’ve received support and ideas for how to be a better man and lead a better life is by spending time with other guys and talking through what’s going on. Get it on the calendar and keep it there. Find some guys to do life with.</p>

<p>Defining the tasks that make a man is not simple. Some are obvious and some are subtle, but they are all important. The GTD framework makes it possible for you to keep up with life and stay on top of your role and skills as a man.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[26: The Value of Lurking]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/26/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[discussions]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[lurking]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/26/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Let’s talk about lurkers. Well, I’ll talk about them. You can just listen. And that’s okay because there’s a lot of value in lurking.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-Value-of-Lurking.jpg" /><p>Let’s talk about lurkers. Well, I’ll talk about them. You can just listen. And that’s okay because there’s a lot of value in lurking.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com">Discussion site</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a></p>

<p><a href="https://experts.feverbee.com/">The FeverBee Community</a></p>

<p><a href="https://experts.feverbee.com/t/lurker-behaviour-and-the-engagement-challenge/2183?u=joebuhlig">I was called out</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/">Using Drafts</a></p>

<p><a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://macstockconferenceandexpo.com/">Macstock Conference &amp; Expo</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/22/">22: Addiction to Numbers</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/">An Alternative to Evernote</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A …</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Dad]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-dad/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-dad/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One of the greatest things a dad will ever hear is the sound of his kids squealing in joy while they play games together. It’s energizing and pure pleasure to see the delight and sparkle in their eyes as they ask to “do it again!” Those are the memories that...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Dad.jpg" /><p>One of the greatest things a dad will ever hear is the sound of his kids squealing in joy while they play games together. It’s energizing and pure pleasure to see the delight and sparkle in their eyes as they ask to “do it again!” Those are the memories that we hope to multiply.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But there’s a boogie man that creeps up in these moments: wandering thoughts about something else. This is usually work of some kind but it can also be the worry about an upcoming conversation you need to have with a friend or the wiring in the bathroom that needs fixed. I hate it. I want these focused times with my kids to be cherished and frequent.</p>

<h2 id="mental-freedom-again">Mental Freedom… again</h2>

<p>I have to fight against feeling that I can get away with being distracted because they’re just kids. That’s not fair to them. They deserve my full attention just as <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">my wife does</a>. And they’re smarter than we give them credit for. They can tell when you’re with them or not. I think kids have an innate <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/every-body-saying-book-review/">ability to read us</a> that they eventually unlearn. So it’s even more important that I keep my head clear of worrisome tasks. Having the GTD structure gives me a way to maintain that clarity.</p>

<h2 id="quantity-time">Quantity Time</h2>

<p>We’ve overdone this in the past, but we’ve found a good balance lately. We want to make sure that we have time together as a family each day. That means we spend a little time together after I get off work and then again from dinner until bedtime. Yes, there are other commitments that come up and we handle those, but we can usually plan on these times as a family. That means I keep those times on the calendar and my wife and I try to plan out our afternoons ahead of time. We know that we both need time to work on fun projects or to just step away for a bit. But we always come back together at the end of the day for dinner and fun before the kids’ bedtime.</p>

<h2 id="gifts-and-activities">Gifts and Activities</h2>

<p>I do the same for my girls as I do with my wife. I want to keep lists of possible gifts for my girls and activities that we could do together. Coming up with activities for kids can be exhausting if you don’t have an idea bank to pull from. Most of the time I can run with whatever toys the girls want to play with, but there are instances when a list to fall back on is extremely helpful.</p>

<h2 id="at-the-end-of-the-day">At The End of the Day</h2>

<p>I use GTD to help me remember all the important dates in my girls’ lives and keep track of a few Someday/Maybes. With the the other areas of my life under control, I know when I can take time for them and I can do it without worrying. As long as I continue trusting the system (and quit thinking I need to check my phone when I’m around them), I can focus on my girls and enjoy making them squeal.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Husband]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-husband/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-husband/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I find it easy to let my marriage slide. We love each other so it should come naturally, right? Roses every Valentine’s, daily love notes, and genuine conversations each night. If that’s second-nature to you, I envy you.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Husband.jpg" /><p>I find it easy to let my marriage slide. We love each other so it should come naturally, right? Roses every Valentine’s, daily love notes, and genuine conversations each night. If that’s second-nature to you, I envy you.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Building and growing an intimate relationship with your spouse is a choice. If you’re going to choose to love her, you need to do something about it. You need to show it. Step up and make the sacrifices of time and energy to let her know you love her, even when you don’t feel like it. It’s a choice.</p>

<p>But we all show our love in different ways, different <em>love languages</em>. I won’t go into the details of these here but I think you can get the gist of what they are by their titles. If you want more detail on them, <a href="http://www.5lovelanguages.com/">check out the book</a>. Here they are:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Words of Affirmation</li>
  <li>Acts of Service</li>
  <li>Receiving Gifts</li>
  <li>Quality Time</li>
  <li>Physical Touch</li>
</ol>

<p>Before you can use GTD to better your marriage, you’ll need to have an idea of how you and your spouse each prefer to be shown love. You do things for someone whose love language is <em>Quality Time</em> much differently than someone whose language is <em>Receiving Gifts</em>. In my case, I’m <em>Physical Touch</em> and my wife somehow manages to be a four-way tie for all the others (okay, not really, but they’re pretty closely ranked). So we’re opposites. You can <a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/moody-profiles/uploads/profile/attachment/5/5LLPersonalProfile_COUPLES__1_.pdf">take the test</a> to find yours on the book’s website.</p>

<h2 id="anniversaries-and-birthdays">Anniversaries and Birthdays</h2>

<p>Let’s start with the obvious ones. Dates are important. We <em>have</em> to remember them. And even with all the help of my system, I still find myself putting things off until the last minute. Keep these dates on the calendar and create a project for them a month out or more. I have to do this a couple months ahead of time or I’ll fail to do anything at all.</p>

<p>In my case, I typically get my wife a gift and plan a night out in some form. That covers <em>Receiving Gifts</em> and <em>Quality Time</em>. It usually starts with a project for the event and a task that tells me to make a decision about what to do or research upcoming events that coincide.</p>

<h2 id="gifts">Gifts</h2>

<p>I honestly don’t know what I would do without GTD here. When crunch time arrives and I want to pick something up for my wife, I can never think of that thing she said she wanted. But with a Someday/Maybe list for gift ideas, all I have to do is look there and pick one. Sometimes I share items on this list with family members. It makes it really easy to answer the question, “What does Becky want for Christmas?” Giving gifts to my wife has a lot more impact. <em>Receiving Gifts</em> covered.</p>

<h2 id="finding-time">Finding Time</h2>

<p>But sometimes time is a better (and more affordable) gift. This fits the <em>Quality Time</em> bill, and it’s where the calendar really comes in handy. My wife and I share calendars with each other so we can see what’s coming up between us. Because of that we can work together to find time away from the house and kids. Or maybe we use the time after they go to bed to watch a movie together (or get way too many ideas from <em>Fixer Upper</em>) or talk about our day.</p>

<h2 id="day-to-day">Day to Day</h2>

<p>Little things can go a long way in our house. My wife really appreciates help with maintaining the dishes, laundry, plants, toys, etc… These play into <em>Acts of Service</em> for her. Some of these are second nature and I don’t need a system for them. They’re habit at this point, which is great since my wife loves having the help. But some of these, like watering the plants, require a recurring task in my GTD setup.</p>

<p>There are also some bigger things that come up irregularly that make things much easier on her. If I take on the taxes process, she can sleep a lot better. Without a project in place to handle all of those steps, we would be paying fines every time. I’m not interested in introducing that kind of stress in our relationship.</p>

<h2 id="mental-space">Mental Space</h2>

<p>The most important aspect of GTD for me is the mental space it affords me. When we sit down to talk or go on a walk, I can be there with her. Yes, I still worry about work sometimes and she can tell when I do. If I flex the system and write those thoughts down when they come, it allows me to focus on her, give her the <em>Words of Affirmation</em> that she needs and show her that I care. She’s my best friend. I want her to know and feel that.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[25: Creating Ideas]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/25/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/25/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Coming up with ideas doesn’t have to be hard. There are four ways I create new ideas. And I had a moment of insight about being content at a birthday party for our girls.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Creating-Ideas.jpg" /><p>Coming up with ideas doesn’t have to be hard. There are four ways I create new ideas. And I had a moment of insight about being content at a birthday party for our girls.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">Using Omnifocus for Someday/Maybe Lists</a></p>

<p><a href="https://getpocket.com/">Pocket</a></p>

<p><a href="http://feedly.com">Feedly</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-setup-workflow/">My Omnifocus Setup and Workflow</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-value-of-tradition/">The Value of Tradition</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/8/">8: Waiting to Upgrade</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Writer]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-writer/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-writer/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It never fails. I’ll be mowing the lawn or riding my bike and that’s when it hits me. There’s nothing I can do about it. I wish it would leave me alone until I could do something about it, but there I am; trying to figure out how I’m going...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Writer.jpg" /><p>It never fails. I’ll be mowing the lawn or riding my bike and that’s when it hits me. There’s nothing I can do about it. I wish it would leave me alone until I could do something about it, but there I am; trying to figure out how I’m going to write those lines down.
<!--more--></p>

<p>This hasn’t been an easy lesson to learn. Writing things down. I have a pretty good memory for tasks, so I always have this nagging voice telling me “I’ll just remember this one. I don’t need to get it out of my head. I can handle it.”</p>

<p>When I started writing I had a tendency - as many first-time writers do - to wait until the muse hit me and then get to work. When it comes, take advantage of it and write like crazy. When you’re tired or the ideas stop flowing, you stop, too. No point in continuing when the good stuff is gone.</p>

<p>But there were times when this flow started to creep up on me and I couldn’t do anything about it. I was at work or I was driving. The more writing I did, the more frequently this happened and the more frustrating it was to sit helplessly and watch my inspiration fly past uncaptured.</p>

<p>I’d been using GTD for a while but I was only beginning to understand the more subtle nuances and the freedom that it can create. Because it was helping me so much in other areas, I started to apply the principles and set up systems to help with my writing. I wanted to harness the creativity that couldn’t decide on a schedule.</p>

<h2 id="topics-and-stories">Topics and Stories</h2>

<p>If you don’t already know, I’m a big fan of <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">Someday/Maybe lists</a> and setting up a list of potential topics was one of the best things I could have done to help my writing. I could be talking to a friend or reading an article and an idea would come to me. Originally, I would think about it for a moment or two and then move on. I couldn’t do anything with it right now and if was a really good idea I wouldn’t forget it. Well, that was a lie I told myself. I forgot a bunch of them. These days I type it into Drafts and send it away to the ideas list for me to review later when I’m gearing up for a new article.</p>

<p>I also keep a list of stories. If something happens or a situation impacts me, I write a note about it. I don’t always know when I’ll use these, but if I’m writing and need a story to go with it, I can look here.</p>

<h2 id="managing-creativity">Managing Creativity</h2>

<p>This is hard. I never know when I’ll have a great idea for an article I’m working on, but I have a set time when I sit down to write. One side is sporadic and unpredictable. The other is structured and uniform. The key GTD principle here is <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/getting-things-done-capture/">ubiquitous capture</a>. I must have a way to grab those sentences or paragraphs when they come, and I need a way to grab them even when my hands are busy. Sometimes that means I’m <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/siri-to-omnifocus/">dictating into Siri</a> and sometimes it means I pull the car over. I know that if I take those few moments to use my system, I’ll end up with better words on the page. As a writer, I can’t pass that up.</p>

<h2 id="clear-mind">Clear Mind</h2>

<p>It’s taken me a long time to trust my system. I go through spells when I still want to keep everything in my mind even though I know it leads to trouble. But I always come back to it stronger and more devoted. I’ve gradually ironed out points of resistance and made it simple enough to use even when I don’t feel like it. I can appreciate the freedom my mind has when I sit down to write. When it’s time to work on articles in the morning I don’t worry about the other stuff I have to do. I don’t want that clutter jumbling my thoughts. I want <em>mind like water</em> so I can be free to let the words come.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using GTD As A Homeowner]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Most of the time when I’m discussing GTD with a friend or online it’s in the context of getting more work done more efficiently. I agree that this is the easy target for the framework; our jobs and the work we do each day are the most pressing and stressing...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-GTD-as-a-Homeowner.jpg" /><p>Most of the time when I’m discussing GTD with a friend or online it’s in the context of getting more work done more efficiently. I agree that this is the easy target for the framework; our jobs and the work we do each day are the most pressing and stressing in our lives. We need as much help as we can get to stay on top of it.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Once you start to understand the nuances of GTD and you have a handle on your job, there are a couple paths you can take. You can coast and enjoy the peace that comes with having work off your mind. Or you can continue to find areas of your life to integrate into GTD. It’s not just for work, but life. And the area of life that most closely resembles the responsibilities of work - making this an easy transition - is homeownership or managing your household.</p>

<h2 id="small-stuff">Small Stuff</h2>

<p>I’ve found that you can never truly be done keeping up or improving your home. There are always light bulbs burning out and appliances wearing out over time. With the <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/seasons-tasks/">changing seasons</a> there are annual tasks that can sneak up on you when you aren’t paying attention. With the GTD mindset, these are pretty simple to handle.</p>

<p>When you see something that needs attention, either do it right away or write it down. You should have a place for these household tasks so that when you have time to work on the house (you do have a context for these, right?) you pull up this list and bring the house back up to date.</p>

<h2 id="the-projects">The Projects</h2>

<p>If you’re talking to your spouse and the two of you have an idea pertaining to the house, capture that as well. You need to keep an eye on these potentials. I wish I had started doing this sooner. Because I keep a list of these, I can often knock out a few at a time.</p>

<p>I’m currently working on some trim and finishing touches in our family room. We had an idea to add <a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/heavy-duty-floating-book-shelves/192?u=joebuhlig">built-in bookshelves</a>, but we’ve also talked about adding a switch to our fireplace to eliminate potential issues with the remote we have for it. If the remote stops working, I want a fallback and since the remote is currently a bit finicky, I thought it best to go ahead and hard-wire it. With a list of these potential projects in place, I was able to see the work I wanted to do in the family room and bundle it together. It’s a lot easier to do the fireplace wiring now when I have a wall opened up than after I have everything painted and back in place.</p>

<h2 id="irregular-tasks">Irregular Tasks</h2>

<p>There are also infrequent tasks that you can’t let slide. We live in Minnesota and with that comes a cold winter. Our house has outdoor spigots that need to be turned off in the fall so they don’t freeze and burst the pipes… again. I don’t want to relive the memories of that lesson, so I keep tasks like these in an annual <em>Fall Maintenance</em> list. When it starts to get cold outside, I run through this checklist of pre-cold items to make sure we don’t have major issues later on.</p>

<h2 id="the-principles">The Principles</h2>

<p>At the end of the day, these are the same tenants of GTD that we’re used to. When something comes up or you have an idea about something around the house, write it down; put it into the system; trust yourself. Come back to it when your contexts allow, but make sure you have a dedicated context or a specific time for these things. They won’t magically happen just because you wrote them down. Use GTD to help you engage with the tasks around your house as well as work.</p>

<div class="post-series">
<p>This series is about using GTD outside the lines of our day jobs. Yes, it can be used in every aspect of your life.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-homeowner/">Using GTD As A Homeowner</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-writer/">Using GTD As A Writer</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-husband/">Using GTD As A Husband</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-dad/">Using GTD As A Dad</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-man/">Using GTD As A Man</a></li>
<li><a href="/using-gtd-as-a-woodworker/">Using GTD As A Woodworker</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[24: No More Project Codes]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/24/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[evernote]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/24/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[With my recent move away from Evernote, I’ve made the decision to leave my project codes behind. And although there are serious competitors to Evernote, I’m staying away from them.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/No-More-Project-Codes.jpg" /><p>With my recent move away from Evernote, I’ve made the decision to leave my project codes behind. And although there are serious competitors to Evernote, I’m staying away from them.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/creating-personal-project-codes/">Creating Personal Project Codes</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/">An Alternative to Evernote</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/heavy-duty-floating-book-shelves/192?u=joebuhlig">Heavy duty floating book shelves</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak Transition</a></p>

<p><a href="http://happenapps.com/#quiver">Quiver</a></p>

<p><a href="http://literatureandlatte.com/">Scrivener</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The Value of Tradition]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-value-of-tradition/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-value-of-tradition/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Having young kids has made us think consciously about the traditions we want to pass down to them. What do we want them to learn? Will our traditions help them see the importance of our view of the world? Are they fun?

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-Value-of-Tradition.jpg" /><p>Having young kids has made us think consciously about the traditions we want to pass down to them. What do we want them to learn? Will our traditions help them see the importance of our view of the world? Are they fun?
<!--more--></p>

<p>My wife and I have a number of yearly activities that we’ve adopted from our own parents, and we want to pass them down to our own kids. But why? Is it purely nostalgia or old-fashioned? Should we just let them go and come up with our own?</p>

<p>I don’t think we pass them on because of nostalgia. There might be a bit of that, but there’s something more. Each tradition we pass on has a background and a starting point. It wasn’t something that our grandparents just made up because it sounded fun (though I wonder sometimes). They started with a desire to remember an activity or value, or they just had a great time with family doing it.</p>

<p>Say you have a tradition of watching the football game on Thanksgiving with your cousins. How did that start? Likely, there was someone in the family that turned the game on one year to check the score. Someone else asked about it and the next thing you know you’re watching the game together. Since the game is on, a few others started to show an interest and the next year you plan to watch the game. The following year you’re upgrading your TV specifically for this event and so on. But it started with a mutual interest and a connection with a family member, and now it’s grown to be a thing in itself at Thanksgiving. You come together for a day and connect with family.</p>

<p>This reminds me of any male’s rite of passage into manhood. It’s a search that every guy goes through at some point and many cultures acknowledge it with a traditional challenge to the boy. If he completes the challenge, he becomes a man. If he fails, he remains a boy. The tradition teaches him to overcome something difficult to show that he is ready for manhood, and that lesson of triumph over a trial will give him the confidence and strength he needs in the future. Without it, he will constantly be searching for his place in society.</p>

<p>Our traditions are typically altered and perfected over time. They can become more intricate or more simple as they are enacted numerous times. That’s exactly what makes them so powerful. With years of iterations, they become rich with lessons about values and morals that make our families unique. That’s what I want for our girls. I want them to learn these lessons from our grandparents and parents and eventually teach them to our grandchildren. It’s one way for me to have a positive impact on the generations beyond me and leave a proud legacy.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[An Alternative to Evernote]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[evernote]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve been a supporter of Evernote for a long time. I’ve written a number of articles on it and convinced a number of friends and family to start using it. But I’ve run into some issues with it and it’s come time to throw in the towel. I’m leaving Evernote....]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/An-alternative-to-Evernote.jpg" /><p>I’ve been a supporter of Evernote for a long time. I’ve written a number of articles on it and convinced a number of friends and family to start using it. But I’ve run into some issues with it and it’s come time to throw in the towel. I’m leaving Evernote.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="why-leave-evernote">Why leave Evernote?</h2>

<p>It’s proprietary. There are a lot of ways this <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/21/">becomes an issue</a> in my daily workflows.</p>

<ul>
  <li>I capture ideas in Drafts and want to move that text to an article I’m writing. I can’t easily get it into Evernote without a copy/paste in some form.</li>
  <li>Uploading files to Evernote creates a mess when you want to edit them. This is primarily an issue on iOS. You have to monkey around with sharing the file to and from other apps to make it work and it usually creates new problems somewhere.</li>
  <li>I write in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">markdown</a> and want to convert it to html. There is zero support for markdown in Evernote.</li>
</ul>

<p>I could go on, but I think you get the point. If you’re good with their format and like using the Evernote apps for editing everything, it’s great. But the moment you need to share the information with a non-Evernote user or edit it with something outside Evernote, the mess quickly grows.</p>

<p>I understand there is a <a href="https://blog.evernote.com/blog/2015/07/20/meet-evernotes-next-ceo-chris-oneill/">new sheriff at Evernote</a>, but if I want to have the freedom to use any app I want with the information I’m storing, I need to step away. I’m sure there are good things coming with the change in leadership and I genuinely hope it works out for them. I know a lot of people that rely on and love their service.</p>

<h2 id="the-new">The New</h2>

<p>I looked into a number of alternatives to Evernote. <a href="http://www.devontechnologies.com/">DEVONThink</a> led the pack with its standard file database on the backend. But no matter which of these “all-in-one” solutions I looked at, they all either have a proprietary file format or they require (or highly recommend) you to use their own apps to work with your data. Neither of those requirements are something I’m willing to meet.</p>

<p>I’m ultimately looking for a way to access standard files from any app I choose. In the current app world, that means the information needs to be stored in raw text, images, or PDFs. In order for these files to be used by almost any app I choose, it needs to use DropBox as a backend. With those two criteria in place, it was pretty easy to whittle this down to a simple folder structure in DropBox.</p>

<p>I should note that I wanted this alternative to be something that is easy for others to use as well. I could build a new proprietary system or one that uses shell scripts and such, but that’s not easily picked up by folks who aren’t interested in scripting their Mac. I wanted this to be accessible.</p>

<h2 id="the-structure">The Structure</h2>

<p>The base of the system is a folder structure in DropBox. The folder that I use as an inbox becomes the center point for collection. This is identical to my methods in Evernote. It’s called <em>!nbox</em>. Unless it has a preprocessed location, information goes here for organizing later.</p>

<p>After the inbox, I treat the remainder of my folder structure much like I would my tags from Evernote. Client projects have a dedicated folder under <em>Clients</em>. Each podcast episode has its own folder under <em>Podcasts</em>. This isn’t complicated.</p>

<p>The one grouping that gets special treatment is <em>Writing</em>. I keep a folder for all my writing (articles, podcast scripts, book chapters, website alterations) which is linked to Editorial to make writing from my phone easier. This is also linked to a <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/writing-with-github/">local git repository</a> on my Mac which allows me to review changes from my editor.</p>

<p>The base file formats I’m working with are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Text files</li>
  <li>Markdown files</li>
  <li>Images</li>
  <li>PDFs</li>
</ul>

<p>It’s pretty easy to find apps (no matter your OS) that will work with these file types, and their broad use means new apps are always being created to pair with them. Just look at <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/ios-text-editors/">Brett Terpstra’s iTextEditors</a> to see how many options you have on iOS for editing text files. There’s a bunch, and they keep coming.</p>

<h2 id="capturing">Capturing</h2>

<p>Storing and working with the files is the easy part. Collecting things is where Evernote shines. It can be dead simple to get stuff into it, but once you step away from features like the Web Clipper, it gets more difficult. In this new setup, installing and using the DropBox app on all my devices eliminates most of the friction.</p>

<p>There are three main types of information I find myself capturing:</p>

<h3 id="web-pages">1. Web Pages</h3>

<p>Sometimes I want to come back to a website because it’s interesting; sometimes the design of the site intrigues me; other times I’m just gathering a bunch of research for a project. In all cases, I need to be able to save the webpage for later and I need to be able to do it from the Mac <em>and</em> iOS.</p>

<p>It’s pretty simple on the Mac. There is a menu item called “Export as PDF…” under the File menu. You can <a href="http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-set-up-custom-keyboard-shortcuts-on-your-mac--mac-176">map this to a keyboard shortcut</a> (look at step 5) to make it faster to access. In my testing, these PDFs are full-text searchable as well.</p>

<p>From iOS, I was a bit stumped on this. I was trying to use Workflow to pull it off and kept thinking about ways to convert html to a PDF. But I couldn’t get it to work right, and it seemed jumbled. Eventually I took a step back to think (which is what I usually need to do when things start looking muddled) and deduced that I simply wanted a way to share a PDF to DropBox. Then I remembered the “Save to DropBox” button in the Share Sheet. Hold on to your hats: It turns out that <em>this will convert the web page to a searchable PDF for you.</em> I was pretty darn excited to figure that out.</p>

<h3 id="images">2. Images</h3>

<p>Most pictures I collect are done through my phone. I used to send pictures to my Mac using AirDrop and then move them to DropBox later. But when I discovered the “Save to DropBox” trick, those issues were gone. It saves an image directly to DropBox.</p>

<p>If I do take a screenshot with my Mac, I save it to the inbox or put it where it belongs right away, depending on what I’m doing. Working with images on the Mac in this way isn’t much different than how I was using Evernote. They simply land in a new place.</p>

<h3 id="text">3. Text</h3>

<p>If I’m grabbing a quick note on something, it starts in nvALT (which is synced with DropBox). If it’s an article or something longer, it goes into a Sublime Text project (also synced with DropBox). In either case, I can access the text from my phone in Editorial.</p>

<p>When I think of an idea or a paragraph I want to add to an article and I’m away from my Mac, I start in Drafts. I always start there, sometimes it stays there for a while. When it’s time for the text to leave, I can create new text files out of it or send it to another app. There are too many options for what you can do with it from Drafts to spell them all out now. Again, options are gold, and I can do pretty much anything I want from here.</p>

<h2 id="in-the-end">In The End</h2>

<p>I still have a lot of work to do pulling 14,000 notes from Evernote. I’m looking for ways to export the data and move it over, but for now I’m happy with where I’m putting all the new. It gets me away from a proprietary format and makes it a whole lot easier to use the apps I enjoy.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[23: White Space]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/23/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[margin]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/23/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Leaving space around the edges of your day can have a major impact on your productivity and happiness throughout the day. Also, I’m glad I don’t have an Apple Watch.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/White-Space.jpg" /><p>Leaving space around the edges of your day can have a major impact on your productivity and happiness throughout the day. Also, I’m glad I don’t have an Apple Watch.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/">The Joe Buhlig Discussions</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/22-addiction-to-numbers/177?u=joebuhlig">Discussion about paper schedule</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/omnifocus-workflows-with-shawn-blanc/167?u=joebuhlig">OmniFocus Workflows with Shawn Blanc</a></p>

<p><a href="http://shawnblanc.net/2016/01/margin-month/">Margin Month — Shawn Blanc</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/lost-in-transition/">Lost in Transition</a></p>

<p><a href="https://marco.org/2016/02/05/watch">The Apple Watch got me hooked on mechanical watches – Marco.org</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/22/">22: Addiction to Numbers</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/">Keyboard Maestro 7.0.3: Work Faster with Macros for Mac OS X</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[How to Create Energizing Rituals]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/how-to-create-energizing-rituals/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[rituals]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/how-to-create-energizing-rituals/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I learned about creating rituals after I read The Power of Full Engagement over a year ago. Since that time I’ve been figuring a few things out about building and implementing energizing rituals.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/How-to-Create-Energizing-Rituals.jpg" /><p>I learned about creating rituals after I read <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/power-full-engagement-book-review/">The Power of Full Engagement</a> over a year ago. Since that time I’ve been figuring a few things out about building and implementing energizing rituals.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="what-and-why">What and why?</h2>

<p>We’ve talked about the difference between <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/routine-vs-ritual/">ritual and routine</a> before, but the gist is that a routine is similar to a checklist that you go through each day and a ritual is a series of steps you take (just like a routine) that you find energizing or bring you enjoyment. This is an important distinction to make when you start learning to <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/power-full-engagement-book-review/">manage your energy levels</a> instead of your time.</p>

<p>If you’ve ever achieved more in a day than you did the entire previous week, you know what I mean by energy levels. Sometimes we naturally feel super energized and get a lot done. Then we all have “those days,” when just checking email feels daunting. When you build energizing rituals into your day, you can start to manufacture those moments of flow; but they aren’t always simple to create.</p>

<h2 id="finding-energizing-activities">Finding energizing activities</h2>

<p>What are your favorite topics to bring up with friends? What are the little things that you like doing or using but can’t explain why? What time of day do you look forward to?</p>

<p>I have a thing for fountain pens. I just like the way they write and that they’re different. I like the quality of the pens I use and look for excuses to write things down when I have them around.</p>

<p>Building things with my hands has always been a joy for me. After working on the computer throughout the day, I love the creative process of turning a piece of raw material into something useful.</p>

<p>I’m also a fan of the outdoors. Anytime I go outside to tackle the elements, I come back with a sense of accomplishment and pride.</p>

<p>I tell you these to give you ideas. The first step of building these rituals is understanding yourself and what you like to do. I bet you can nail these down pretty quickly if you stop for a couple minutes and think about it. Or if you have a spouse or close friend, ask them. There’s a good chance they can tell you what you love to do faster than you can. They have a different perspective that gives them a clearer view.</p>

<h2 id="converting-routines">Converting routines</h2>

<p>Whether you realize it or not, you use routines every day. You get up in the morning and get ready for work. You get ready for bed at night. Maybe you have a routine of daily journaling or playing with your kids after work. In any case, most have at least a few instances when they do something similar every day. These are the routines in your life.</p>

<p>You’ll have to decide which ones to convert (more on that in a moment), but the idea is to take an already existing routine and turn a piece of it into a ritual by injecting one of those energizing activities into it.</p>

<p>I have a routine that I run through at the end of my work day to plan for tomorrow. Recently, I started to do this plan on paper using my fountain pens. I enjoy using them and it takes a small neutral task and transforms it into an energizing one.</p>

<p>As a family, we enjoy spending time together when I get off of work. In the summer, we often take long walks with the girls. It’s a chance for me to get outside, get some exercise, and have a great conversation.</p>

<p>In both of these scenarios, I’ve been able to take something that I’m already doing and inject something into it. It makes them more fulfilling and gives me energy for whatever comes next in the day.</p>

<h2 id="which-routines">Which routines?</h2>

<p>The big question here is which routines do I try to convert? You don’t want to do this for everything or you’ll run out of time in the day and likely be way too energetic. We all know that guy who is way over the top and needs to settle down. Don’t be that guy.</p>

<p>Here’s the question to ask yourself: what times in the day do I feel like watching YouTube? It’s at least a good test for me. I know that if the only thing I want to do is stop and blow a few hours cruising YouTube, it’s a good time for me to stop and do something energizing. It can be simple, like checking in at the <a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com">discussion site</a> or it can be bigger, like taking 20 minutes to grab a snack with my family. No matter which energizing activity you decide to do, do it at a time when you need to increase your energy.</p>

<p>One word of caution: don’t do more than one at a time. Introduce a single ritual and stick with it until it’s second nature. Just like habits, if you try to take on more than one at a time, they’ll be overwhelming and have a negative effect instead of a positive.</p>

<p>In the end, you’re looking for things to do every day that will give you the energy to be more engaged with the people you see and the work you accomplish.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Budgeting and Irregular Expenses]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/budgeting-and-irregular-expenses/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[budget]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/budgeting-and-irregular-expenses/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[You’re cruising along and your bank account is looking good. But then, surprise! You get the bill for your car insurance premium and everything is out the window.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Budgeting-and-Irregular-Expenses.jpg" /><p>You’re cruising along and your bank account is looking good. But then, surprise! You get the bill for your car insurance premium and everything is out the window.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="the-budget-flaw">The Budget Flaw</h2>

<p>This is one of the flaws that most budgets face because they are weekly or monthly. But the timing doesn’t align with all the bills and wreaks havoc on the plan when you least expect it. Some bills come in monthly. Others come in annually or quarterly. But you normally won’t have an increase in income at the same time you have an unexpected or unplanned increase in expenses. It would be nice if it worked that way, but it’s wishful thinking.</p>

<h2 id="designated-funds">Designated Funds</h2>

<p>What if you had a fund set aside to pull from when these bills come in? You sometimes see these in company budgets: <em>designated funds</em>. They know that they’ll need to replace their employee computers some time in the future so they set aside dollars to pay for it when the need comes. This is exactly what we do to handle these abnormal bills.</p>

<p>I used to kick and scream about this because it cut into my <em>fun money</em> in a month, but I have to admit that it really helps stress levels. All that’s needed is some way to calculate and keep track of the allocated dollars in your budget. Create a separate fund for each of these bills and calculate how much you would pay if the bill was actually monthly (or weekly, depending on your budgeting period). That’s how much you need to pay yourself each period. When the bill comes in, just transfer the money you need into your budget for the month (increasing your income) and pay it. No stress involved.</p>

<h2 id="the-savings-tab">The Savings Tab</h2>

<p>I talked about this in the <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/time-and-dollars/">Time &amp; Dollars article</a>. There are items for my business that I know I will need to replace in the future. I want to upgrade my phone and computer regularly, so I need to put money into those designated funds in my budget. For the business budget, I’ve created a tab called Savings in the spreadsheet to handle everything for me (<a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1kDUSdsIKvtUnXxd4z9hgBQMUiht1oq_p6Iixl6dTyCU">see example budget</a>). It takes the amount of savings I have for the month, allows me to allocate it to each fund, and shows each fund’s balance.</p>

<p>The end goal here is to plan for these supposedly “unexpected” expenses. They aren’t truly unexpected when I know how much they will cost ahead of time and when they will be due. As long as I plan and save ahead, stress doesn’t have to enter the equation.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[22: Addiction to Numbers]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/22/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[addiction]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/22/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Since I started my business I’ve developed an addiction to checking numbers. But I watched a webinar last week that really changed the game for me and has me hand writing my schedule for the day.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Addiction-to-Numbers.jpg" /><p>Since I started my business I’ve developed an addiction to checking numbers. But I watched a webinar last week that really changed the game for me and has me hand writing my schedule for the day.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://learnomnifocus.com/tutorials/2016-01-28-omnifocus-workflows-with-shawn-blanc/?ref=11">OmniFocus Workflows with Shawn Blanc</a></p>

<p><a href="https://learnomnifocus.com/">Learn OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.timstringer.com/">Tim Stringer</a></p>

<p><a href="http://shawnblanc.net/">Shawn Blanc</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BBFkAYIORl0/">Shawn’s paper plan for the day</a></p>

<p><a href="https://farmerhank.com/">Farmer Hank</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>