<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="https://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 12:29:36 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[18: Decisive by Chip Heath, Dan Heath [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/18-decisive-by-chip-heath-dan-heath/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/18-decisive-by-chip-heath-dan-heath/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[A new baby, a continuing morning phone addiction, and learning how to make better decisions. It’s all covered in this week’s episode.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>A new baby, a continuing morning phone addiction, and learning how to make better decisions. It’s all covered in this week’s episode.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[17: QBQ! The Question Behind The Question by John Miller [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/17-qbq-the-question-behind-the-question-by-john-miller/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/17-qbq-the-question-behind-the-question-by-john-miller/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It may not be your fault, but you can take responsibility for it. Mike and Joe discuss the role of personal accountability in our lives and asking ourselves better questions.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>It may not be your fault, but you can take responsibility for it. Mike and Joe discuss the role of personal accountability in our lives and asking ourselves better questions.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[16: The Checklist Manifesto by Atul Gawande [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/16-the-checklist-manifesto-by-atul-gawande/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/16-the-checklist-manifesto-by-atul-gawande/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Mike loves his coffee and he’s trying to drag Joe along. But that still doesn’t stop them from talking checklists and the power they hold.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Mike loves his coffee and he’s trying to drag Joe along. But that still doesn’t stop them from talking checklists and the power they hold.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Top Five Books From 2016]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/top-five-books-from-2016/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/top-five-books-from-2016/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In the past I’ve wanted to be a reader and yet never picked up a book. But that changed when I said yes to Bookworm. Since then I’ve read 16 books for Bookworm and four more on my own. And I’m on pace to read three more by year’s end....]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/top-five-books-from-2016.jpg" /><p>In the past I’ve wanted to be a reader and yet never picked up a book. But that changed when I said yes to <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a>. Since then I’ve read 16 books for Bookworm and four more on my own. And I’m on pace to read three more by year’s end.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I was recently reflecting on the year and began thumbing through my growing collection of finished books. It was then that I realized I have a few favorites. So I figured why not share them with you? Here are my top five:</p>

<h2 id="deep-work-by-cal-newport">Deep Work by Cal Newport</h2>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/7/">Bookworm</a> - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Work-Focused-Success-Distracted/dp/1455586692/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>I’ve known the value of setting aside dedicated work sessions for a while. But it wasn’t until I read Deep Work and discussed it with Mike that the importance of disconnection and extended focus on a task fully struck me. It is within those times that my most valuable work emerges. Newport does an excellent job explaining the how and why behind deep work sessions.</p>

<h2 id="the-war-of-art-by-stephen-pressfield">The War of Art by Stephen Pressfield</h2>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/3/">Bookworm</a> - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/War-Art-Through-Creative-Battles/dp/1936891026/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>Regardless of whether we realize or confess it, we are all creative in some way. The degree of creativity within us varies, of course, but it’s there. The trouble is fighting the voice in our mind that tells us not to create and keeps us from doing unique work. Pressfield calls this Resistance and he carefully picks apart the tactics Resistance uses to stop us. I consider this a must-read for anyone who is a maker or who uses knowledge to do their work.</p>

<h2 id="daring-greatly-by-brené-brown">Daring Greatly By Brené Brown</h2>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/9/">Bookworm</a> - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Daring-Greatly-Courage-Vulnerable-Transforms/dp/1592408419/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>Being vulnerable is not something most of us do voluntarily. And for some of us it invokes fear. The last thing on our minds is being open, honest, and willing to endure rejection. But as Brown points out, that is exactly what we must do in order to achieve and build meaningful relationships. It’s also the key ingredient to accomplishing the big and the impactful. It helps us take a chance and do something important.</p>

<h2 id="managing-oneself-by-peter-drucker">Managing Oneself By Peter Drucker</h2>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/13/">Bookworm</a> - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Managing-Oneself-Harvard-Business-Classics/dp/142212312X/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>Over the last two years I’ve been on a journey of self-awareness. The value of understanding myself, how I think, and what makes me a good worker is invaluable. Despite having started this adventure previously, Drucker drives the point home in this quick read. It’s packed full of insights that will make you slow down and process the words. This book changed my view of myself and helped me ask the necessary questions that prompted a plethora of personal insight.</p>

<h2 id="the-checklist-manifesto-by-atul-gawande">The Checklist Manifesto By Atul Gawande</h2>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/16/">Bookworm</a> - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Checklist-Manifesto-How-Things-Right/dp/0312430000?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>I’ve been a list maker for years. I know they have a lot of value, but I had never realized why they help and their importance in everyday projects until I read this story by Gawande. As a surgeon, he explains his journey and continual discoveries that led him to the creation of a “safe surgery” checklist. It’s the process and the volume of stories that reveal the power of the simple checklist.</p>

<h2 id="bonus-gods-smuggler-by-brother-andrew">Bonus: God’s Smuggler By Brother Andrew</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Gods-Smuggler-Brother-Andrew/dp/0800796853/ref=la_B000APEW2M_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Amazon</a></p>

<p>Brother Andrew has quite a story about his life of taking Bibles behind the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iron_Curtain">Iron Curtain</a>. It’s one of encouragement and brings with it motivation and a call to action for the Christian. I highly recommend it to anyone interested in a story about the power of the Bible.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Time Tracker With Running Status]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/time-tracker-with-running-status/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/time-tracker-with-running-status/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve been tracking where I spend my time for a while now. In the majority of cases it has been purely for personal use and decision-making, but since I have now taken a part time IT position, I need to know exactly how many hours I spend on the job...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/time-tracker-with-running-status.jpg" /><p>I’ve been tracking where I spend my time for a while now. In the majority of cases it has been purely for personal use and decision-making, but since I have now taken a part time IT position, I need to know exactly how many hours I spend on the job and calculate whether or not I’ve met my expected quota for the week.
<!--more--></p>

<p>In theory, it’s simple. I work 20 hours a week as Director of IT at my church. But how do I know if I’m under or over my allotted time? I could go off a feeling, but I’m certain I’ll always be wrong in my estimate.</p>

<p>Instead, I did what I always do: set up a system to track it for me. And with the power of IFTTT, Launch Center Pro, and Workflow, I’m able to let Google Sheets do all the hard work. In the end, this is what I see when I check my status:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/time-tracker-with-running-status/time-tracker.jpg" /></p>

<p>Getting the spreadsheet set up is easier by copy-paste than it is by explanation. The formulas are simply too much and too involved to explain. So I created a <a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1X2gVw4j-dM6nz1jpGnKqyEONQWPm-Zk61n_P8yKTbOk">copy of my tracker</a> for you to view and replicate.</p>

<p>The part you’ll need to edit is on the Report worksheet. You can manually adjust the Available Hours per week and it will take care of the rest.</p>

<p>As for data entry, I do it all through IFTTT. There are a lot of ways to do it but setting up applets to add a row to a Google Sheet is fairly straightforward.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[15: BrainChains by Theo Compernolle [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/15-brainchains-by-theo-compernolle/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/15-brainchains-by-theo-compernolle/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[BrainChains was a listener recommendation that taught Mike and Joe a lot about how technology affects our minds. From attention to focus, it’s all covered.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>BrainChains was a listener recommendation that taught Mike and Joe a lot about how technology affects our minds. From attention to focus, it’s all covered.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using a Cloudfront CDN for Jekyll Without S3]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/using-a-cloudfront-cdn-for-jekyll-without-s3/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[jekyll]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-a-cloudfront-cdn-for-jekyll-without-s3/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[On occasion I find myself with a sliver of free time. And it seems inevitable that I use it to tinker with this site. Given my latest obsession with page load speeds, this time I directed my attention towards the implementation of a CDN.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/using-a-cloudfront-cdn-for-jekyll-without-s3.jpg" /><p>On occasion I find myself with a sliver of free time. And it seems inevitable that I use it to tinker with this site. Given my latest obsession with page load speeds, this time I directed my attention towards the implementation of a CDN.
<!--more--></p>

<p>This is an idea I stole from Brett Terpstra who has an <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2014/02/21/a-jekyll-cdn-with-cloudfront/">article about his method</a> of doing the same. My case has some slight differences and if you do a search for how to use Cloudfront with Jekyll, you’ll be hard-pressed to find an explanation of how to do it without using S3 for your hosting. Which is why I felt compelled to share my process with you.</p>

<p>I chose <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/">Cloudfront</a> because I’m a fan of <a href="https://aws.amazon.com">AWS</a> (Amazon Web Services) and they are fairly cheap in comparison to the other big names in industry. I’ve worked with AWS enough in the past to trust it. But here’s how I set up Cloudfront to work with Jekyll:</p>

<h2 id="setting-up-cloudfront">Setting Up Cloudfront</h2>

<p>Once you have an account with AWS, open Cloudfront from the management console and create a new web distribution. There are only three settings I changed from the default.</p>

<p><strong>Origin Domain Name</strong> - This is your site homepage. I entered <code class="highlighter-rouge">joebuhlig.com</code></p>

<p><strong>Origin ID</strong> - This is merely a description you want for the origin. I used <code class="highlighter-rouge">joebuhlig.com Resources</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Alternate Domain Names</strong> - This becomes the new base URL you’ll use to serve the files from Cloudfront. I was very original and used <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn.joebuhlig.com</code> for this.</p>

<p>With the settings in place and the distribution created, you’ll be given a domain name for your distribution that looks similar to this: <code class="highlighter-rouge">abcdefg123456.cloudfront.net</code> We’ll use this to set up our DNS record.</p>

<h2 id="setting-up-dns">Setting Up DNS</h2>

<p>I’m not going into each registrar here, but the idea is to create a CNAME record on your domain with the host as your subdomain (in my case <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn</code>) and the target as the domain name given for your distribution in the previous step (<code class="highlighter-rouge">abcdefg123456.cloudfront.net</code>).</p>

<p>You want to give this some time to populate and to allow AWS to do its magic. I left it alone and went to work on converting the URLs within Jekyll to accommodate the new CDN URL: <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn.joebuhlig.com</code>.</p>

<h2 id="setting-up-jekyll">Setting Up Jekyll</h2>

<p>As a Jekyll user, you are probably familiar with using the Liquid tag <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span></code>. That variable is coming from the <code class="highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file and we simply want to add <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code> to it. Mine looks like this:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="s">baseurl</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s2">"</span><span class="s">"</span>
<span class="s">url</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s2">"</span><span class="s">http://joebuhlig.com"</span>
<span class="s">cdn_url</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">http://cdn.joebuhlig.com</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>With <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code> in place, you need to go through your static files and image references and change the base URL from a relative reference or <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span></code> to <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.cdn_url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span></code> instead. I recommend previewing this before you deploy it just to make sure it’s working correctly and that Cloudfront is fully up and running. You can also test this by navigating to the base <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code> itself and check if a copy of your site is available. If not, you need to wait for the DNS changes to populate.</p>

<h2 id="jekyll-development">Jekyll Development</h2>

<p>A problem you’ll quickly run into is doing development of CSS and JS when your assets are being served from a CDN. In my workflow I run two commands: <code class="highlighter-rouge">jekyll s --future</code> to test and preview my site and <code class="highlighter-rouge">JEKYLL_ENV=production jekyll b</code> for a production build right before deployment. This allows me to use the Liquid variable <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">jekyll.environment</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span></code> to test if I am in production, like so:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">%</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">if</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">jekyll.environment</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">==</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">'production'</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">%</span><span class="p">}{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.cdn_url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">%</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">endif</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">%</span><span class="p">}</span></code></p>

<p>If you use this in conjunction with the <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code>, it means that when I’m building for production, the <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code> is added and empty if it’s for development. I’m left with relative and local URLs in development and the full CDN URL in production.</p>

<h2 id="cache-busting">Cache Busting</h2>

<p>The last step here is adding a version number to the static assets that change fairly frequently. There are a number of ways to do this but I prefer the tried-and-true query string: <code class="highlighter-rouge">main.css?v=5</code></p>

<p>Just like the <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code>, I added <code class="highlighter-rouge">version: 1</code> to my <code class="highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file. That allows me to append any asset URL to look like this: <code class="highlighter-rouge">/assets/main.css?v={{ site.version}}</code> When used at the same time as the <code class="highlighter-rouge">cdn_url</code>, I’m left with this:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">%</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">if</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">jekyll.environment</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">==</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">'production'</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">%</span><span class="p">}{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.cdn_url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">%</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">endif</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">%</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">/assets/css/main.css?v=</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">site.version</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="err">}</span></code></p>

<p>Now, I’m lazy and don’t want to manually increment this version number every time I want to bust the cache so I again <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2013/03/05/site-versioning-with-jekyll/">stole a page from Brett Terpstra’s book</a> and wrote a rake task to do it for me:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">desc</span> <span class="s2">"Bump version number"</span>
<span class="n">task</span> <span class="ss">:bump</span> <span class="k">do</span>
    <span class="n">content</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">IO</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">read</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'_config.yml'</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="n">content</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">sub!</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sr">/^version: (\d+)$/</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span><span class="o">|</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="o">|</span>
        <span class="n">ver</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="vg">$1</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">next</span>
        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"At version </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">ver</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
        <span class="s2">"version: </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">ver</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="no">File</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">open</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'_config.yml'</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s1">'w'</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">f</span><span class="o">|</span>
        <span class="n">f</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">write</span> <span class="n">content</span>
    <span class="k">end</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now all I need to do is run <code class="highlighter-rouge">rake bump</code> after I’ve edited static files and it will take care of the rest.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Baby Time Checklist]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/a-baby-time-checklist/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[checklists]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-baby-time-checklist/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[As I write this, my wife and I are expecting our third baby girl to join us within the next week. I wish I could say there is nothing but pure excitement in our house, but as anyone who has kids knows, there are a number of things to do...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/a-baby-time-checklist.jpg" /><p>As I write this, my wife and I are expecting our third baby girl to join us within the next week. I wish I could say there is nothing but pure excitement in our house, but as anyone who has kids knows, there are a number of things to do once you know it is “time.” Depending on your situation, which you can’t predetermine, you may not have much time to accomplish everything and get out the door, so most of us put together a checklist to help us remember.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I use checklists all the time. They are a prominent fixture in my life and it is inevitable that others see me using or creating them. In most cases there is one of two responses: an agreement that the checklist is helpful or a joke about its worthlessness for them.</p>

<p>But despite the reaction, I know I’ll stick by my list. I’m all too aware of the shortcomings of my memory. Even if I remember an item the first 50 times through, eventually it becomes second nature and I’ll be unable to recall if I completed a task or just think I did. It’s much like trying to remember if you closed the garage door. You’ve done it so many times that the task is automatic and there’s nothing to trigger your memory to indicate that you actually did it this time. So you’re left wondering if it happened at all, or turning around to make sure it’s shut.</p>

<p>In the case of going into labor, I want my focus to be on helping my wife. But I still need to make sure all bags are in the car, the hospital is aware that we are coming, that someone is home to watch our girls, and on and on. The situation could be one of extreme urgency (at least to me) and yet I want and need to be attentive to my wife. Thus, a checklist to spell out these mundane but important tasks.</p>

<p>I have a list of things to do that kicks off the moment my wife starts having contractions. It doesn’t make me a robot, it gives my mind the freedom to be attentive to situational needs without worrying about what comes next. The potential for urgency and stress is high. In that moment I want to be there for my wife and not wandering the house trying to make sure I have everything in place. This checklist is far from impersonal. It allows me to be present.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Creating Custom Web Searches in Alfred]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/creating-custom-web-searches-in-alfred/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[alfred]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/creating-custom-web-searches-in-alfred/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Searching is one of the most technically complicated processes to build and yet the simplest to use. And it’s almost universally accepted that every website has a way to search the entirety of their content. Connect this with the ability to search websites directly from Alfred and you can create...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/creating-custom-web-searches-in-alfred.jpg" /><p>Searching is one of the most technically complicated processes to build and yet the simplest to use. And it’s almost universally accepted that every website has a way to search the entirety of their content. Connect this with the ability to search websites directly from Alfred and you can create a one-stop shop for searching all your favorite sites.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Alfred can do searches in Google and many other websites out-of-the-box. But if you notice yourself searching a specific website repeatedly, it makes sense to set up a custom search within Alfred. If you continually repeat this process, you’ll end up using Alfred for all your searches instead of going through the multiple steps required to open a site, find the search bar, and type your query.</p>

<p>To set up a new custom search, you first need to know how the site handles search queries from a URL standpoint. For joebuhlig.com, this is what that looks like:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">http://joebuhlig.com/search/?q=</code></pre></figure>

<p>Once you have that information, open Alfred preferences, go to Features, then Web Search. At the bottom-right you’ll see “Add Custom Search.” From there, simply fill out the details you want for the search. Here’s the full example for this site:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="https://cdn.joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/creating-custom-web-searches-in-alfred/alfred-custom-search.jpg" /></p>

<p>To make it even easier, you can <a href="alfred://customsearch/Search%20joebuhlig.com%20for%20%7Bquery%7D/joe/utf8/nospace/http%3A%2F%2Fjoebuhlig.com%2Fsearch%2F%3Fq%3D%7Bquery%7D">click here to install it directly</a>.</p>

<p>Using this search is quite simple. Invoke Alfred, type “joe” followed by your query. It’ll look like this:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-large" src="https://cdn.joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/creating-custom-web-searches-in-alfred/alfred-search.jpg" /></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using Discourse for IT]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/using-discourse-for-it/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[discourse]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-discourse-for-it/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m a fan of Discourse. That should come without surprise at this point. As a fan, it’s natural for me to see the potential for Discourse to solve communication problems and create selective visibility within an organization. So it was easy for me to gravitate toward it for the IT...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/using-discourse-for-it.jpeg" /><p>I’m a fan of <a href="http://discourse.org">Discourse</a>. That should come without surprise at this point. As a fan, it’s natural for me to see the potential for Discourse to solve communication problems and create selective visibility within an organization. So it was easy for me to gravitate toward it for the IT communication structure at my church.
<!--more--></p>

<p>To the best of my knowledge, there are four areas that need to be clearly conveyed and accessible to those I support: technology needs, how tos, structural upgrades, and technical documentation. In my case, I have two groups of people to work with: staff members and tech volunteers. The staff needs to share their support requests and have access to the knowledgebase, while the tech team handles the infrastructure and documentation.</p>

<p>In Discourse, this translates quite well. I can create four topic categories (Support, How To, Infrastructure, and Documentation), and two user groups (<code class="highlighter-rouge">staff_members</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">tech_team</code>).  Distinguishing by user groups, I can restrict access as needed in each category.</p>

<p>In my case, there are some end users that will likely struggle if I require them to use Discourse directly. I don’t say this to be mean but to acknowledge that their strengths are outside of computer systems. Understanding this, I take advantage of the email-in feature of Discourse as well as reply-via-email.</p>

<p>My users can send an email to the system and have it handled automatically. Whether it’s a new ticket or a reply to a support update, they can interact solely from their email. Outside of setting up their accounts, they never have to access the system directly. They can stick to what they know: email.</p>

<p>Here’s a breakdown of how each category is used:</p>

<h2 id="support">Support</h2>

<p>This is used primarily for issues and support tickets. Both the staff and tech team can access it and users can send an email into this category. When one of these is completed, I simply close the topic.</p>

<h2 id="how-to">How To</h2>

<p>These topics are checklists or videos explaining how to accomplish a specific task within our building and structures. These can range from website updates to installing printer drivers. Again, this is viewable by both staff and the tech team, but currently I have it restricted so only I can create new topics. I want to vet these before they’re posted.</p>

<h2 id="infrastructure">Infrastructure</h2>

<p>Only the tech team can use this one. It’s designed to capture and discuss system upgrades and migrations as well as the little things we need in order to improve the reliability and functionality of our hardware and software. I think of it as a technical version of the support category.</p>

<h2 id="documentation">Documentation</h2>

<p>Again, this is tech team only. And most of these topics are wiki-fied so that team members can update them as changes are made. These can be descriptions of VLANs or they may list the base computers we use when a replacement is needed. Anything that helps describe the infrastructure so that others can step in should go here.</p>

<p>I’m aware that there are a lot of software options available that are specifically designed for these purposes. And the number of communication methods is endless. But after having worked with and for multiple companies, I’ve seen the pros and cons of using many of them. In most cases the IT team ends up hacking them together to do what they want. Or worse, they lose track of a request in the stream of posts.</p>

<p>What I love about Discourse is its flexibility and configurability. I can dial up or down individual pieces and even allow end-users to avoid it entirely. Telling my staff members that they simply need to send email is tremendously more effective than training how to navigate a new piece of software.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[14: The 12 Week Year by Brian Moran, Michael Lennington [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/14-the-12-week-year-by-brian-moran-michael-lennington/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/14-the-12-week-year-by-brian-moran-michael-lennington/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[If you’re looking for a way to set goals and achieve a year’s worth of work in 12 weeks, then The 12 Week Year is an excellent choice and structure to try.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>If you’re looking for a way to set goals and achieve a year’s worth of work in 12 weeks, then The 12 Week Year is an excellent choice and structure to try.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Hybrid Productivity]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/hybrid-productivity/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/hybrid-productivity/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There’s a common misconception in the productivity world that when you develop a new process or system it needs to be entirely digital or entirely analog. Or the more common version of this dilemma: to work toward the use of a single database for your tasks. That may be nice,...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/hybrid-productivity.jpg" /><p>There’s a common misconception in the productivity world that when you develop a new process or system it needs to be entirely digital or entirely analog. Or the more common version of this dilemma: to work toward the use of a single database for your tasks. That may be nice, but it’s far from necessary.
<!--more--></p>

<p>In one week, I join the staff of our local church as Director of IT. As a part of that role, there needs to be a way to track the projects I have going on at the church. A handful of other folks will also be participating in the collection of those projects, as well as taking ownership of them.</p>

<p>For this reason (and many others), I set up a <a href="http://discourse.org">Discourse forum</a> to help me manage the work I do at the church. I can try to duplicate tasks and projects across Discourse and OmniFocus, but why? Yes, this creates two systems to maintain but they serve completely separate purposes. They need to be broken up.</p>

<p>The key here lies in boundaries and hard lines. OmniFocus manages the work I personally need to do and Discourse will track the work I need to do at the church. But this only works if I treat the church as its own context. I work off of Discourse when I am “on the clock.” I shut it off when I’m on my own time.</p>

<p>The same process works with digital tools combined with analog. As long as there are clear lines where one drops off and the other picks up, all is well. It’s when you try to mix systems, duplicate tasks, and create sync methods that issues arise and unnecessary problems surface. It’s okay to use multiple systems.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Auto-Archiving Emails in Gmail]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[email]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In the midst of reading for Bookworm, I discovered my habit of quickly checking my email throughout the day. It’s a simple habit on the surface, but try to break it and you’ll find that willpower alone may not be enough to win.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail.jpeg" /><p>In the midst of reading for <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a>, I discovered my habit of quickly checking my email throughout the day. It’s a simple habit on the surface, but try to break it and you’ll find that willpower alone may not be enough to win.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I set out to create resistance to checking my email from my phone. I can remove it entirely but I have legitimate scenarios that dictate the checking of email on the go. Since I can’t remove it, I decided to force difficulties when opening an email in any scenario.</p>

<p>Instead of removing email on my phone, I wrote a Google Apps Script that moves any read message in my inbox to the archive. And it does so once every minute. It’s basic and seems to not accomplish much since the messages end up in my archive anyway. But what if I need to reply? What if I need to act on that email? If I open it and don’t reply immediately or don’t capture in some way, it’s gone. Not completely, but it’s moved out of sight. And I will likely drop the ball since there is no placeholder in my inbox. That by itself is enough to keep me from opening mails on my phone. I can’t have them disappear.</p>

<p>I should warn you that if you decide to set this up, it will be frustrating at first. I failed immediately and checked my email shortly after installing the script. I saw a message I wanted to read but knew I couldn’t touch it or it would be gone since I didn’t have time to act on it. I spent a lot of time trying to get around this setup and quickly found that I couldn’t check a mail without a lot of extra steps. It’s a lot easier to not check it at all.</p>

<p><strong>Warning: Before going further, make sure read messages are ready to be archived. They will be moved.</strong></p>

<p>To set this up you need to go to your Google Drive and created a new Google Apps Script. Here’s the code to paste into that script:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">autoArchiveGmail</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">threads</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">GmailApp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">search</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'label:inbox is:read'</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="k">for</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">i</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="nx">i</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="nx">threads</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">length</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="nx">i</span><span class="o">++</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nx">threads</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">i</span><span class="p">].</span><span class="nx">moveToArchive</span><span class="p">();</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>To run it the first time, click the debugger icon and give the script access to your Gmail:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/debugger.jpg" /></p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/permissions.jpg" /></p>

<p>Once the script is in place, set up a new trigger for it:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/trigger_menu.jpg" /></p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-large" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/autoarchiving-emails-in-gmail/trigger.jpg" /></p>

<p>I wish you all the best in checking email from your phone.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Food and Productivity (From a Farm Boy)]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/food-and-productivity-from-a-farm-boy/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[food]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/food-and-productivity-from-a-farm-boy/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We all need to eat. The consequences of rejecting that fact are far from pleasant and none of us would argue this reality. The problem comes when choosing which foods to consume. It’s not enough that our supermarkets are overflowing and options are endless; we have corporate marketing schemes, dietary...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/food-and-productivity-from-a-farm-boy.jpeg" /><p>We all need to eat. The consequences of rejecting that fact are far from pleasant and none of us would argue this reality. The problem comes when choosing which foods to consume. It’s not enough that our supermarkets are overflowing and options are endless; we have corporate marketing schemes, dietary standards, and fear mongering to battle.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I was raised on a large crop farm and I have worked with, for, and around farmers and agricultural companies my entire life. In my journey I’ve helped raise crops and animals, develop new seed varieties and hybrids, and aided the marketing efforts of all the above. I understand what goes on behind the scenes of our food system quite well. And it’s this understanding that has given me clarity in choosing what to eat.</p>

<p>Some of these choices are purely for health reasons. Some are made out of a concern of the unknown or the constantly changing science of diet. But regardless of the rationale behind these decisions, they all lead me to an increase in energy and mental precision. And you could argue that these two results are the foundation of productivity, which means the justification I’ve developed for what I eat is tied not only to a healthy diet but also to my ability to complete tasks.</p>

<p>Enough of the groundwork, let’s jump in with an easy one: processed foods. Most people I encounter understand that these are best left alone. I like to think of them in terms of natural and manufactured complexity. In its natural state, a potato has a lot of complexity to it. There are a lot of nutrients in the skin as well as the heart. But it’s the combination of the two parts that allows it to achieve its dietary value.</p>

<p>But when you remove an element of the potato and introduce a foreign element, you have now manufactured a new complex arrangement of nutrients. Or in some cases, an element is removed and then replaced with a theoretically identical element that comes from a different, cheaper source. In either case, we’ve created a food item that doesn’t exist naturally in our environment. Some scenarios indicate that this is perfectly fine. But most lead to health issues due to a lack of understanding in how to create a food that is perfectly digested and beneficial to the human body. Or, as in most companies, the desire to create a healthy, processed food is secondary to profit.</p>

<p>One of the most difficult and hotly debated conversations you can have about food revolves around GMOs, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genetically_modified_organism">Genetically Modified Organisms</a>. These are crops that have received a DNA alteration in order to enhance or add a trait within the crop. This usually leads people to seeing them as “frankenfoods” but that’s an exaggeration of the facts. The traits being added are typically found within the same species, just not the specific strain that’s being altered. This isn’t always the case, but generally speaking it holds true. The idea of pulling traits from strawberries and combining them with corn is mythology and typically used by fear mongers.</p>

<p>That said, there are tremendous benefits to GMOs. They’ve enabled food producers to grow exponentially higher yields and feed the world with fewer resources and less land. And it is true that they’ve helped farmers cut back significantly on the volume of chemicals used on their land. I’ve seen this transition first hand and I can tell you that the numbers you see on this are conservative. GMOs have proven highly beneficial to everyone raising crops.</p>

<p>However, there is a growing concern over the safety of GMOs. Despite there being a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genetically_modified_crops#Crops">small number of GM crops they have been approved</a>, it <em>is</em> true that they make it into our food system. Which begs the question, are they safe for me to eat?</p>

<p>You can answer this question one of two ways: scientifically or with cautious reasoning. If you read the studies on GMOs, you’ll quickly conclude that they are perfectly safe. But to land at this conclusion you have to trust the source of the studies. In most cases, that source is either the company selling the GM crop or the company selling its processed form to you and me. Personally, I’m not convinced they’re able to do these studies with a completely unbiased approach. And knowing that some of these researchers (I’ve worked with them) will repeat a study multiple times looking for a particular result, I’m often skeptical of their findings.</p>

<p>The other way to answer the GMO safety question is with cautious reasoning. We know that eating whole fruits and vegetables is good for our bodies. There seems to be a perfect relationship between our physical needs and the offerings of these whole foods. If we intentionally alter the makeup of these foods genetically or with post-harvest processing, we are breaking this existing relationship and introducing a new one. It also means that how our bodies react may have unwanted effects on our energy and overall health. This new relationship <em>could</em> work out to be fine. But we’re introducing risk, since there’s so much about the human body we don’t know. We can’t truly comprehend the full impact this new relationship has on our long-term health. I don’t understand why I should voluntarily take this risk. Why would I choose the unknown when the known has a long list (and history) of benefits?</p>

<p>Just to be clear, <em>I’m not saying you should completely avoid and vilify GM foods.</em> They do have a place and save lives daily. But if given a choice and available resources, I err on the side of caution.</p>

<p>Given my experiences, I have learned that eating healthfully has a major impact on my ability to think clearly and creatively. And the better I feel, the better equipped I am to be productive. So to be wise with my time and energy, I need to eat well. For me, that means the consumption of simple, natural foods.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Stop The Should]]></title>
    <link>https://joebuhlig.com/stop-the-should/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[expectations]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/stop-the-should/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One of the strongest fears I grapple with is that of rejection. Like most, I want people to appreciate the work I do and me as a person. My struggle develops when I sense a dislike or underappreciation directed towards me in some way. Red flags start flying and I...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="https://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/stop-the-should.jpeg" /><p>One of the strongest fears I grapple with is that of rejection. Like most, I want people to appreciate the work I do and me as a person. My struggle develops when I sense a dislike or underappreciation directed towards me in some way. Red flags start flying and I find myself searching for ways to get out of the scenario.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Over time, I’ve learned who to trust and when. And although I rarely follow through on my thoughts about running away, I still have this nagging sense about what is expected of me. Instead of acting on my fear, I try to weigh it and pay attention to what the other person expects me to do.</p>

<p>However, this presupposition of actions can also rear its head in situations involving only myself. There are times when I feel the need to incorporate something new into my daily schedule. The latest case here is my need for more sleep. Rather than sleep longer at night, I’ve felt that an afternoon nap would better suit me. The fear and “should” that creeps in is telling me that I don’t have time for a nap everyday. I have enough to do. I can’t pull more time away for “leisure.”</p>

<p>Here’s the problem with these scenarios: they leave me feeling like I should say or do something because unspoken expectations have been placed on me. I’m expected to go along with a conversation I don’t agree with. I’m expected to maximize my time perfectly every day. I’m expected to utilize every app or tool to its fullest potential.</p>

<p>These are all things I <em>should</em> do. And when I stop long enough to notice when a “should” has been placed on me, I often find myself asking why. Why should I do this thing? “Because Joe expects it” or “because I paid decent money for this app” aren’t always the best answers. It’s taken time (and I’m still learning) to put a stop to the “should” that is placed on me and gain the confidence to think for myself.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>