<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:44:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Guest Posting]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/guest-posting/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/guest-posting/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Over the past month I’ve made some design changes and layout alterations here on the site. Some of that was purely for aesthetics and ease of use, but it also included some back-end alterations to allow guest posting. I’ve debated this for a long time and I’m finally ready to...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/guest-posting.jpeg" /><p>Over the past month I’ve made some design changes and layout alterations here on the site. Some of that was purely for aesthetics and ease of use, but it also included some back-end alterations to allow guest posting. I’ve debated this for a long time and I’m finally ready to pull the trigger.
<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>You can read the details about how to participate on the <a href="/guest">guest posting page</a>.</strong></p>

<p>One of the best ways to expand our thinking is to explore new ideas and perspectives that may differ from our own. It forces us to formulate our own opinions on the subject. We may love the thought or think it’s trash but either way, making that decision helps us understand our own reasoning behind the subject. By allowing others to write articles for this site, we can see glimpses of how others operate and think, which broadens the perspective on productivity conveyed here.</p>

<p>This also frees up some of my own time. I really like the current posting cadence, but I’m looking to direct some of my writing time to new areas. I have a couple important projects I’m working on that I want to dedicate more time to and I know there will be more projects when those are complete. Guest posting will allow the rhythm to continue and these new areas to accelerate.</p>

<p>I can continue listing reasons why I think this is a good thing, but you get the point. There’s a lot of value that can come to all of us. So if you’re interested in sharing your thoughts and words with readers like yourself (even if you’ve never written an article before), check out the details on the <a href="/guest">guest posting page</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[37: Reading Books vs Articles]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/37/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[adhd]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/37/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[As I learn how to handle the good and bad that comes from being ADHD, I’ve learned the power of reading books over articles.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/reading-books-vs-articles.jpg" /><p>As I learn how to handle the good and bad that comes from being ADHD, I’ve learned the power of reading books over articles.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Delivered-Distraction-Getting-Attention-Disorder/dp/0345442318?tag=joebuhlig-20">Delivered From Distraction</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/alternating-types-of-tasks/">Alternating Types of Tasks</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/writing-articles-by-hand/">Writing Articles By Hand</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.macstories.net/">MacStories - Federico Viticci</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Alternating Types of Tasks]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/alternating-types-of-tasks/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[task-management]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/alternating-types-of-tasks/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There’s something liberating about putting a name to something you didn’t understand. This was my exact experience when I learned I am ADHD. It gave me words to explain the way I think and those words have given way to a deeper comprehension of how I operate.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/alternating-types-of-tasks.jpeg" /><p>There’s something liberating about putting a name to something you didn’t understand. This was my exact experience when I learned I am ADHD. It gave me words to explain the way I think and those words have given way to a deeper comprehension of how I operate.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Putting a name to it also makes it easier to connect with people in the same boat. And it makes it possible to learn what others do to take advantage of the positives and overcome the negatives. So naturally, I did some research and found that many try to eradicate it entirely. It’s seen as a disease to overcome. But you may be doing yourself an injustice by trying to delete a portion of who you are. I would rather heighten the useful aspects and downplay the detrimental. If I have an overactive mind, is there a way to allow myself to bounce from thing to thing and still accomplish my creative work? After a bit of experimentation, I’ve discovered a way to do this.</p>

<p>I can only will myself to focus on a new task for about 20 minutes - unless I’m really excited or interested in it, then it can be days before I come up for air. But when I’m not in hyperfocus mode, 20 minutes is about all I have.</p>

<p>For a long time I’ve been breaking my projects down into 15 - 20 minute tasks. My focus-ability may be why I’ve done that but I can’t say for certain. Typically, I would sit down and work on a project with the intent of completing three or four of these tasks. And I’ve had fairly good success doing so. But it’s never occurred to me that this was a bad idea. It’s what everyone else does and they seem to have a great success with it. Why shouldn’t I follow suit?</p>

<p>Learning that I am ADHD gave me the clarity I needed to explore other options. If I can naturally focus on a task for 20 minutes, what if I started a completely different type of task afterwards instead of doing more of the same? What if I alternate between coding, writing, learning, and admin every 20 minutes?</p>

<p>Bingo! It turns out that I’ve wanted to work this way all along, but I couldn’t see it. Yes, there are times when I get into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">flow</a> and won’t switch. If I can focus for longer, why move on? But if I can’t focus, I don’t fight it. I switch to a different type of task and come back at the next switch off. After all, I tend the bounce quickly. Why not take advantage of it?</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[What To Review]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/what-to-review/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/what-to-review/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[The longer I practice GTD principles, the more intentional I try to be with the time I spend updating my systems. I need my commitments to be thought through and my decisions to be made ahead of time. Knowing that I am prone to starting new projects before I have...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/what-to-review.jpeg" /><p>The longer I practice GTD principles, the more intentional I try to be with the time I spend updating my systems. I need my commitments to be thought through and my decisions to be made ahead of time. Knowing that I am prone to starting new projects before I have time for them leads me to a need for a recurring time of reevaluation.
<!--more--></p>

<p>David Allen declares the Weekly Review a vital component of the framework. And I would agree that this once-weekly update is a <em>make it or break it</em> step to success. Without it, I would have a growing list of stalled projects that should be dropped, or at least moved to a Someday/Maybe list. But I’ve also found other levels of review to be beneficial. And those are better done at different intervals than the Weekly Review. It’s not worth my time to evaluate each context and project every morning. I would spend the vast majority of my time in reflection and never accomplish the tasks I’m reviewing.</p>

<p>The glaring question here is “What do you actually do during these reviews?” The easy thing to do is share a picture of my checklists, but that fails to explain the reasoning for the review itself. You are free to copy these, but be sure to think through your intent and understand why you are doing it before you tweak these to fit your personality. There’s potentially more harm in aimlessly going through these than in skipping them altogether.</p>

<h2 id="daily-review-20-mins">Daily Review (~20 mins)</h2>

<p>The first step in GTD is Capture. It all starts with the habit of putting tasks and ideas into an inbox. My problem is that without daily time for making a decision about each item, inboxes perpetually grow. At the same time, I struggle to jump start my day. Despite the system, I’m drawn to the most urgent or interesting thing on my mind and want to focus on it first thing in the morning. To combat this I set up the Daily Review with the purpose of clearing inboxes and creating motivation on the right task.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Process Inbox: Paper</li>
  <li>Process Inbox: Email</li>
  <li>Process Inbox: Drafts</li>
  <li>Process Inbox: Browser</li>
  <li>Process Inbox: DropBox</li>
  <li>Process Inbox: OmniFocus</li>
  <li>Review @Waiting For</li>
  <li>Review Forecast</li>
  <li>Review Calendar</li>
  <li>Review Weekly Plan</li>
  <li>Review Completed</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="weekly-review-70-mins">Weekly Review (~70 mins)</h2>

<p>The core purpose of my Weekly Review is to be honest with myself and verify that I’m headed in the right direction. I’m terrible at getting a feel for this and can easily get off track in the course of an afternoon. My tendency is to put off projects that are no fun or that have a daunting next action. I need to limit the projects and tasks available to pick from. I also need to review projects that aren’t moving and ask myself why they are stalled.</p>

<p>I should note that the tasks on this checklist look deceptively simple, but they’re far from it. <em>Clear Review Perspective</em> is a 30 minute or longer task that forces me to decide if I’m going to keep the project in the active queue, put it on hold, or drop it entirely. <em>Review Stalled Projects</em> makes me look at projects I keep thinking I’ll work on but continue failing to follow through on. These two steps alone can sometimes take an hour. But if I skipped that hour of commitment reevaluation, I’ll spend weeks working on fluff that takes me nowhere.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Process Inbox: @Joe in Kitchen</li>
  <li>Clear Review Perspective</li>
  <li>Review Stalled Projects</li>
  <li>Set Weekly Plan</li>
  <li>Weekly Reflection</li>
  <li>Clean Workstation</li>
  <li>Empty Trash</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="monthly-review-30-mins">Monthly Review (~30 mins)</h2>

<p>It’s impossible to validate my direction in the Weekly Review if I don’t have goals and a mission by which these projects are guided. The simple purpose of my Monthly Review is to create guidance and help me design my days to realize these goals. I look over my Horizons of Focus and make sure I have a sense of direction for the upcoming months and years. Granted, I’m always revising this. But it’s this process of reading and altering the plan that allows me to course correct quickly.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Review 50,000</li>
  <li>Review 40,000</li>
  <li>Review 30,000</li>
  <li>Check Old Projects</li>
  <li>Evaluate Morning Ritual</li>
  <li>Evaluate Evening Ritual</li>
  <li>Evaluate Daily Schedule</li>
  <li>Evaluate Contexts</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="annual-review-3-hrs">Annual Review (~3 hrs)</h2>

<p>I’ve found some value in rethinking the basic aspects of how we as a family operate once a year. Those can include insurance and savings, but they should also encompass your goals as a family or couple. And they do not need to be done all at once or alone. Involve your spouse and kids if you have them. But remember that your tolerance for this type of thinking than may be much higher (or lower) than your spouse’s. Break it up across a few weeks if you need.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Becky: Big accomplishments in the past year?</li>
  <li>Becky: Big goals for the next year?</li>
  <li>Becky: Evaluate financial state</li>
  <li>Becky: Evaluate insurance state</li>
  <li>Determine monthly goals for next year</li>
</ul>

<p>Again, this amount of review may be overkill for you. As long as your system helps you drive down the right road, you’re golden. But there are always times when we need to reference the lines on the road to keep us from hitting the ditches, and some of us need more reference points than others to stay on the road.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[36: My Current GTD Structure]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/36/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/36/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It’s been a while since I’ve shared my entire GTD structure. And now that I’m rereading the book, I figured it would be a good idea to share what I’m currently doing before it changes.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/My-Current-GTD-Structure.jpg" /><p>It’s been a while since I’ve shared my entire GTD structure. And now that I’m rereading the book, I figured it would be a good idea to share what I’m currently doing before it changes.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity/dp/0143126563?tag=joebuhlig-20">Getting Things Done - 2015 edition</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/what-is-an-hpda-and-how-do-i-use-it/">What Is An hPDA and How Do I Use It?</a></p>

<p><a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts/">Drafts</a> (<a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/drafts-4-quickly-capture-notes/id905337691?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">iTunes</a>)</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z9UjeTMb3Yk">Inbox Zero Origin</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus">OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">Using Omnifocus for Someday/Maybe Lists</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-evernote/">An Alternative to Evernote</a></p>

<p><a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/implementation-details-for-omnifocus-2-14-automation/24179?u=joebuhlig">iOS Automation in OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-the-analog-to-grasp-the-digital/">Using the Analog to Grasp the Digital</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/writing-articles-by-hand/">Writing Articles By Hand</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/12/">12: The Higher Horizons</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Hazel Keeping OmniFocus Updated]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/hazel-keeping-omnifocus-updated/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[hazel]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/hazel-keeping-omnifocus-updated/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There are times when you need a feature in software that doesn’t currently exist. Sometimes that leads to exploring alternatives or even creating your own, which is how inventors and entrepreneurs get a lot of their ideas.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/hazel-keeping-omnifocus-updated.jpg" /><p>There are times when you need a feature in software that doesn’t currently exist. Sometimes that leads to exploring alternatives or even creating your own, which is how inventors and entrepreneurs get a lot of their ideas.
<!--more--></p>

<p>In our current app culture, there is a growing push for extensibility and the ability to interact with the core data of a service from other apps. This ability has become necessary in my core applications. I’ve reached a point where there are no apps out there that have <em>all</em> the features I’m looking for.</p>

<p>I don’t see this as a bad thing. It simply means my view of software and my willingness to augment the existing functionality reaches beyond the current options. This does not mean an app is the wrong choice. Basically, I’m asking for things that either don’t exist in any current app, such as <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/32/">shuffling tasks</a>, or it means that the developer has yet to implement them.</p>

<p>With something as personal as a task manager, we’re certain to find shortcomings in every option available. Some people decide to work within the system they’ve chosen while others search for and create structures to fill in the gaps with new, bolt-on features. Again, this doesn’t mean you’ve chosen the wrong tool. It means you understand yourself and the app well enough to develop a system that is specific to you.</p>

<p>I’ve done this feature augmentation with OmniFocus. The Omni Group is excellent at making their apps scriptable and they have zero intentions of changing that. This is only <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/why-i-use-omnifocus/">one of the reasons</a> I’ve made OmniFocus my life manager of choice. They understand the impossibility of creating a tool that fits everyone, so they make it possible for us to customize our experience.</p>

<p>The experience I’ve created on my Mac has a hands-off mentality. I’ve written a handful of AppleScripts to create features I rely on. I could run these daily or every time I want to my database to update, but here’s a better solution: <a href="https://www.noodlesoft.com/kb/">Hazel</a>.</p>

<p>Hazel has the ability to run a script when a certain criteria has been met. That criteria is extremely flexible and has allowed me to fine-tune this new functionality. The following is an overview of these augmented features that Hazel has allowed me to add to OmniFocus without any manual interventions.</p>

<h2 id="auto-parser">Auto-Parser</h2>

<p>There has been <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/implementation-details-for-omnifocus-2-14-automation/24179?u=joebuhlig">great progress</a> on this in recent weeks but I often have a desire to capture an idea and send it to a specific project and context from my phone. I could use the new URL scheme but it’s not as quick and smooth as using the <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Auto-Parser">Auto-Parser</a>. I’ve written about this <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-auto-parser/">in the past</a>, but the short of it is that it allows me to email a task into OmniFocus and let my Mac put it into the correct home within my database. I let Hazel run this script in the background every time OmniFocus syncs.</p>

<h2 id="scheduled-reviews">Scheduled Reviews</h2>

<p>Some people love the ability to do daily “mini-reviews” in order to keep their projects updated. I prefer to do them all at once and on scheduled days. Since OmniFocus doesn’t currently support this, I wrote <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Update%20Reviews">this script</a> which resets the “Next Review Date” to my scheduled date depending on the review cycle I have set for that project. I used to run this manually whenever I saw the perspective highlight but now I let Hazel run it (without the confirmation) on a daily basis.</p>

<h2 id="weather-activation">Weather Activation</h2>

<p>Sometimes I add features that I feel should be a part of the core software, like scheduled reviews. This is far from that. I wanted to turn projects on or off depending on weather conditions, namely temperature. <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Weather%20Activation">This script</a> does exactly that. Again, I let Hazel run it daily and it searches for projects with notes that meet a certain criteria. Based on the results, it decides if the project should be made active or not. This is really handy for spring and fall maintenance projects.</p>

<h2 id="text-file-report">Text File Report</h2>

<p>I generate a daily report that shows all the tasks I’ve completed that day. It gives me a historical record that I can use for clients, but mostly I just like to be able to look back on a certain day and see what I did. It’s not necessary but I like the satisfaction in seeing it. <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Daily%20Task%20Report">This script</a> takes the tasks completed yesterday and puts them into a text file. Hazel runs it daily to give me a single file for each day.</p>

<p>Although I would love to see these features built-in, I understand they are too specific to my preferences and a broader implementation would add too much to an already intimidating and powerful tool.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Writing Articles By Hand]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/writing-articles-by-hand/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/writing-articles-by-hand/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[After reflecting on the process of writing a daily schedule by hand and discussing the benefits of the analog over the digital, I’ve decided to try writing articles with pen and paper.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/writing-articles-by-hand.jpeg" /><p>After reflecting on the process of <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/22/">writing a daily schedule by hand</a> and discussing <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/33/">the benefits of the analog over the digital</a>, I’ve decided to try writing articles with pen and paper.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I’ve accrued a variety of theories for why I should to this, but ultimately, I’m curious to know if there are any benefits of analog writing tools for someone who writes for the web. Even contemplating this makes me think it’s a crazy idea. Why use pen and paper when typing is so much faster? And wasn’t typing speed part of the rationale behind my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak transition</a>? On both counts, yes.</p>

<p>And to be honest, I hope to return to typing them. But my curiosity won’t leave me alone. I cannot help but wonder if the physical process of putting ink on a page has benefits I’m unaware of. I can speculate what those may be, but until I give it a real and genuine attempt, I’ll never be able to let the idea go.</p>

<p>It is all the unknowns surrounding the process that has me writing this away from all screens with fountain pen in hand. Will the slower pace lead me to clearer thoughts and better phrasing of my ideas? Is there a deeper satisfaction in the writing process? Does a pen help me focus more than a keyboard? My presumed answer to all of these questions is yes. If the quality of my articles goes up as a result and the extra time is available, then it is certainly worth the extra effort. And if that’s the case, why can’t this mode of thinking and way of writing be duplicated through a keyboard?</p>

<p>My normal writing environment is in <em>Distraction Free Mode</em> inside Sublime Text. It’s nothing more than full screen mode with all display panels hidden. The theory should hold that I’m writing in the same environment as analog: with no outside distraction or tendencies to deviate from the task at hand. But one major difference remains with the availability of distractions. There are easily more opportunities to jump in and out of alternatives on the Mac. So in theory, the analog process should yield greater focus.</p>

<p>My hope is that the slower pace allows me to process and develop my thoughts more completely. Too often I reread an article I released a few days prior and see a gaping hole in my rationale. Or I’ll see a point that I touched on but could have spelled out in more detail. My brevity isn’t wrong, per se, but I would prefer to put it all out there in most cases. My shortness is due to a lack of decision more than a set intention. I don’t want to hold back without realizing I’ve done so. I know the slower pace of hand writing my articles will have an impact, but is it a noticeable and valuable difference?</p>

<p>I am also tempted to think that the overall process of writing an article will be faster. As much as I like to think that typing can be done distraction-free and focused, I have to confess to “checking in” when I have a pause in words. By stepping away from the screen entirely, those “just checks” and the time they take should disappear and allow me to develop a better phrase instead of defaulting to my original and often predictable way of stating the idea.</p>

<p>I’ve committed to writing five articles by hand - this being the first - so I have four to go. It doesn’t sound like a lot but I’m fairly certain it won’t take long to draw a conclusion. I will give it my best try and explore the results because, as usual, my curiosity has gotten the better of me.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[35: Why I'm Into Productivity]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/35/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/35/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve been actively exploring why I am big into productivity for the past two months. In part, that led me to seeing a counselor and discovering a missing piece to my mental puzzle, even though it’s likely obvious to most.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Why-I'm-Into-Productivity.jpg" /><p>I’ve been actively exploring why I am big into productivity for the past two months. In part, that led me to seeing a counselor and discovering a missing piece to my mental puzzle, even though it’s likely obvious to most.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://store.asianefficiency.com/dojo/">Asian Efficiency Dojo</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-omnifocus-dashboard/">The OmniFocus Dashboard</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Creating a Personal Book Index]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/creating-a-personal-book-index/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/creating-a-personal-book-index/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I used to just pick up a book, start at the beginning, and read it to the end. I tried not to bend any pages and always used a bookmark to make sure the book still looked brand new when I was finished. I had an unwarranted fear of ruining...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Creating-a-Personal-Book-Index.jpeg" /><p>I used to just pick up a book, start at the beginning, and read it to the end. I tried not to bend any pages and always used a bookmark to make sure the book still looked brand new when I was finished. I had an unwarranted fear of ruining my books because I held them in such high regard.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I think that does the author an injustice. Yes, we’re reading the book. But are we doing anything with what we’re reading? Are we thoroughly comprehending it and engaging with the content? For me, the answer to those was “No”. Sure, I would learn a few things, but most of the time I found myself skimming the whole thing trying to find a section with the solution I was looking for or an <em>aha moment</em> to teach me something new.</p>

<p>After reading this way for a long time I eventually started underlining or highlighting passages I found interesting or inspiring. That was a big step for me. But those words, despite having an impact on me, would eventually be lost. I might remember reading something in a specific book and then go back and look for it but this rarely happened.</p>

<p>While reading <a href="http://now.joebuhlig.com/reading">my latest books</a> I started creating my own index of these highlights at the prompting of <a href="http://fourhourworkweek.com/2014/10/21/brain-pickings/">Tim Ferris and Maria Popova</a>. I wasn’t sure if it would be worth it or not, but I can now say that being able to glance at the back of a book to see the location of these important passages makes it a much better experience and well worth the extra seconds it takes to create it.</p>

<p>What I’m doing is simple. When I underline or highlight some text, I go to the back of the book where there are always a couple blank pages, create a topic heading or find one that already exists, and I add the page number of the text I just underlined. Done.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/creating-a-personal-book-index/book-index.jpg" /></p>

<p>When I’m finished reading the book, I do my best to write a quick overview for myself in a text file. As part of that process, I transcribe this book index into a digital format at the bottom of the review. This makes it possible to search for topics and see the books I’ve read that pertained to that topic. It also allows me to see what pages in the book pertain to that topic.</p>

<p>The searching piece is just icing on the cake, though. To me the real joy is having that personalized index at the back of the book to thumb through. I know that if there’s something that struck me in the book, I can always get back to it quickly and easily.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Is Dvorak Worth It?]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/is-dvorak-worth-it/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/is-dvorak-worth-it/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[After almost three months of typing with a Dvorak keyboard, I’ve reached some conclusions about this QWERTY alternative. Like most comparisons of this nature there are some significant pros and cons between the two. But I don’t think it’s fair to draw any conclusions until you’ve experienced both sides.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Is-Dvorak-Worth-It.jpg" /><p>After almost three months of typing with a <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak keyboard</a>, I’ve reached some conclusions about this QWERTY alternative. Like most comparisons of this nature there are some significant pros and cons between the two. But I don’t think it’s fair to draw any conclusions until you’ve experienced both sides.
<!--more--></p>

<p>My conclusion: <strong>I’m sticking with Dvorak</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="speed">Speed</h2>

<p>One of the main reasons given for using Dvorak is typing speed. Because the layout is designed to limit finger travel, the theory is that you can hit the keys much more quickly and create words faster. There are a lot of studies refuting this rationale and I don’t know what the real answer is when you look at the best of the best in each group. But I do know my own results are quite conclusive. When I started this journey I was typing 72 WPM on QWERTY. Today I’m averaging 84 WPM on Dvorak. Again, this is after only three months. And since the majority of my work is done by typing, this leads to potential gains for me even if they are small.</p>

<h2 id="keyboards">Keyboards</h2>

<p>One drawback of going with Dvorak is access to the physical keyboards needed to make it work. Yes, you can learn it and use a QWERTY keyboard to type Dvorak. But I find that having <a href="http://www.amazon.com/KB-Covers-DV-M-CB-2-Dvorak-keyboard/dp/B00NCD1UZ6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1461856193&amp;sr=8-1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=joebuhlig-20&amp;linkId=ada498e9c149e95d19118e594db94578">a cover</a> on top makes it a lot easier. There are a times when most typists glance even slightly at the keys for reference. Having the actual key displayed can have a big impact. I use a cover that fits both my MacBook Pro and the Apple Wireless Keyboard since those are the two I use. That is an added expense to consider here.</p>

<h2 id="multiple-users">Multiple Users</h2>

<p>My wife uses my primary machine from time to time and that means she needs QWERTY to remain available. What I’ve found is that it’s really a non-issue. You can set the layout on each profile and once logged in it will always goes back to that layout. Even when switching users on the lock screen it changes the layout. I sometimes need to use QWERTY from the lock screen but that’s the only time it’s an issue. My wife never has to deal with it.</p>

<h2 id="rsi">RSI</h2>

<p>I wouldn’t say that I have RSI but I do know when I’ve had a heavy typing day. For me that usually means typing 4,000 words in a day or more. I’ve had a few days when I hit 7,000 and my hands really need a break afterwards. I don’t have any data behind it but I know that since the switch I’ve had a couple 5,000+ days and I didn’t realize it until I saw the numbers later. I normally would have felt it at that level. To me, that’s a good indicator of positive long-term results.</p>

<h2 id="ios">iOS</h2>

<p>On iOS I find my biggest complaint. There is no built-in Dvorak keyboard so I end up using a third-party keyboard. But there are still times when those keyboards aren’t allowed or won’t show up reliably. Searching in Spotlight or typing in passwords are the biggest culprits I’ve found. So there are still times when I’m using QWERTY on iOS but I don’t always know when I’ll be required to do so. I would love for Apple to add this to their built-in options.</p>

<h2 id="retaining-qwerty">Retaining QWERTY</h2>

<p>There are still times when I’ve found myself using another computer or device. The tech and sound booth at our church is the most common one. But I also use my wife’s profile once in a while. So I still find myself typing on a QWERTY keyboard from time to time. I did a quick test out of curiosity and found that I’m still at 45 WPM on QWERTY. It’s nowhere near my original speed but that’s to be expected. I’m alright with where I am, but I’m not actively trying to keep it around.</p>

<p>In the end, I’m quite happy with the transition and benefits I’m seeing with Dvorak. And since I’ve only been at it a short time, I can only hope that the positives continue to surface, my speed continues increasing, and the strain on my hands remains limited.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[34: A Web Developer Using Markdown]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/34/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/34/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Markdown has become a major part of how I do all of my writing despite being a web developer. It has a lot of benefits even if you know how to write the HTML itself.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/A-Web-Developer-Using-Markdown.jpg" /><p>Markdown has become a major part of how I do all of my writing despite being a web developer. It has a lot of benefits even if you know how to write the HTML itself.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://daringfireball.net/">Daring Fireball</a></p>

<p><a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/basics">Daring Fireball: Markdown Basics</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig/status/718819253277753344">Twitter conversation about markdown on paper</a></p>

<p><a href="http://kramdown.gettalong.org/">kramdown</a></p>

<p><a href="http://fletcher.github.io/MultiMarkdown-4/tables.html">Markdown Tables</a></p>

<p><a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll • Simple, blog-aware, static sites</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/discourse-feature-voting">joebuhlig/discourse-feature-voting</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text: The text editor you’ll fall in love with</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/revolunet/sublimetext-markdown-preview">revolunet/sublimetext-markdown-preview: markdown preview and build plugin</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.support.wordpress.com/markdown/">Markdown Support — WordPress</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak Transition</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/9/">9: Really? Journaling?</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working with OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/newsletter">Email Newsletter</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using the Analog to Grasp the Digital]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-the-analog-to-grasp-the-digital/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[analog]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[digital]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-the-analog-to-grasp-the-digital/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m guilty of looking for ways to accomplish tasks on the computer long before it crosses my mind to try paper or the whiteboard. It’s almost embarrassing sometimes. The idea of going to a notepad as a first instinct is hard for me to grasp.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-the-Analog-to-Grasp-the-Digital.jpeg" /><p>I’m guilty of looking for ways to accomplish tasks on the computer long before it crosses my mind to try paper or the whiteboard. It’s almost embarrassing sometimes. The idea of going to a notepad as a first instinct is hard for me to grasp.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I’m slowly growing fond of pen and paper. I’ve written meeting notes on paper for a long time but it’s only been the last few months that I’ve really embraced the value of writing daily schedules and brainstorming sessions on a notepad. And for someone so devoted to digital tools I must confess that the results have baffled me.</p>

<p>Mike Schmitz and I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/33/">talked about this</a> on the podcast recently. Because physically writing something down engages more of your body and requires you to use more of your self to get the idea out of your mind, you have more memory indicators created in your brain. In turn, it leaves you with more connections made and more ability to recall the thing you wrote down. In other words, writing it on paper helps you remember more than typing it into a computer.</p>

<p>When I started writing out a daily plan on paper I found that I didn’t need to reference the paper nearly as often as I used to reference my digital calendar. I was able to move from one task to the next with little or no transition cost. I knew what the next step of my day was without needing to look at the paper.</p>

<p>After doing this for the better side of a month I went back to using my digital calendar with no loss of results over the paper version. The experience of writing it down with pen and paper solidified the rationale and nuances of the process. It showed me the importance of deciding where the minutes of my day will go and the repetitiveness of my real schedule began to come through. It was only after I developed the memory through handwriting the daily schedule that I was able to best utilize the digital calendar and understand the cycles I naturally fall into.</p>

<p>And that proved to have great value. Developing an awareness of how you work is the best way to create truly productive systems. But it turns out that once I went back to the digital calendar, the side effects of relying on calendar alerts and the use of repeating events aren’t worth the move back to digital. I can now understand how to set up my digital calendar in more detail. But doing so and using it leaves me with symptoms I’d rather not have. So I’m back on the paper for my daily schedule.</p>

<p>The time it takes to write it out by hand and think it through in detail every day develops a memory that I can use throughout the day and relieves me of the robotic nature of recurring events that aren’t regularly kept in check.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The OmniFocus Dashboard]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-omnifocus-dashboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-omnifocus-dashboard/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I write and talk about my OmniFocus Dashboard a lot. And that’s for good reason: it’s the central hub of my day-to-day work and the place where my decisions about the day surface.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-OmniFocus-Dashboard.png" /><p>I write and talk about my OmniFocus Dashboard a lot. And that’s for good reason: it’s the central hub of my day-to-day work and the place where my decisions about the day surface.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The intent behind the Dashboard is to show me a list of tasks to be completed today. I want those tasks to be shown in order, meaning I start at the top and work to the bottom. There’s no need to choose the next task because I’ve already decided ahead of time.</p>

<p>Before I get too far into this, let’s go through the setup. All the Dashboard contains are tasks that are <em>Due or Flagged</em>. The task needs to have a due date within the next five days or I must manually flag it before it shows up here. As for the display settings, I want it to group tasks by context but sort by project.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-mini" src="/assets/posts_extra/the-omnifocus-dashboard/settings.png" /></p>

<p><img class="right-image post-image-tiny" style="max-width: 100px;" src="/assets/posts_extra/the-omnifocus-dashboard/contexts.png" /></p>

<p>I keep my contexts in order of importance from top to bottom. And I give my @Admin tasks the highest priority. If the task impacts the state of my system and accuracy of the projects in it, I want that task to be completed first. I want to trust that I have all the appropriate information collected and in place before I move on. With the perspective grouped by context, it first sorts the tasks by context; and with the @Admin context at the top of my list, it shows up first on the Dashboard.</p>

<p><img class="left-image post-image-tiny" style="max-width: 125px;" src="/assets/posts_extra/the-omnifocus-dashboard/projects.png" /></p>

<p>I also sort my projects in order of importance. See a theme here? At the top of my project list is a folder called <em>Guidance</em>. It holds my higher horizons, reviews, and meta projects. Again, I want these at the top of the list because these projects keep my daily activities in alignment with my long-term goals. With the Dashboard sorted by project, the tasks within the context groupings maintain the priority I give my projects. I should also note that all projects in this Guidance folder are flagged and their tasks are given the @Admin context. The flag is what pulls them into the Dashboard and the context ensures they will always be at the top.</p>

<h2 id="reviews">Reviews</h2>

<p>The projects at the very top are my reviews: daily, weekly, monthly, and annual in that order. I need to complete my daily review before I go on to the weekly review. The same goes for the monthly and annual reviews. I can’t make decisions about which projects to take on or drop if there are still unprocessed tasks in my inbox. The system must be up-to-date beforehand. Again, these projects are flagged and all their tasks are given the @Admin context, so these tasks show up in the first grouping of the Dashboard.</p>

<h2 id="meta">Meta</h2>

<p>Underneath my reviews are a couple meta projects I’ve put in place to help me accomplish my weekly commitments and the projects that are important to me. The first is called <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-important-not-urgent-projects/"><em>Important Projects</em></a> and it’s set to repeat daily.  It’s a simple list that helps me put valued projects first and it’s the first thing I do once my reviews are completed. These aren’t tasks themselves but they prompt me to go elsewhere in OmniFocus to complete a task that pertains to the original item.</p>

<p>The second meta project is called <em>Weekly Creation</em> and it repeats weekly. I do my best to write two articles for this site and record one podcast episode each week. This project holds a few tasks that come after the <em>Important Projects</em> tasks. I need to have this week’s content created before I move on to other work for the week. Again, these two projects are flagged to add them to the Dashboard.</p>

<h2 id="due-or-flagged">Due or Flagged</h2>

<p>Once all reviews and important tasks are completed, I move on to the tasks that will be due soon or that I’ve decided to work that today. The due soon tasks show up automatically based on how close I am to the due date. For me, that means five days out from the assigned date. I want a little lead time on these. But I fill the remainder of my day’s work with tasks that I’ve flagged. Sometimes these apply to the projects on my <em>Important Projects</em> list, but often times they are simple one-off tasks that are bugging me and I want done.</p>

<h2 id="reality">Reality</h2>

<p>The nice thing about this Dashboard is that it is mostly robotic. It happens on its own. Each day these tasks show up without me needing to do anything. But there’s risk involved with that. You can become numb to seeing them every day; if you skip one day, it becomes easy to skip them the next; or you start looking through the list, get overwhelmed by it, and do nothing. For me, the problem can arise when I start re-thinking my previous decisions that led to the list in the first place. I’m not always the best at sticking to it, but I know if I trust my previous self that I have a greater tendency to create flow and accomplish more by the end of the day.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[33: Analog vs. Digital with Mike Schmitz]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/33/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[analog]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[digital]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/33/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Mike Schmitz joins me this week to talk through the use of analog tools and how that can help us understand when and where to use the appropriate digital tool.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Analog-vs-Digital-with-Mike-Schmitz.jpg" /><p>Mike Schmitz joins me this week to talk through the use of analog tools and how that can help us understand when and where to use the appropriate digital tool.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/author/mikeschmitz/">Mike Schmitz - Asian Efficiency</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/podcast/">The Productivity Show</a></p>

<p><a href="http://thesweetsetup.com/">The Sweet Setup</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mikeschmitz.me/">mikeschmitz.me</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Thou-Shalt-Hustle-Pushing-Average-ebook/dp/B00SZDI876?tag=joebuhlig-20">Thou Shalt Hustle</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-important-not-urgent-projects/">The Important (Not Urgent) Projects</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/podcast/057-joe-buhlig/">TPS57: Advanced OmniFocus Setup + Workflow w/ Joe Buhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/podcast/011-buhlig/">TPS11: Joe Buhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://learnomnifocus.com/tutorials/2016-01-28-omnifocus-workflows-with-shawn-blanc/">OmniFocus Workflows: Shawn Blanc - Learn OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://discussion.joebuhlig.com/t/22-addiction-to-numbers/177/2?u=joebuhlig">Discussion about daily planning</a></p>

<p><a href="http://patrickrhone.com/dashplus/">The Dash/Plus System</a></p>

<p><a href="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/04/22/0956797614524581.abstract">The Pen Is Mightier Than the Keyboard</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Moleskine-Evernote-Notebook-Pocket-Notebooks/dp/886613760X?tag=joebuhlig-20">Moleskine Evernote Smart Notebook</a></p>

<p><a href="http://rohdesign.com/sketchnotes/">Sketchnotes</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/013383171X/therohdesignwebs?tag=joebuhlig-20">The Sketchnote Workbook</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Steal-Like-Artist-Things-Creative/dp/0761169253?tag=joebuhlig-20">Steal Like an Artist - Austin Kleon</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Show-Your-Work-Creativity-Discovered/dp/076117897X?tag=joebuhlig-20">Show Your Work! - Austin Kleon</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=llw4ACIKt00">Choosing Tools for GTD® - YouTube</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/systems/think-like-a-geek/">How to Think Like a Geek</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.relay.fm/cortex/26">Cortex #26: Pick your Poison</a></p>

<p><a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/automation-in-omnifocus-2-14-now-in-testflight/23985">Automation in OmniFocus 2.14 (now in TestFlight)</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bobbleheadjoe">@bobbleheadjoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[The Flawed Foundation of Diets]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/the-flawed-foundation-of-diets/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[food]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/the-flawed-foundation-of-diets/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[After working on multiple sides of agriculture and seeing how the back-end of the food industry operates, I’ve come to the realization that there is some really bad information out there about agriculture and how we decide what to eat.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/the-flawed-foundation-of-diets.jpg" /><p>After working on multiple sides of agriculture and seeing how the back-end of the food industry operates, I’ve come to the realization that there is some really bad information out there about agriculture and how we decide what to eat.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Most of our decisions about what to eat are adopted from a huge list of diets. There are a lot of cultural diets, but anymore most Western diets are put together with a purpose in mind. Some of them help us put on muscle and some help lower cholesterol levels. There’s even a <a href="http://www.tofugu.com/japan/japan-long-breath-diet/">breathing diet</a> to help you lose weight. No matter the goal, diets face an underlying flaw in their design.</p>

<p>When you break it down, a diet is simply a recommendation on how to achieve health through the food that you consume. It’s a way of eating that provides you with a long, energetic life. But the problem we face today is the plethora of diets out there all claiming to be the best way to eat. A lot of these diets contradict each other and leave us wondering which ones are worthwhile. What’s worse is the regular discovery of new scientific evidence revealing the fact that some diets actually make us <em>less</em> healthy than we were originally.</p>

<p>Why is that? Let’s go back to the premise of what a diet is: a recommendation on how to eat. In order to make an honest and accurate recommendation we need information and experience with the thing we are recommending. Generally speaking, you wouldn’t ask a web developer to work on your car. Most developers don’t have the deep knowledge about cars that they would need to find the issue with your motor. The food industry is much the same.</p>

<p>The vast majority of diets are based on research done by scientists. We run across diets created by individuals once in a while but those typically have a base derived from the research done by scientists. We learn that antioxidants can help fight or prevent cancer, so we put together a recommendation on how to get more of them into our daily food intake. We even go to the extreme of adding them into products where they don’t naturally exist so that we can consume even more of them. But that mindset can give us <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/antioxidants-may-make-cancer-worse/">alarming results</a>.</p>

<p>Any time we develop new research that shows a way to prevent or fight a disease or that shows the health benefits of a specific nutrient, we blow it out of proportion. You would think that with all the research being done and the experience we have with eating that we would know how to eat healthfully. Why can’t we get this right?</p>

<p>In order to make a perfect recommendation, you have to know <em>everything</em> about the thing you’re recommending. If you don’t know everything about it, there will inevitably be flaws in the rationale behind the recommendation. Sometimes those flaws are no big deal but sometimes they have unexpected results.</p>

<p>Say I recommend a wireless router to a friend. It’s one I’ve used for years and have a great experience with. My friend trusts me so he buys the router. He sets it up and has nothing but issues with it. I come over and give it a try with no luck. After digging into it, I find out that this router doesn’t play nice with his specific modem. I made what I thought was a great recommendation but it turned out to be a nightmare for my friend. If had known about the pairing issues of that combination, I wouldn’t have recommended it. I didn’t know <em>everything</em> about the router even though I thought it was excellent.</p>

<p>We have a lot of data about the human body. We understand things about it that our great-grandparents could only speculate about. And that means we have a ton of information at our disposal that we can use to build the perfect recommendation on how to eat. But remember what I said earlier:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In order to make a perfect recommendation, you have to know <em>everything</em> about the thing you’re recommending.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In order to make the perfect diet, we have to know <em>everything</em> about the human body. We have to know about every nutrient that exists, how they work in combinations, and what our digestive system does with each one. We also have to understand how we break those nutrients down and how they help brain function. We need to know how our nutritional needs change as we age and develop. But it turns out there’s a lot we don’t know about ourselves:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/what-we-know-about-the-brain-2015-5">What we know about the brain</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.newscientist.com/round-up/ten-mysteries-of-you">Ten things we don’t understand about humans</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/65435/scientists-discover-new-part-human-body">Scientists Discover a New Part of the Human Body</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/body%E2%80%99s-bacteria-don%E2%80%99t-outnumber-human-cells-so-much-after-all">Body’s bacteria don’t outnumber human cells so much after all</a></p>

<p>The other side of this is that we don’t even understand the food itself well enough to know how it fits into our own nutrition. Take the tomato for example. It’s consumed all over the world and yet we know very little about <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/05/31/science/the-tomato-ripe-juicy-and-bursting-with-genes.html">why it has more genes</a> than we do. If we can’t explain everything about our own bodies and the food that we eat, how can we expect anyone to develop a diet that completely meets our nutritional needs?</p>

<p>It simply isn’t possible to develop a diet that is completely accurate and 100% reliable. We don’t know enough to do that. Yes, we can put together good guesses and see great results, but we often don’t see the long-term effects for many years and by that time we may have learned that it was actually a really bad idea all along.</p>

<p>Scientists are doing an excellent job of learning about us and the food we eat. We’ve been able to create diets for people struggling with diseases and help patients extend their lives and have a higher quality of life at the same time. There’s a lot of value in these continued attempts to make the best recommendations we can. And the more we learn about ourselves, the better these recommendations get. But we will very likely never have the ability to build the perfect diet and we will never be able to manufacture the perfect food.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, we simply need to keep in mind that the diets we choose to follow are never ideal. Scientists are great at giving us information to follow, but we need to remember the basics when we decide what to eat.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>