<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 09:28:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Introducing The New Working With OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Working With OmniFocus has been recreated in video format!  It’s now available on the new dedicated website: workingwithomnifocus.com.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/introducing-the-new-working-with-omnifocus.jpg" /><p>Working With OmniFocus has been recreated in video format!  It’s now available on the new dedicated website: <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">workingwithomnifocus.com</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Something I didn’t plan on with this project was the expansion of content. By the time I finished the set of videos, I realized there are over four hours of content and an additional 40% in topics covered over the book. And I already have another hour worth of topics in the queue. So it’s easy to say that this is a pretty extensive resource and I’m really excited to share it with you!</p>

<p>Quick note: if you’ve previously purchased the book, check your email. There’s a present waiting for you there. If you haven’t bought the book, you can still get it as part of the video series. I’m keeping it simple and throwing it all into one package.</p>

<p>Go check out <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">the new website</a>! There are a handful of freebies there even if you’re not planning to buy.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[8: The Power of Full Engagement by Jim Loehr, Tony Schwartz [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/8-the-power-of-full-engagement-by-jim-loehr-tony-schwartz/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/8-the-power-of-full-engagement-by-jim-loehr-tony-schwartz/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When you step out beyond time management you land in the world of energy management. It’s a simple concept that is drastically different for everyone embarking on the journey.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>When you step out beyond time management you land in the world of energy management. It’s a simple concept that is drastically different for everyone embarking on the journey.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[7: Deep Work by Cal Newport [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/7-deep-work-by-cal-newport/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/7-deep-work-by-cal-newport/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Mike has a new Apple device despite his minimizing efforts and Joe has finally done something about his email issue.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Mike has a new Apple device despite his minimizing efforts and Joe has finally done something about his email issue.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A Year Without Extra Screens]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-year-without-extra-screens/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-year-without-extra-screens/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[For the last year I’ve been running my business from a MacBook Pro  and an iPhone.  No iPad. No Watch. And no external monitors.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/a-year-without-extra-screens.jpeg" /><p>For the last year I’ve been running my business from a MacBook Pro  and an iPhone.  No iPad. No Watch. And no external monitors.
<!--more--></p>

<p>This started out of necessity. I had jumped into bootstrapping my business quicker than I wanted and knew I shouldn’t spend extra dollars on unnecessary gadgets. So I took on the bare essentials.</p>

<p>At first, this was painful. I had done development and data analysis work for quite a while and had been able to use iPads and at least three monitors for years. I could easily argue the validity of multiple monitors for someone doing my line of work. To go from three 27” Thunderbolts and an always-on iPad at my desk to nothing more than a MacBook Pro screen was not fun.</p>

<p>To be honest, the freelance development and online business world isn’t all roses and rainbows. I haven’t felt comfortable spending extra dollars on a nice-to-have that isn’t necessary for me to do my job. So I’ve spent the last year working with the same minimal setup I started with.</p>

<p>Despite the wounds this inflicted at the onset, I’ve discovered some unexpected benefits and learnings from this unwanted experiment. I can’t say everyone will experience these and frankly some will say these are illogical conclusions. Regardless, my feelings on the topic remain.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Multiple screens don’t increase productivity.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>When forced to work from a single, small screen, you find ways to make the process as easy as possible. Instead of designating apps to specific locations on a specific screen, I found a <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/mac-navigation/">way to quickly switch</a> to a screen filling view of an app. With a single keyboard shortcut, I jump from program to program. But that means my need to see multiple things at once is no longer necessary because I can switch about as fast as my eyes can move to another screen and back.</p>

<p>The other aspect at work here is pure willpower to focus. Multiple screens increase the speed at which I can be distracted. Even if the distraction is productive, it still takes me away from my intended task. A single screen forces me to look at the application and task in front of me. I have to make a conscious decision to navigate elsewhere.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Device overlap is detrimental to focus.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>When I owned an iPad, it served two purposes. It was used to read articles and watch videos and it became a dashboard for my task list, outline, or reference material. Without it, I read articles and watch videos on my phone or Mac. But honestly, I do this very little anymore. And from what I can tell, I’m better off scaling this back even further.</p>

<p>The lack of the dashboard has been a different story. It was a big loss initially since I’ve been using an iPad that way for three years or better. I struggled to find an alternative. As expected, I eventually found a combination of tools and techniques to simulate what I was doing previously. But what surprised me was the fact that my “new” methods were already in place. I had been switching between the iPad and my iPhone for a task list. My outlines and references were a shortcut away on the Mac. I had been duplicating the main purpose of the iPad on the Mac and iPhone already.</p>

<p>It’s tricky, but I found there was a split in focus when there were options about which device to use. Because I could choose between devices for a given task, I would have to make an extra decision (iPad or Mac?) about the right one in the moment. Remove the decision (the extra device) and I can get to work quicker and, in most cases, more effectively. Without the choice and the potential overlap in devices, I’m free to focus on the task itself instead of asking which device to use for the task.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Owning every Apple device isn’t logical.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ll say it. I’m an Apple fanboy. Every product with an Apple logo has me looking for an excuse to own it. But each time I consider one, I’ve had to ask myself, “What does this enable me to do that I can’t already do and need to do?”” It’s the last piece of that question that always throws me off. There’s a lot of new and shiny with Apple products, but at the end of the day, I’ve learned that it takes only a couple of them to do what I need and to do it well.</p>

<p>All that said, there are changes I would make and I <em>would</em> increase my screen count by one. But I would only do so in the realm of Macs. Given my work in audio/video lately, I would put in either an iMac or a Mac Pro with a single, large monitor. I’m unsure of the exact hardware needs at the moment. But to allow travel, I would pick up a new MacBook. I can do a light weight machine for this, since it only needs to do email and raw text when I’m away from my office. I wouldn’t buy an iPad and I wouldn’t go for more than a single monitor for the Mac.</p>

<p>When will this happen? I don’t know. But learning how to work with so little has taught me where I want to go.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Information Overwhelm Without The Internet]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I hear people refer to information overwhelm more often than I would expect. The context varies but the idea is the same: finding information on the internet is so easy that the person has a hard time deciphering what is right and what to question. Some even take it as...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/information-overwhelm-without-the-internet.jpeg" /><p>I hear people refer to information overwhelm more often than I would expect. The context varies but the idea is the same: finding information on the internet is so easy that the person has a hard time deciphering what is right and what to question. Some even take it as far as to suggest <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2008/07/is-google-making-us-stupid/306868/">Google is making us dumb</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The validity of that statement and my opinion of it aren’t important for the context of this article. What is important is the cause of the overwhelm: a broad range of topics at our fingertips. Type a word into any web search tool and you are hit with page after page of words to consume. It boggles your mind when you try to comprehend the complexity of the systems behind the interface that deliver those search results.</p>

<p>And regardless of your opinion on the effects this has on our brains, it’s safe to say that most of the results are surface level articles. In other words, the vast majority of the internet articles out there will focus on the introduction of a topic or dive deep into one small aspect of a broader discipline. When combined and reviewed collectively, it’s possible to ascertain expert levels of knowledge about a given search. But more often than not, it requires a great deal of time and experience in scouring the web to develop that level of expertise from search results.</p>

<p>In most cases, we aren’t going to take the time necessary to understand a topic fully. We would rather skim the headlines we find, get our answer, and move on. This is where the traditional sense of information overwhelm comes in. There are so many potential solutions to our query that we have difficulty discerning which trail to follow. It’s overwhelm due to a wide variety of topics made available to you.</p>

<p>But I’ve recently discovered a different type of overwhelm. Instead of this <em>broad topics overwhelm</em>, there’s also <em>deep topic overwhelm</em>. Both flavors come with two constraints: a lot of information going into your mind in a short time frame. With the broad form, we see a variety of subjects available to us through systems like Google. But the deep form flips the equation and gives us a ton of detail about a single realm of knowledge. In my case, this is revealed through the rapid consumption of business and productivity books.</p>

<p>You could make the argument that given wisdom in writing queries you could create a list of search results that would emulate deep topic overwhelm. But again, you will be presented with a series of webpages that would need to be reviewed collectively and digested over a longer period of time. At that point you no longer fall into the constraint of a short time period, whereas reading multiple longform works on a single subject in short succession does.</p>

<p>A prime example of this difference is the book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity/dp/0143126563/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Getting Things Done</a>. There are countless people, myself included, who discovered the GTD framework through searches and failed to implement it successfully until they broke down and actually read the book. Despite the thousands of articles out there about GTD and, in my case, months of reading them, you’ll never reach a level of full understanding until you read the book.</p>

<p>But if you read a lot of these types of books in a short time, you’ll quickly start to feel this deep topic overwhelm. There’s so much information and an incomprehensible level of rationale behind each author’s arguments that you can’t help but notice numerous aspects of your life and work that you want to change or develop. You have loads of data entering your mind that you want to act on and feel like you can’t keep up.</p>

<p>The logical response is to slow down. Give yourself time to process and adapt. In my case, that’s not possible since my quick reading is a part of <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a>. But I’m convinced I would continue my biweekly pace even without the podcast and accountability. There are two reasons for this:</p>

<p>One, <strong>I’m able to draw correlations and similarities I wouldn’t otherwise have seen</strong>. Given the short timeframe that I consume these books within, I have found that I still have a deep recollection of the last seven to ten that I’ve read. The book I am currently reading ends up being colored by what I’ve learned across thousands of pages I am still intimately familiar with. I find connections across multiple texts that I would normally miss.</p>

<p>Second, <strong>the new information I’m learning becomes motivation to keep moving forward with action items and deepens my rationale for what I’ve learned</strong>. Reading a thought-out reasoning for an author’s belief will encourage you to either develop your own perspective or challenge you to reconsider your existing view. In both cases, you come out better on the other side.</p>

<p>When you have the ability to be both broadly overwhelmed and deeply overwhelmed, through the internet or through books, you can choose between two responses: you can wait to learn until you need a piece of information, or you can take advantage of your good fortune and learn as much as possible right now. I’ll take the latter.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Woodworking Versus Websites]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/woodworking-versus-websites/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[woodworking]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/woodworking-versus-websites/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One of the most difficult aspects of building websites or doing knowledge work full-time is the lack of motivation and pride that typically comes from physically seeing the work of your hands. Yes, it is possible to achieve this sense of accomplishment when working purely with information and computers, but...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/woodworking-versus-websites.jpeg" /><p>One of the most difficult aspects of building websites or doing knowledge work full-time is the lack of motivation and pride that typically comes from physically seeing the work of your hands. Yes, it is possible to achieve this sense of accomplishment when working purely with information and computers, but it’s far from natural.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Looking at my own life, I compare it to woodworking. When I build a piece of furniture I rarely need a to-do list for it. And (given available time) I don’t struggle with getting to work on it like I do a bug-fix. I know that I can go to the woodshop, see my current progress, immediately determine what comes next, and get to work. And when I’m done, there is a innate joy that comes from having built the piece or at least made progress on it.</p>

<p>But when it comes to websites, it’s a different story. I need a list to know where I left off. And I have to develop tricks and rituals to motivate me to get to work. Even after I’m done with the build I need to reflect on my work and put it in perspective to understand its value and develop pride in my work.</p>

<p>The weird part of this is that I really enjoy both. But I do think there’s value in understanding the feelings and mechanics that come with working as a craftsman. If they can be applied to knowledge work, I think there is a drive and enjoyment we can achieve that has typically been reserved for those working with their hands.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Moving OmniFocus Scripts To iOS]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[applescripts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have been hesitant to adopt the new automation methods in OmniFocus for iOS. The abilities of the new URL Scheme are exciting but there’s still quite a bit missing from the structure as it stands.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/moving-omnifocus-scripts-to-ios.jpeg" /><p>I have been hesitant to adopt the <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/implementation-details-for-omnifocus-2-14-automation/24179?u=joebuhlig">new automation methods in OmniFocus</a> for iOS. The abilities of the new URL Scheme are exciting but there’s still quite a bit missing from the structure as it stands.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The main piece I found missing was the “autosave” parameter to the <code class="highlighter-rouge">/add</code> URL. My current structure uses the <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts/tree/master/Auto-Parser">Auto-Parser</a> which allows Drafts to send tasks to the app without the need to confirm or edit an item. Thankfully, the Omni Group introduced this feature recently and I can now add items directly to OmniFocus on iOS and come back to Drafts without any extra steps. Here’s the URL I’m using to add new Blog Post Ideas:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">omnifocus://x-callback-url/add?x-success=drafts4://&amp;name=[[title]]&amp;note=[[body]]&amp;project=Blog%20Post%20Ideas&amp;context=Running&amp;autosave=true</code></p>

<p>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">/paste</code> URL is a different story. Combined with Editorial or Workflow, this thing is awesome! It allows me to port two of the AppleScripts I use over to iOS.</p>

<p>The obvious one here is templates. <a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/t/automation-in-omnifocus-2-14-released-2016-04-26/23985?u=joebuhlig">Ken Case shared an Editorial workflow</a> that takes a template project in Taskpaper format and adds it to OmniFocus. I’m using his workflow unedited and found it really easy to recreate my templates on iOS. Navigate to the project you want to use as a template, tap the Share button, and copy it. In Editorial I simply pasted the project into a new Taskpaper file and I’m set. All I have to do is open the template and run the workflow.</p>

<p>The other script I moved over was the <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/reading-books-on-a-schedule/">“Read Book Tasks” script</a>. This was a complete rebuild of the code in Workflow. Using it on iOS is the same as running the script on a Mac. Run the workflow, answer the prompts, and you get a sub-project for the tasks added to your inbox.</p>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/cece509a6fd6477d8d9e479f3f5df184">OF Book Tasks - Workflow</a></p>

<p>Everything above is about creating new tasks. In the world of data, we often refer to CRUD - Create, Read, Update, Delete. It’s shorthand for the four ways you can work with information. You can make new data - Create. You can get existing data - Read. You can change or edit existing data - Update. And you can destroy the data - Delete. If you have the ability to do all four of these, you are able to do anything you want with the database.</p>

<p>If we overlay those four methods on top of the new OmniFocus URLs, we see only the first (Create) as a possibility. So we’re still limited in what we can do on iOS. It’s also why I’m not able to move <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts">all of my scripts</a> to iOS. It simply isn’t possible. Given the support for AppleScripting that the Omni Group shows, I can imagine it is only a matter of time before the RUD of CRUD makes it to iOS.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[6: The More Of Less by Joshua Becker [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/6-the-more-of-less-by-joshua-becker/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/6-the-more-of-less-by-joshua-becker/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[This week Mike and Joe talk about cutting back and simplifying life with Joshua Becker’s book The More Of Less.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>This week Mike and Joe talk about cutting back and simplifying life with Joshua Becker’s book <em>The More Of Less</em>.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Too Much Tech?]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/too-much-tech/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[devices]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/too-much-tech/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[One of the common threads in the books we’ve read for Bookworm is the impact of computers on our effectiveness, self-control, and overall happiness in life. Their prevalence and ubiquity in our world coupled with the newness and speed of their adoption has a lot of us wondering and speculating...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/too-much-tech.jpeg" /><p>One of the common threads in the books we’ve read for <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a> is the impact of computers on our effectiveness, self-control, and overall happiness in life. Their prevalence and ubiquity in our world coupled with the newness and speed of their adoption has a lot of us wondering and speculating about the positives and negatives of this shift. So I would expect any book written in the last decade to incorporate thoughts on the topic.
<!--more--></p>

<p>David Allen is a big proponent of using the latest technology in creating an external brain. The ability of these devices to manage information and deliver it at will is astounding and enables us to find whatever we want, whenever we want it. David’s GTD methodology (proposed in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity/dp/0143126563/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20"><em>Getting Things Done</em></a>) is perfectly aligned with and almost dependent on the mobility and universality of computers.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1583335080/?tag=joebuhlig-20"><em>The Willpower Instinct</em></a>, Kelly McGonigal explains the neurological processes and chemicals released when using many of today’s most popular applications and social networks. They are a double edged sword in that they connect us with people all over the world, but they also create never ending potential for distraction that we must overcome by developing a level of willpower. This is similar to Stephen Pressfield’s view of Resistance in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/War-Art-Through-Creative-Battles/dp/1936891026/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20"><em>The War Of Art</em></a>. It’s easy to let the notifications and possibility of something new keep us from creating our best work.</p>

<p>And if you start asking yourself questions about what is absolutely essential in your life as Greg McKeown suggests in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentialism-Disciplined-Pursuit-Greg-McKeown/dp/0804137382?tag=joebuhlig-20"><em>Essentialism</em></a>, you start to question the necessity of technology in general. Our access to information and interconnectedness are nothing short of remarkable. Throw in home automation and our capabilities are hard to fully comprehend. But to what gain? Are those things indispensable? Do they introduce an unnecessary level of complexity just because we can? Where is the line of too much?</p>

<p>I hate those questions. I have a tendency to adopt new technology because of the cool factor and for the sake of experimentation and knowledge. I want to know how something works and see how I can use it. The pros and cons battle hardly enters my mind. I don’t want to consider its benefits because I’m afraid there are none. And in most cases I know that it will be another thing to maintain and support when it doesn’t work correctly.</p>

<p>For the past year I’ve been without an iPad. For someone in my line of business, that is absurd. It wasn’t a goal or even intentional at first. I left the company I was working for at the time and needed to return the company iPad I had been using. Finances didn’t warrant the purchase of a replacement right away so I was forced to go without an iPad for the first time since they were introduced.</p>

<p>After 12 months without one, I’m seriously wondering if I would ever buy one as a replacement. I can’t find a legitimate purpose for it in my life that doesn’t increase the complexity of what I do and how I work. In other words, <em>I don’t miss it.</em></p>

<p>It’s this same rationale that I’ve applied to an Watch. What does it gain me that I can’t already accomplish? I already wear a watch and I always have my phone around. I simply cannot justify it.</p>

<p>However, there are a couple areas I would like to introduce a bit more tech. External monitors and an external hard drive for my MacBook would help me out considerably. But even then, I’m only augmenting an existing computer as opposed to introducing a new device entirely.</p>

<p>I don’t think there’s some magical line for technology to which we all need to adhere. The level of interconnectedness and digitization we each desire and can manage in our lives is different. But I think I have my line for now and I enjoy the freedom these limitations give me.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Embracing The New TextExpander]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/embracing-the-new-textexpander/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[textexpander]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/embracing-the-new-textexpander/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When Smile introduced the new “Snippet As A Service” version of TextExpander, there was quite an outcry. To be completely honest, I was confused by and resistant to the change at the onset. However, if I look at the new version without allowing my previous experience to color my opinion,...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/embracing-the-new-textexpander.jpg" /><p>When <a href="https://smilesoftware.com/">Smile</a> introduced the new “Snippet As A Service” version of TextExpander, there was quite an outcry. To be completely honest, I was confused by and resistant to the change at the onset. However, if I look at the new version without allowing my previous experience to color my opinion, it is striking how similar it is to my other choices for software.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="data">Data</h2>

<p>One of the big complaints is the location used for data storage and syncing. Previously, we used DropBox or some other syncing service to host and update our snippets as we alter them. The new version forces you to use <a href="//smile.7eer.net/c/298450/277331/2936">textexpander.com</a> as the backend. I understand the concern over data control here but it really doesn’t apply to me. I already use the backend for other software and services like OmniFocus, Workflow, and Overcast. This isn’t much different.</p>

<h2 id="pricing">Pricing</h2>

<p>This is the one that got me at first. Year-over-year, the price to me would increase almost twofold. At least, that’s what it was originally. Since release, Smile listened to the flood of feedback and generously implemented a 50% upgrade discount for life. In the end, that means I’m paying no more than I have in the past. It’s a wash.</p>

<h2 id="subscription">Subscription</h2>

<p>Anymore I’m slow to upgrade hardware. But software is a different story. I deliberately limit the number of tools I use, which means I pick quality, pro-user tools with a lot of features and flexibility. Any time these tools have an upgrade available, I like to jump on it quickly. If you look at it from a high-level, I am effectively paying a subscription plan already. By adopting this recurring payment structure, I get no-hassle updates without the worry.</p>

<h2 id="new-features">New Features</h2>

<p>My big question when I first saw the release of the new TextExpander was about features. What’s new that would lead me to upgrade? I didn’t have an answer. But then I tried the trial and found two features that are important to me and a third I’m considering.</p>

<p>The first is inline search. You type a keyword anywhere, hit a keyboard shortcut (that you can customize), and see search results of your matching snippets. Since we typically have these memorized it may not sound very useful until you consider the pain of changing your snippet abbreviations or a database with hundreds of snippets. I find the need to alter abbreviations every few months which means the inline search ability has received a lot of my attention.</p>

<p>Second, the <a href="//smile.7eer.net/c/298450/277331/2936">website</a>. It seems unnecessary at first. If you have the apps, why would you use the website? Then I ran into a couple instances where I wanted a block of text from TextExpander while on a different profile on my computer. I don’t want TextExpander on it for other reasons but it’s incredibly handy to log on to the website to access that data. It makes it possible to retrieve the info I want without a software installation.</p>

<p>And the feature I’m considering is the one that initiated this whole thing: teams and sharing. I can see a lot of value in sharing email templates with clients or for <a href="http://bookworm.fm">Bookworm</a>. Anytime there are communications, blocks of text, or forms that are used by multiple people, this could save us all a lot of time. I haven’t tried it yet, but I’m looking for the opportunity.</p>

<h2 id="personal-use-only">Personal Use Only?</h2>

<p>With all of this in mind, I’m happy with my choice to upgrade to the new TextExpander even if I choose not to use the sharing features. There’s enough added value in the new version and consistency in pricing (for me) to convince me to buy in. TextExpander is one of those core applications I incorporate into a lot of other tools. That means I want it up-to-date. And since there are new possibilities that come along for the ride, I’m exploring the options that the new functionality gives me.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[5: Essentialism by Greg McKeown [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/5-essentialism-by-greg-mckeown/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/5-essentialism-by-greg-mckeown/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Joe gets too much email, Mike thinks he should hide his email address, and they both have an interest in saying “no” more often.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Joe gets too much email, Mike thinks he should hide his email address, and they both have an interest in saying “no” more often.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Leaving Pocket For Instapaper]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[instapaper]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[pocket]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I follow specific websites less and less. I’m more inclined to follow people and services on Twitter and Medium that act as sources of curated articles. This gives me the ability to find sites I normally would have glossed over and still read my favorite writers.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper.jpeg" /><p>I follow specific websites less and less. I’m more inclined to follow people and services on Twitter and <a href="https://medium.com/@JoeBuhlig">Medium</a> that act as sources of curated articles. This gives me the ability to find sites I normally would have glossed over and still read my favorite writers.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But regardless of where I find these articles, I still need a way to save them for later. I rarely have time to read an article the moment I discover it. In the past I’ve used Pocket, but I have now moved to <a href="https://www.instapaper.com">Instapaper</a>.</p>

<p>Originally, I chose Pocket for its IFTTT integration. I had built a number of recipes that acted on the tagging ability of Pocket. But over time I slowly turned these off one by one, mostly due to my move away from tagging articles.</p>

<p>I still would’ve stayed with Pocket if they had simply left the URLs of the articles alone. When I’m finished with an article, I either archive it or share it. But if you share it through Pocket, they insist on shortening the URL with their custom link. The only way around it that I have found is to have <a href="https://workflow.is/">Workflow</a> expand the the link before sharing. When I see links shared by others, I use the top level domain (TLD) of the link as part of my decision about whether or not I want to read it. So I don’t want my own links preventing that ability.</p>

<p>Coupled with the link shortening is the difficulty in sharing quotes from Pocket. It is similarly complicated to do so without the Pocket custom link. Contrast this with Instapaper, where it works perfectly without the need for Workflow actions to expand the link and format the text. Instapaper uses the link you originally saved and gets out of the way.</p>

<p>The reading experience is also far better on Instapaper. They give a lot of options to customize the reading view. And since these are apps designed for reading, I feel this is paramount. The experience in Pocket is not bad, I simply prefer the environment created and allowed by Instapaper.</p>

<p>When I realized I was no longer using IFTTT with Pocket it gave me the freedom to explore other options. And because I have been watching Instapaper for a long time hoping their IFTTT integration would progress, it was the perfect time to switch. I no longer needed Instapaper to adopt a deeper relationship with IFTTT, so I could make the transition with zero compromises.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Updates For Working With OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/updates-for-working-with-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/updates-for-working-with-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It’s been about nine months since I released Working With OmniFocus. A lot has happened in that time and my systems around OmniFocus have morphed quite a bit. Throw in a pile of learning accrued from other projects and I have decided to make some significant changes to the book....]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/base/WorkingWithOmniFocus-Small.png" /><p>It’s been about nine months since I released <em>Working With OmniFocus</em>. A lot has happened in that time and my systems around OmniFocus have morphed quite a bit. Throw in a pile of learning accrued from other projects and I have decided to make some significant changes to the book.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="video">Video</h2>

<p>Easily the most prominent change will be the medium through which the content is delivered. Words on page work well, but when software is involved video can be a better route to follow. The ability to visually demonstrate a concept and how it works can dramatically increased the comprehension level of the viewer. So in the near future <em>Working With OmniFocus</em> will no longer be a book, but a repository of over 60 screencasts explaining and visualizing the idea at hand.</p>

<h2 id="location">Location</h2>

<p>I originally built a custom Ruby and Rails application to host the sales page and associated mechanisms for the book. That works well but gets to be a lot of maintenance that I’d rather not have. So <em>Working With OmniFocus</em> is moving to a new home on the web: <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">workingwithomnifocus.com</a>. Obviously, this is currently under development and will continue to change over the next few weeks.</p>

<h2 id="dynamic">Dynamic</h2>

<p>One of the major difficulties in writing a book about software is the static nature of a book compared to the continual development of the software. It makes it difficult to keep the book up to date. By moving to web-based video and breaking the content into smaller pieces, it allows me to tweak the content as the program changes.</p>

<h2 id="pricing">Pricing</h2>

<p>I hate pricing. Throw in discounts, launch promotions, and levels of access and it’s a nightmare to me. I have avoided much of this by sticking with a single price and I’m not leaving that mindset. In this case, the content will be more advanced and have more depth so I know the price will need to increase over the price of the book. I don’t currently have an answer on what it will cost, but I do know that those who have purchased the book (and those who <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">purchase it before the relaunch</a>) will receive $20 off the videos.</p>

<h2 id="affiliates">Affiliates</h2>

<p>The current affiliate program for the book has been a big success for me and I plan to continue to run one for the videos. But since I’m rebuilding the site, the mechanism will be different and will require you to sign up again for the new program. I know this is inconvenient but it will be better for all of us in the long run.</p>

<h2 id="book">Book?</h2>

<p>I’m not planning to update the book itself and the ability to purchase it by itself will go away. I will, however, make it available to those who purchase the video series with the caveat that my processes mentioned in the book are out of date.</p>

<h2 id="overall">Overall</h2>

<p>I’m really excited about these changes.  I will be able to explain the mindsets and demonstrate the app mechanisms in much more detail than was ever possible through the book. I’m devoting most of my current working time to these edits and plan to deliver it in mid to late August.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[4: The Obstacle Is The Way by Ryan Holiday [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/4-the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/4-the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We all deal with something painful in our lives. And although they are hard to talk about, it’s these obstacles that strengthen us for the future.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>We all deal with something painful in our lives. And although they are hard to talk about, it’s these obstacles that strengthen us for the future.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[TextExpander And OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/textexpander-and-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[textexpander]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/textexpander-and-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[TextExpander and OmniFocus are two of the first tools I install on any new device, so it’s no surprise that the two work well together. You may expect some kind of Applescripting or shell magic, but I keep this extremely simple and only use true text expansion with OmniFocus. I...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/textexpander-and-omnifocus.jpeg" /><p>TextExpander and OmniFocus are <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/first-apps-on-a-new-mac/">two of the first tools</a> I install on any new device, so it’s no surprise that the two work well together. You may expect some kind of Applescripting or shell magic, but I keep this extremely simple and only use true text expansion with OmniFocus. I run the scripts manually or behind the scenes with Hazel.
<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>xwait = “Waiting for “</strong></p>

<p>This is easily the most commonly used snippet I have for OmniFocus. Any time I need to create a new Waiting For task, I always type <em>xwait</em> and keep going. It’s not a huge savings in one instance but multiply this by the average 20 uses a day and it really adds up.</p>

<p><strong>xresp = “Waiting for response from “</strong></p>

<p>Similar to the first, I use this one a lot. I receive and send a ton of email. Any time I send one that warrants a response, a new task is created and this is where the naming starts.</p>

<p><strong>xplan = “Plan project for “</strong></p>

<p>Most of the time when I decide to take on a new project, I don’t have time right then to plan it out. So I use this to create a task for the planning process.</p>

<p><strong>xpfm = “Plan for meeting re: “</strong></p>

<p>I don’t use this as much as I used to, but this helps me create a new task as a reminder to review meeting materials and get resources together for a call.</p>

<p><strong>xlook = “Look into “</strong></p>

<p>I do a ton of research to help me get better at a project or learn how a new process works. I always start these tasks with “Look into” as an indicator to Google, read, or learn about the item.</p>

<p><strong>xdwc = “ (Delete when complete)”</strong></p>

<p>I stole this one from <a href="http://www.usingomnifocus.com">Kourosh</a>. I sometimes have repeating tasks that are creative in some form or don’t have a clear definition of “completed.” I augment the end of the task title with “(Delete when complete)” so I know to delete the task instead of check it off when I’m done with it. That will keep it from repeating when it’s done and allow the project to move on.</p>

<p><strong>x5tom = “5am tomorrow”</strong></p>

<p>Occasionally, I need to push a task off until tomorrow. When I do, I use this in the Defer Date field to push it out one day. I could hit the “+1 day” button but this is habit.</p>

<p>Overall, this is extremely basic compared to what is possible. But this does all I need,  there’s no point overcomplicating it.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>