<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:52:16 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[20: Code Freeze]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/20/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[discussions]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/20/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[My Dvorak typing speed is picking up and I’ll be launching a new discussion in two days. Once that’s out, I’ll be going on a code freeze.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Code-Freeze.jpg" /><p>My Dvorak typing speed is picking up and I’ll be launching a new discussion in two days. Once that’s out, I’ll be going on a code freeze.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak Transition</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/19/">19: Online Discussions</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/">Using Drafts</a></p>

<p><a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.phpbb.com/">phpBB</a></p>

<p><a href="https://discourse.omnigroup.com/">The Omni Group Forums</a></p>

<p><a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a></p>

<p><a href="https://meta.discourse.org/">Discourse Meta</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Just a Laptop]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/just-a-laptop/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/just-a-laptop/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When I started my business I made the shift from three 27” monitors to just a laptop screen. That shift has taught me a few things about how I work.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Just-a-Laptop.jpg" /><p>When I started my business I made the shift from three 27” monitors to just a laptop screen. That shift has taught me a few things about how I work.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="different-modes">Different Modes</h2>

<p>I have different mindsets and needs when I’m doing different types of work. I can listen to upbeat music and kick back on the couch when I’m cycling through email, but I need instrumental, low-key music and my desk when I’m coding. These two examples were the extremes that made me start to pay attention.</p>

<p>Noticing those subtle differences has brought some pretty big gains in productivity. I used to rarely leave my desk because the monitors made it possible to see so much at once. When I only have the laptop screen it forces me to focus and choose the best (or most comfortable) environment.</p>

<h2 id="focus">Focus</h2>

<p>Forcing focus has paid big dividends in my writing. Because I don’t have the ability to see a whole bunch of things at once, I stick to the task in front of me. Since the time I’m most vulnerable to YouTube binges is when I sit down to write, this has paid off. I usually enjoy the process of writing but getting started is hard when there’s a Twitter feed staring at me from the corner.</p>

<h2 id="development">Development</h2>

<p>One area that has suffered is coding. It’s not uncommon for me to have three browsers open, multiple instances of Sublime Text, and multiple terminal windows running all at once. The ease of seeing a bunch of those at once is extremely helpful and allows me to work much more quickly and efficiently.</p>

<p>This isn’t my forever setup, but it is good for me to appreciate the advantages and acknowledge the limitations of working from “just a laptop.”</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dictating vs Typing]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/dictating-vs-typing/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[dictation]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/dictating-vs-typing/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Dictation is becoming more and more commonplace, and as the software behind it continues to get better we’ll likely see it become a bigger part of our daily lives.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Dictating-vs-Typing.jpg" /><p>Dictation is becoming more and more commonplace, and as the software behind it continues to get better we’ll likely see it become a bigger part of our daily lives.
<!--more--></p>

<p>It takes some practice, but once you understand the mechanics, dictating can increase your time efficiency. From texting to getting the latest Chiefs scores, there are endless uses for the technology. I use Siri a fair amount and now that “Hey Siri” is wireless in the iPhone 6S, I’ve found my use cases increasing.</p>

<p>Because of Siri’s current accuracy, I decided to dictate the first draft of <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/"><em>Working with OmniFocus</em></a>. I knew that I could get the ideas out of my mind much faster if I were able to simply speak them.</p>

<p>It was great. I plugged in my podcasting mic, turned on dictation, and went to town. I could draft an entire chapter in about 90 minutes. In 6 days I had finished the entire first draft. It felt awesome to be able to do so much in so little time.</p>

<p>When I reflected on that process I realized that I spent a lot of time trying to find the specific words I wanted instead of working to get the ideas out of my head. I was able to input the words so quickly that I had a hard time coming up with the words I wanted. This by itself really isn’t a big deal, but it meant that I needed to find a way to pre-process my thoughts ahead of time.  In the end I spent an hour writing or typing my notes for each chapter before I dictated them, so there wasn’t much for time savings.</p>

<p>Since the dictation wasn’t 100% perfect, I spent quite a bit of time deciphering my original intent when editing. Not only was I trying to improve the sentences and paragraphs, but the words themselves were so far off at times that I couldn’t figure out what I was talking about and ended up rewriting the whole thing anyway.</p>

<p>More practice would likely improve my dictation, but the slower pace of typing gives me time to process my thoughts more clearly and reduce editing later. It helps me gain clarity faster and spend more time refining the ideas than the process. I will continue to use dictation for smaller chunks, but in my case anything long-form is better suited to typing.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[19: Online Discussions]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/19/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[discussions]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[masterminds]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/19/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m looking for a good way to promote online discussions. I share my idea about it and give an update on Dvorak. And what about masterminds?

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Online-Discussions.jpg" /><p>I’m looking for a good way to promote online discussions. I share my idea about it and give an update on Dvorak. And what about masterminds?
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/">/r/joebuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/newsletter/">Newsletter</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a></p>

<p><a href="https://thefocuscourse.com/">The Focus Course</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/">Dvorak Transition</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Mac Navigation]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/mac-navigation/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[alfred]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/mac-navigation/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Nerdy Mac users are known for customizing their machines. Between keyboard shortcuts, Spaces, and third-party apps, you can effectively set up a computer that is perfect for you and unusable by someone else.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Mac-Navigation.jpg" /><p>Nerdy Mac users are known for customizing their machines. Between keyboard shortcuts, Spaces, and third-party apps, you can effectively set up a computer that is perfect for you and unusable by someone else.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But folks don’t typically think about how they move from one application to another. Mission Control or Spaces are the standard solutions. I’ve found that Spaces doesn’t work well because it forces me to pull my hands from the keyboard to the trackpad. And I can never find the app I want in Mission Control.</p>

<h2 id="hiding">Hiding</h2>

<p>I’ve developed a process of showing and hiding apps, making it possible to immediately switch to the app I want by hiding the one I was just using. I use the built in shortcut Command-H to hide an application from view. It doesn’t close the application, it just moves it to the background. I can get back to it in a couple ways, by using Spotlight or by clicking on the app icon in the dock.</p>

<h2 id="alfred">Alfred</h2>

<p>But I prefer to use my launcher of choice, <a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred</a>, to bring it back. I can invoke Alfred, type the name of the application I want, and keep moving. To make it even faster, I set up a few shortcuts for commonly used programs so I can go directly to the app I want. For example, I can hit Control-Option-O to pull up OmniFocus. Control-Option-F will open Finder and Control-Option-T opens Sublime Text. They all start with Control-Option to make it easier to remember.</p>

<h2 id="in-practice">In Practice</h2>

<p>Anytime I need a different app, I either type the Alfred shortcut or type the name of the app into Alfred. When I’m done with it, I hide it or repeat the process to open the next one. Just remember to close them when you’re done or your computer will be as slow as a slug.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dvorak Transition]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/dvorak-transition/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve had an interest in the Dvorak keyboard layout for a couple years now. The concept makes sense to me and I’m finally doing something about it.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Dvorak-Transition.jpg" /><p>I’ve had an interest in the Dvorak keyboard layout for a couple years now. The concept makes sense to me and I’m finally doing something about it.
<!--more--></p>

<p>For those not familiar with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard">Dvorak</a>, it’s a simplified keyboard layout that is designed to reduce finger motion and errors. And by association, many proponents claim faster typing speed as a result.</p>

<p>I’m very interested in the typing speed claims, but I’m also intrigued by the idea of preemptively combating RSI. I don’t have any major issues right now, but as someone who makes a living by typing I can’t afford long-term degradation.</p>

<p>When it’s all over, I would like to know if the switch was worth it. But measuring finger movements would be pretty difficult. It would require setting up cameras and running the video through a sensing algorithm to determine the distance my fingers travel while typing a lot of text. And since Dvorak is already built to reduce motion, I don’t see the point. I would be trying to prove it was correctly designed. So instead, I’ll be measuring my typing speed to get a comparison.</p>

<p>I’m a data junky and want to make sure I have good numbers. But this case is complicated. I use two different keyboards in two different locations for most of my typing. I use the built-in keyboard in my MacBook Pro (MBP) when I’m writing from the couch and an Apple Wireless Keyboard (AWK) when I’m at my desk. Those scenarios rarely deviate, so I’ll be testing each instance.</p>

<p>I needed a baseline, so I started with the QWERTY keyboard I’m used to and picked four texts from <a href="http://www.typingtest.com/">typingtest.com</a>. I ran two rounds of two minutes from each keyboard/location. I started on the couch with the MBP and did two rounds of two minutes and then moved to my desk for another two rounds.</p>

<p>However, I have one issue with this: timing. I’ve always felt that my speed tends to fluctuate from the morning to the afternoon. I did the initial testing in the morning so I did another round in the afternoon. And because I like be extra sure of things, I repeated the whole process two days in a row. All of this was done from the QWERTY keyboard before switching anything to Dvorak. No need tainting the waters.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>QWERTY</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Day</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Time</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Location</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">WPM</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">74</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">69</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">74</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">67</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">72</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">70</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">71</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">68</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">75</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">73</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">78</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">76</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">73</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">71</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">74</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">72</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>I was surprised to see very little difference between the MBP and the AWK. Overall, my average QWERTY typing speed was 72 wpm. Not bad.</p>

<p>Once I had all of my numbers on QWERTY, I added a <a href="http://kbcovers.com/dvorak-keyboard-cover">keyboard cover</a> to my MBP and switched everything over to Dvorak. I made the switch cold turkey and won’t be trying to maintain QWERTY at the same time. And in the interest of good data, I repeated the entire process above on Dvorak.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Dvorak</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Day</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Time</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Location</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">WPM</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">10</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">12</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">9</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">11</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">13</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">12</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">15</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">16</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">13</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">11</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Morning</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">15</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">17</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Afternoon</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">12</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>I have a long way to go before I reach my initial QWERTY speed. My hope is that going all-in with Dvorak will help me get there quicker. It’s all for the sake of faster and more efficient typing.</p>

<p><strong>Updates:</strong></p>

<p><strong>Day 5:</strong></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Dvorak</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Location</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">WPM</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">22</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">24</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">20</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">23</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">21</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">26</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">22</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">24</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><strong>Day 10:</strong></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Dvorak</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Location</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">WPM</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">31</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">34</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">29</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">35</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">33</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rules of Baseball</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">AWK</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">34</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enchanted Typewriter</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">36</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tigers in the Wild</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">MBP</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">31</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<script src="/assets/js/jquery-tablesorter.js"></script>

<script>
$("table").tablesorter();
</script>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[18: Cold Turkey on QWERTY]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/18/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[dvorak]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/18/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[After an awesome break for Christmas and the New Year, I’m back with a slight change and format to talk about my switch to Dvorak, the bloated web, and resolutions.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Cold-Turkey-on-QWERTY.jpg" /><p>After an awesome break for Christmas and the New Year, I’m back with a slight change and format to talk about my switch to Dvorak, the bloated web, and resolutions.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/2015-by-the-numbers/">2015 by the Numbers</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/joebuhlig/status/683406828286312448">Tweet about Dvorak - Joe Buhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard">Dvorak Simplified Keyboard - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QWERTY">QWERTY - Wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="http://kbcovers.com/dvorak-keyboard-cover">Dvorak Layout Keyboard Cover for Mac Keyboards - KBCovers</a></p>

<p><a href="https://fleksy.com/">Fleksy Keyboard - GIFs, Custom Extensions, and Themes</a></p>

<p><a href="http://idlewords.com/talks/website_obesity.htm">The Website Obesity Crisis</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/gtdguy/status/683413489461903360">Tweet from David Allen</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[2015 by the Numbers]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/2015-by-the-numbers/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/2015-by-the-numbers/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[With 2015 completed, we’ll start seeing numbers roll in summarizing what happened throughout the year. So I thought I would pull together this site’s numbers for 2015. It’s been a ride.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/2015-by-the-Numbers.jpg" /><p>With 2015 completed, we’ll start seeing numbers roll in summarizing what happened throughout the year. So I thought I would pull together this site’s numbers for 2015. It’s been a ride. 
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="top-articles">Top Articles</h2>

<p>This is the most basic form of counting I do: how many views did each article receive? The OmniFocus Setup article has always been my top article, but one of the newcomers is the Monthly Planning article. It made the top 10 in views for the year and it’s only been live for three weeks.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Article</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Pageviews</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Published Date</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-setup-workflow/">OmniFocus Setup and Workflow</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">12,637</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2014-07-14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/evernote-setup-workflow/">Evernote Setup and Workflow</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">3,492</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-01-23</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">Using OmniFocus for Someday/Maybe Lists</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">3,476</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-05-01</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/">Using Drafts</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2,910</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-10-09</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>5. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-auto-parser/">OmniFocus Auto-Parser</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1,613</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-09-04</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>6. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/my-omnifocus-home-screen/">My OmniFocus Home Screen</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1,410</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-06-05</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>7. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/getting-things-done-introduction/">Getting Things Done: Introduction</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1,370</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2014-10-24</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>8. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/a-chaotic-week-with-gtd/">A Chaotic Week with GTD</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1,234</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-05-29</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>9. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/getting-things-done-day-life/">Getting Things Done: A Day In The Life</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1,142</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2014-12-05</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>10. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/monthly-planning/">Monthly Planning</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">831</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-12-14</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="whaddya-know-joe">Whaddya Know Joe?</h2>

<p>One of my goals for 2015 was to step into the podcasting world, and I have been amazed by the number of you who have been listening. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/whaddyaknowjoe/"><em>Whaddya Know Joe?</em></a> has only been public for about five months and it managed to break the 10,000 downloads mark right at the end of December.</p>

<p>Here are the top five episodes by download count:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Episode</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Downloads</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Published Date</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/5/">5: Developing a Task Management System</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">929</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-09-15</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/11/">11: Using Evernote for GTD</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">813</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-10-27</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/12/">12: The Higher Horizons</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">767</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-11-10</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/9/">9: Really? Journaling?</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">710</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-10-13</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>5. <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/6/">6: Collecting and Storing Research</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">691</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2015-09-22</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="working-with-omnifocus">Working with OmniFocus</h2>

<p>This is my favorite accomplishment of 2015. I had been wanting to write a book for a long time but never had the time. It seems that there were a lot of you interested in reading it as well. In two short months, there were 667 copies of <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/"><em>Working with OmniFocus</em></a> sold! I wasn’t expecting anywhere near that number when I started, and I’ve been overwhelmed by the feedback. Thank you.</p>

<h2 id="ha-tech">H&amp;A Tech</h2>

<p>In August, I left the company I was working for and started my own business. It was a fast and unnerving transition, but I’m thrilled to be where I am today. I’m able to work on the projects I love and build things with little or no delay. If I get a crazy idea, I can pursue it without worrying about politics or the red tape of company approvals. I wish I could have done this sooner.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Writing a Book with GitHub]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/writing-a-book-with-github/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[book]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[github]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/writing-a-book-with-github/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[A lot of time and effort go into writing a book. It gets even harder when you need to collaborate with your editor and make revisions.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Writing-a-Book-with-GitHub.jpg" /><p>A lot of time and effort go into writing a book. It gets even harder when you need to collaborate with your editor and make revisions.
<!--more--></p>

<p>All of the edits must be reviewed and approved. Do you keep the change or do you toss it? Multiply this by hundreds of edits (or in my case thousands) and the task is enormous. Even when you think you nailed a paragraph, it can come back shredded (that means it’s better in the end, right?).</p>

<p>When I wrote <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/"><em>Working with OmniFocus</em></a> I used GitHub to manage all of the revisions and help me see the edits. I was doing all of my writing for the blog in Markdown and I didn’t want to change that workflow for the book.  It turned out to be a great choice.</p>

<h2 id="file-layout">File Layout</h2>

<p>I kept the file structure for the book really simple. A single markdown file for the outline and a single file for each chapter. I wrote the first draft for the entire book before I went back to start editing. When I finished editing each chapter I uploaded a copy of it to a DropBox folder I share with my editor. That allowed her to get started while I kept editing the later chapters.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-tiny" src="/assets/posts_extra/Writing a Book with GitHub/file_structure.jpg" /></p>

<p>I created a local git repository on my computer with the GitHub for Mac application. I could do it via command line, but I like the UI that comes with the app. Every time I made edits to the book, I committed the changes to save a history of the work I was doing.</p>

<h2 id="receiving-edits">Receiving Edits</h2>

<p>When my editor finished each chapter, she let me know via email or text. I created a new branch in my local repository that I used to overwrite my version of the chapter with hers. That gave me her edits on my machine with the GitHub application waiting for me to merge those changes. I read through each edit and made decisions.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Writing a Book with GitHub/github_edits.jpg" /></p>

<p>It was simple to see any adds, deletes, or comments that she made. The interface clearly showed what had been done to the file. If I needed to revise what she had done, I could jump over to the file in Sublime Text, make the edits, and save it. When I was done acting on her edits, I committed the changes and then merged them into my master branch in GitHub.</p>

<h2 id="version-history">Version History</h2>

<p>A big benefit of this process is the version history. I can look back on every commit I have made and roll back to that point in time. It keeps each revision and allows me to come back to them as needed. This is a huge load off of my brain. I don’t have to worry about making a change - I know I can always undo it or look back on what I did and see the progression.</p>

<p>I plan to use this method for any books I write in the future. I use GitHub quite a bit, so I’m comfortable with it and it makes the editing process painless. Well, at least logistically.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Trust & Let Loose]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/trust-let-loose/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[systems]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/trust-let-loose/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It takes time to develop consistency in a task management system. I forget. I climb back on the horse, but fall off again. It looks easy - and it is at times - but other times it feels like one more item on my to-do list.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Trust-and-Let-Loose.jpg" /><p>It takes time to develop consistency in a task management system. I forget. I climb back on the horse, but fall off again. It looks easy - and it is at times - but other times it feels like one more item on my to-do list.
<!--more--></p>

<p>All of the apps and systems are nice, but I go through seasons with them. People see my systems and might think I have it all together. I don’t. I forget things all the time. It’s why I gravitate to the structure: it gives me a place to put things so I can come back to them.</p>

<p>There are times when I fail to stick to them. It’s at those times that I drop the ball and miss a deadline, or disappoint my family. It sometimes takes a painful reminder to push me back into the lists. I know I can trust them, but I don’t always.</p>

<p>But the time I spend away from them is continually growing shorter. I climb back into the cockpit more quickly each time. If I continue to collect my thoughts and do something about them, I know they’re taken care of. I know that I can go play with my girls without being concerned about work.</p>

<p>Here is one of the deterrents to GTD: You put a system together, but a big urgent project comes up and you put the structure aside. A month goes by before you notice that thoughts about work are invading your family time and that when you’re at work all you want to do is go home. You come back to the system and start to find clarity again.</p>

<p>It takes time to trust the system in all seasons. I would say it takes years of developing your personal system before you can trust it in every circumstance. This ongoing cycle of leaving and returning builds the trust you need to mentally let go.</p>

<p>Develop a system you can trust and let loose.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[17: Time Off for the Holidays]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/17/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[breaks]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/17/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Take time off this holiday season. And try not to spend too much time doing support for family. Also, don’t miss out on the discount for Working with OmniFocus.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Time-Off-for-the-Holidays.jpg" /><p>Take time off this holiday season. And try not to spend too much time doing support for family. Also, don’t miss out on the discount for <em>Working with OmniFocus</em>.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working with OmniFocus - Use ‘Christmas15’</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Bad Bar Charts]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/bad-bar-charts/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[charts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[data]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/bad-bar-charts/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In previous roles I worked on data analysis and visualization. When you boil it down, that just means I was well versed in Excel and building charts.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Bad-Bar-Charts.jpg" /><p>In previous roles I worked on data analysis and visualization. When you boil it down, that just means I was well versed in Excel and building charts.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I love the challenge of working on a chart until it displays the data honestly. That also means I notice bad designs in charts. There are many ways to skew results with chart design and they all make me see red. If you see a chart with one of these aspects, either ignore it or rebuild it.</p>

<h2 id="non-zero-based-scale">Non-Zero Based Scale</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/nonzero_baseline.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is one of the biggest culprits in bad charts. It’s easy to change the baseline of a chart and make it look like there’s a big difference between two segments. In the chart above, it looks like “Unsure” is drastically overpowering the “Unlikely” category. But if we change the chart to a zero-based axis, we can see that the difference is fairly small.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/zero_baseline.jpg" /></p>

<p>Now it’s a lot harder to see the difference between the categories, but it provides a more accurate picture of what’s going on because the visual matches the real data.</p>

<h2 id="varying-width-bars">Varying Width Bars</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/bar_width.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is more subtle but it can make a big impact on how the outcome is perceived. If you make the already taller bars wider than the others, you increase the visual effect on the viewer and leave them with an exaggerated perception of the data.</p>

<h2 id="unnecessary-lines">Unnecessary Lines</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/extra_lines.jpg" /></p>

<p>In the same way that a non-zero based scale alters the view of the data, a scale that goes too high can also mislead you to thinking there is no difference between two data points. You want the scale to go from zero to the lowest possible number while still allowing room for the entirety of  the bars.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/removed_extra_lines.jpg" /></p>

<p>We can now see that Minnesota has a decent lead on the others. But we couldn’t draw that conclusion until the scale was set appropriately.</p>

<h2 id="inconsistent-scale">Inconsistent scale</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/inconsistent_scale.jpg" /></p>

<p>If you don’t have all the data points (or don’t like them), you either need to forego the chart entirely or be honest. I have seen a similar chart used to show exponential growth of membership when in reality the membership growth rate was fairly consistent. Don’t lie with the data.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/consistent_scale.jpg" /></p>

<p>When you include all of the data points, you can see a big difference. Your perception of the first is that the pace is picking up fast. The second chart shows that the rate of increase is normalized.</p>

<h2 id="d">3D</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Bad Bar Charts/3d.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is just bad design. It’s hard to get a feel for the difference in the bars because our eyes are trying to follow the perceived lines on the chart. And it looks bad. Don’t do it.</p>

<p>Overall, these are really simple fixes. But they can have a major impact on the viewer and how they perceive the data. Don’t lie with a visual. If the data doesn’t show what you want, then you have bigger decisions to make. Get to work and change your methods to get to your desired outcome. Don’t fabricate positive results.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Merry Christmas]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/christmas-2015/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[discounts]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/christmas-2015/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m thrilled to give you a gift for Christmas this year. I’ve wanted to do something like this for a long time and the opportunity is finally here.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Merry-Christmas-2015.jpg" /><p>I’m thrilled to give you a gift for Christmas this year. I’ve wanted to do something like this for a long time and the opportunity is finally here.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I enjoy helping others and I’ve heard from a lot of people that <em>Working with OmniFocus</em> has finally showed them the tools they needed to put their life in perspective. Folks have shared stories about being able to start a business because of the principles shared in the book. One reader found treatment for a serious illness in their child because they were able to work clearly with the doctors. That blows my mind.</p>

<p>If you’ve been on the fence about buying the book, want to give yourself a Christmas present, or know someone who might benefit from reading it, here’s a discount code for you to use when buying <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/"><em>Working with OmniFocus</em></a>. Use the code <code class="highlighter-rouge">Christmas15</code> when filling in your information and it will take $5 off the price. The code will be valid through the day after Christmas.</p>

<p>And if you’re willing, send me your story. I love hearing from you. Merry Christmas!</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[16: Geofenced Lists]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/16/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/16/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Location based lists have a lot of uses. In this episode, I talk about the main ways I use them and how they’ve helped me in the past. There’s also some follow-up to my time tracking mechanism.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Geofenced-Lists.jpg" /><p>Location based lists have a lot of uses. In this episode, I talk about the main ways I use them and how they’ve helped me in the past. There’s also some follow-up to my time tracking mechanism.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig/status/670595803048603648">Tweet about Coffee</a></p>

<p><a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">1Password</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/monthly-planning/">Article on Monthly Planning</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus/">OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="https://todoist.com/">Todoist</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.any.do/">Any.do</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.wunderlist.com/">Wunderlist</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/14/">14: How Much is Down Time Worth?</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/12/">12: The Higher Horizons</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Monthly Planning]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/monthly-planning/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/monthly-planning/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re sneaking up on the annual goal setting push. It’s exciting to sit down and dream about what you want to do next year. But what if your life moves and changes too fast for annual goals?

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Monthly-Planning.jpg" /><p>We’re sneaking up on the annual goal setting push. It’s exciting to sit down and dream about what you want to do next year. But what if your life moves and changes too fast for annual goals?
<!--more--></p>

<p>Setting goals is something <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/an-alternative-to-annual-goals/">I’ve struggled with</a>. And it has generally been instigated by the company I worked for. I went through the typical annual review process when I worked in corporate and at the virtual company I worked for. You find it just about everywhere.</p>

<h2 id="annual-expectation">Annual Expectation</h2>

<p>It always felt like I did it because I <em>should</em>. I even completed a similar process personally because I thought it was the silver bullet to achieving more. I was wrong.</p>

<p>Annual planning doesn’t work for me. That’s one reason I’ve always struggled with it. Putting a plan together for how you’ll build new technology is fun, but often very inaccurate. It moves quickly and you learn a lot in the building process. That typically means that when 12 months have passed, I’ve discovered a new area to work on that is more beneficial or more advantageous. Year-end reviews typically involved a discussion of why I didn’t hit the original goals.</p>

<h2 id="move-to-monthly">Move to Monthly</h2>

<p>12 months is simply too long in my world. So I’ve scaled it back. I still set goals, but I turn those into projects and plan them month by month. And most of those projects are only two or three months long.</p>

<p>Because I can usually see the next two - sometimes three - projects that are coming up, I go ahead and plan those out. I’m only looking at the next seven or eight months at a time, and even those later months will typically change a few times before I complete them.</p>

<h2 id="what-it-looks-like">What It Looks Like</h2>

<p>I keep a simple list of my monthly goals. Each goal is a single line item with a brief description. For the GTD fans, this is synonymous with my 30,000 Horizon of Focus. Here’s what it looks like:</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="/assets/posts_extra/MonthlyPlanning_MonthlyPlan.jpg" /></p>

<p>I have multiple goals per month. I put the name of the month in the title of the task so I can keep them in order, and that’s all it takes for me to stay on track. When I see this list, I know what’s coming up and I can plan my days and weeks appropriately.</p>

<h2 id="working-the-plan">Working The Plan</h2>

<p>A plan is worthless if it isn’t reviewed, so I read each line item once a week and let that dictate what I work on each day. I make sure that I’m on track and that the direction I’ve chosen is still accurate. I don’t get bent out of shape when I change the plan for the next four months; I’m being realistic with myself.</p>

<p>When I’m finished looking over the Monthly Plan, I translate it into a plan for the upcoming week - my Weekly Plan. The Weekly Plan is a simple two or three item list of the things I need to complete next week in order to make progress on the Monthly Plan. It breaks it down into pieces I can digest that week.</p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="/assets/posts_extra/MonthlyPlanning_WeeklyPlan.jpg" /></p>

<h2 id="overkill">Overkill</h2>

<p>I’m terrible at remembering, that’s why I need these systems. This sounds like a lot of work even for me, but here’s the point: 12 months is too far out, and I need guidance. I use this month by month plan to help me decide what to work on each day. It’s a single, uncluttered list that is easily reviewed and updated. I don’t want complicated. I want it to keep my head on straight and help me hit my goals. If it does that, it’s a success.</p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>