<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 07:16:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Generating Creative Energy]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/generating-creative-energy/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/generating-creative-energy/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I had never thought of myself as a creative person until recently. Math and science have always been my strengths, so the arty side never took center stage.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Generating-Creative-Energy.jpg" /><p>I had never thought of myself as a creative person until recently. Math and science have always been my strengths, so the arty side never took center stage.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Then I started this blog. People say that one benefit of writing is a better understanding of your own thoughts. It’s true. I’ve learned a lot about myself since starting to blog, and it’s one of the primary reasons I recommend blogging to others.</p>

<p>But writing on a schedule or regularly creating anything requires a lot of new ideas. When you start, you may have a backlog of these that you’ve been thinking about. But at some point you’ll need more. How do you plan to generate them?</p>

<p>Do a quick search for “releasing creative energy” and you’ll find a lot of articles on how to develop more ideas - going on a walk, meditating, getting outside, drinking coffee, people watching, and so on.</p>

<p>These are great tips to help clear your mind and allow you to find and connect new dots. But I’ve found that there’s more to it than <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/13/">letting my mind wander</a>. Sometimes I need to take action to kick off creativity flow.</p>

<h2 id="check-things-off">Check Things Off</h2>

<p>Think about the most recent big project you completed. What did you do after it was checked off? Celebrate? Take a week off? Lie low for a while?</p>

<p>And how did you feel when it was done? After a big push like I did for <em><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working with OmniFocus</a></em>, I felt a huge weight lift and I started wondering what would come next. I had been working so hard for so long that not having that big project in front of me gave me a sense of freedom and excitement. It released my mind to go on to the next thing, which kicked off creative flow.</p>

<h2 id="analog-brainstorming">Analog Brainstorming</h2>

<p>There’s something about leaving ink on a piece of paper that helps my mind process thoughts more clearly. The process of analog writing is so natural that I can move from one idea to the other with very little friction. Even hitting a keyboard shortcut to add a node to a mindmap can create enough resistance to slow my wandering brain and interfere with the next idea. I have two things to think about - the idea itself and the process of entering that idea. (Talk about high maintenance.)</p>

<p>Between paper and whiteboards, I’m free to roam from one topic or crazy idea to another with zero resistance to connecting the next dot. Writing by hand is natural; when I need an idea for something, I go analog and let my mind meander.</p>

<p>Note: a timer is helpful here. It can eliminate the worry of spending too much time daydreaming.</p>

<h2 id="talk-about-it">Talk About It</h2>

<p>I often forget this step or don’t want to do it, but telling friends about your ideas can spark more ideas. A different perspective on a topic can lead to more connections, developing your idea into something more complete.</p>

<p>I don’t like to do this. What if someone steals my idea? I don’t want something I’ve come up with being taken from me. But I’ve found that rarely happens. If I stick to my trusted circle of mentors and friendships, it’s not an issue.</p>

<h2 id="collect">Collect</h2>

<p>The more inputs and experiences you can bring into your mind, the more points you have to connect. This is partly why going for a walk, getting outside, and watching people can drive new ideas. These experiences provoke your mind to roam and give you new information to connect to your previous ideas and thoughts.</p>

<p>The more information you can collect about your topic and the more experiences you have, the more ingredients you have to formulate and expand your idea.</p>

<p>My goal in all of these scenarios is to <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/getting-things-done-introduction/">free my mind</a> to have ideas. If I’m able to think clearly without worry, I can create more freely.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3veq1r/generating_creative_energy/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[14: How Much is Down Time Worth?]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/14/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[tracking]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/14/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’m starting to track my time. I’ve struggled with this in the past, but now I want to tie it to dollars. I want to know where my time is best spent.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/How-Much-is-Down-Time-Worth.jpg" /><p>I’m starting to track my time. I’ve struggled with this in the past, but now I want to tie it to dollars. I want to know where my time is best spent.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3v4rnv/14_how_much_is_down_time_worth/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.relay.fm/cortex/3">Cortex #3: Good for Brain Health - Relay FM</a></p>

<p><a href="http://contrast.co/launch-center-pro/">Contrast - Launch Center Pro</a></p>

<p><a href="http://programs.clearerthinking.org/what_is_your_time_really_worth_to_you.html">‎Clearer Thinking - What Is Your Time Really Worth To You</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[13: Wandering Brain]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/13/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/13/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have more ideas than I can keep track of. And this is the whole of my creative process from idea development to storage.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Wandering-Brain.jpg" /><p>I have more ideas than I can keep track of. And this is the whole of my creative process from idea development to storage.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3tb6vj/13_wandering_brain/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working with OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-auto-parser/">OmniFocus Auto-Parser</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/6/">6: Collecting and Storing Research</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/">Using Drafts</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">Using Omnifocus for Someday/Maybe Lists</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Breaking the Cycle]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/breaking-the-cycle/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[addiction]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/breaking-the-cycle/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It’s time for a confession: I’m addicted to my phone. I want to check Twitter every five minutes and find myself refreshing Feedly every ten. And I hate it.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Breaking-the-Cycle.jpg" /><p>It’s time for a confession: I’m addicted to my phone. I want to check Twitter every five minutes and find myself refreshing Feedly every ten. And I hate it.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I’ve developed a habit of always wondering if there is something that needs my response. If someone asks me a question on Twitter, I want to get back to them right away. I don’t want them waiting on me. I don’t like being the one that holds up the line.</p>

<h2 id="steps-to-building-a-habit">Steps to building a habit</h2>

<p>There’s a lot of research behind building habits, but it doesn’t have to apply only to good habits. Understanding this cycle can help break bad habits as well. Break one of the steps and the habit stops.</p>

<h3 id="trigger">1. Trigger</h3>

<p>I love helping. Finding ways to solve problems for others will motivate me to work all day, every day. The downside is that I will sometimes go looking for problems that need to be solved. I primarily look for these problems in my own systems and tools, so the trigger is simply wondering if someone found an issue or has a question.</p>

<h3 id="reaction">2. Reaction</h3>

<p>My reaction to this trigger is to solve the problem or look for a problem. Whenever I wonder if there is a problem that needs solved or I think that a question might have popped up, I check the various places where a problem or question could arise. In my case, that’s mostly Twitter, Reddit, or email.</p>

<h3 id="treat">3. Treat</h3>

<p>Much like our dog gets treats when he does a trick, I get a treat when I solve a problem or answer a question. People tend to say thank you or show appreciation when you help out and that small incentive makes me want to keep helping. The trigger has been set off again.</p>

<h2 id="breaking-the-cycle">Breaking the cycle</h2>

<p>Scientists in agriculture have become really good at breaking the life cycle of insects. Whether it’s interrupting their mating season, creating a bad environment for eggs, or not allowing one of the metamorphosis steps, they can find ways to keep the pests from propagating and damaging crops.</p>

<p>It’s this cycle interruption that I’m attempting to put in place. Just telling myself not to  wonder will not likely happen. The thought enters faster than I can stop it, so I need to stop my reaction to the trigger - looking at social media and email. My primary means of checking is my phone and the best way to keep me off my phone is to leave it out of my reach. I’m much too lazy to get up just to check Twitter.</p>

<p>While I’m at work I can keep my phone across the room since I don’t usually check things on my Mac. I can leave it in my office when I go upstairs for lunch. After work, I have designated a place for it to land. If it’s not in my pocket, I’m less likely to get it and check things.</p>

<p>My hope is that by breaking this cycle, I’ll be more present with my family and break the habit. I know that my attention has fallen away from them when they need it. I’m not okay with that.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3snjem/breaking_the_cycle/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

<h3 id="resources">Resources:</h3>

<p><a href="http://jamesclear.com/three-steps-habit-change">The 3 R’s of Habit Change: How To Start New Habits That Actually Stick - James Clear</a></p>

<p><a href="http://shawnblanc.net/2014/11/alternatives-to-the-just-checks/">Alternatives to the Just Checks — Shawn Blanc</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Reviews and Scripting - Learn OmniFocus Webinar]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/reviews-and-scripting-learn-omnifocus-webinar/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[scripting]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/reviews-and-scripting-learn-omnifocus-webinar/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[A great asset behind OmniFocus is the community of people willing to share and ask questions; and one place to enjoy the resources this community creates is at Learn OmniFocus.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Reviews-and-Scripting-Learn-OmniFocus-Webinar.jpg" /><p>A great asset behind OmniFocus is the community of people willing to share and ask questions; and one place to enjoy the resources this community creates is at <a href="http://learnomnifocus.com/?ref=11">Learn OmniFocus</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Tim Stringer, founder of Learn OmniFocus, recently invited me to do a live webinar about my OmniFocus setup on the site and add to this growing repository of content. I was thrilled and  honored to share.</p>

<p>In the recording below you’ll see normal stuff like setting up projects and contexts, but I also emphasize the importance of doing regular reviews and share a script I’ve written to help. I like doing reviews on set days, so I needed to be able to move the Next Review Date of a project to match my scheduled review date. If you’re interested in this script or some of the others I mention in the webinar, you can <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/OFScripts">find them on GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>Outside of <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working with Omnifocus</a>, this is one of the most complete overviews of my entire system. Tim Stringer has generously given me the feed to share with you, so check it out.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3sewyr/reviews_and_scripting_learn_omnifocus_webinar/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

<div class="center video-container">
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/144911621" width="1000" height="560" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[12: The Higher Horizons]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/12/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[horizons]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/12/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[A quick overview of how I see the higher Horizons of GTD and why they are important. Also, I talk about why I think our babysitter is awesome.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/The-Higher-Horizons.jpg" /><p>A quick overview of how I see the higher Horizons of GTD and why they are important. Also, I talk about why I think our babysitter is awesome.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3sa9b1/12_the_higher_horizons/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

<p><a href="http://gettingthingsdone.com/2011/01/the-6-horizons-of-focus/">Getting Things Done® - The 6 Horizons of Focus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://productivity.stackexchange.com/questions/14221/gtd-horizons-of-focus">GTD - Horizons of Focus - Personal Productivity Stack Exchange</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.247inktoner.com/blog/post/2013/08/05/Understanding-GTDs-6-Horizons-of-Focus.aspx">Understanding GTD’s 6 Horizons of Focus - The Spill</a></p>

<p><a href="http://productivityist.com/15000-feet/">15,000 Feet: The Space Between Projects and Areas of Focus and Responsibility - Productivityist</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.degconsulting.net/2014/01/productive-gtd-horizons-of-focus.html">How To Be More Productive By Mastering Your GTD Horizons Of Focus</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Take a Break]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/take-a-break/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/take-a-break/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Numerous times I’ve said that being able to put off work is an important step of being productive. And when you have a big push, it’s even more important to stop.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Take-a-break.jpg" /><p>Numerous times I’ve said that being able to put off work is an important step of being productive. And when you have a big push, it’s even more important to stop.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I’ve been working long hours for the last couple months to make <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/"><em>Working with OmniFocus</em></a> happen. There were late nights, early mornings, and long afternoons. Blood, sweat, tears, sickness and exhaustion all came into play at some point. And I’ve been thrilled at the response.</p>

<p>Many of you have sent me emails and joined the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3rhedi/working_with_omnifocus/">Reddit discussion</a> to let me know what you think of the book. I have received emails from folks who have changed their perspective on how they work and look for better ways to manage their tasks. They are heartfelt and grateful. They drive me to do more and help anywhere I can. It’s these people that keep me excited about the work I do.</p>

<p>And I will continue to look for ways to do that, but not right now. After the hard work that’s gone into this and the unending support that my family has given me over the past months, it’s time to take a short break and give to them. I’ll be back at it next week, but I’m taking a long weekend to recoup.  Thank you for all the great feedback, it’s been a wild ride.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3rr6s0/take_a_break/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Working with OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In the two days before this book launched I checked off 387 tasks in OmniFocus. And there’s no other tool I’d rather do it with.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/base/WorkingWithOmniFocus-Small.png" /><p>In the two days before this book launched I checked off 387 tasks in OmniFocus. And there’s no other tool I’d rather do it with.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="get-working-with-omnifocushttptoolsjoebuhligcomworking-with-omnifocus"><a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Get Working with OmniFocus</a></h2>

<p>It’s been down to the wire, but it’s finally here - <em>Working with OmniFocus</em>. A book that takes you through my entire system. It’s not for someone looking for a how-to manual for OmniFocus, but for those looking to understand the deeper concepts and nuances of the tool.</p>

<p>I’m super excited that it’s finally here! I’ve spent most of my editing time trying to make sure that it’s packed full of details and examples. The more real I can be with you, the better you can understand how it works.</p>

<h2 id="affiliate-sign-uphttptoolsjoebuhligcomaffiliates"><a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/affiliates/">Affiliate Sign Up</a></h2>

<p>If you’ve read the book and want to share it with others, why not make money while you’re at it? You can <a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/affiliates/">sign up</a> to be an affiliate and get paid when others make a purchase using your link.</p>

<h2 id="discuss-the-bookhttpswwwredditcomrjoebuhligcomments3rhediworkingwithomnifocus"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3rhedi/working_with_omnifocus/">Discuss the Book</a></h2>

<p>I made a consolidated place for us to chat about the book. Most of the time that discussion is more helpful in public. And the quickest, easiest way I know to do that is with Reddit. I have a Subreddit (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/">/r/joebuhlig</a>) where I’ve posted the link to the book. Let’s discuss it there - <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3rhedi/working_with_omnifocus/">Reddit Discussion</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Favorite Workflows]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/favorite-workflows/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[setups]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/favorite-workflows/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve received a number of requests for more detail around my use of Workflow (iTunes). I’ve said that it saves time, but here are some details.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Favorite-Workflows.jpg" /><p>I’ve received a number of requests for more detail around my use of <a href="https://workflow.is/">Workflow</a> (<a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/workflow-powerful-automation/id915249334?mt=8&amp;at=1l3vnyQ">iTunes</a>). I’ve said that it saves time, but here are some details.
<!--more--></p>

<p>If I find myself doing something repeatedly, I look for a way to automate it. Since AppleScripting isn’t possible on iOS, I turn to Workflow for some of the same functionality. Here are my heavy hitter workflows.</p>

<h2 id="headed-home">Headed Home</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/efa5488ee8e44687ad75e628a5ba1b1d">Headed Home Workflow</a></p>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Workflow_Headed-Home.png" /></p>

<p>There a quite a few instances each week when I’m out of the house without a specific time that I’m expected to return. My wife often needs to know when I’m headed home so she can plan accordingly. In those cases, I use this workflow to let her know I’m on my way and how long it should be before I get there. This workflow is one of three that I keep in the Today View for easy access because I use it so frequently.</p>

<h2 id="copy-base-url">Copy Base URL</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/1de51ad711624c1daace1159e2abab4e">Copy Base URL Workflow</a></p>

<p>This is a rare case when I introduce more steps to a process in order to get a cleaner result. Many times I need to copy a URL but I really don’t like having extra querystring parameters at the end of the URL. I use this to expand shortened URLS and strip the extra nonsense off the end. Then it’s added to my clipboard.</p>

<h2 id="save-to-dropbox">Save to DropBox</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/db653ceda86942328b802cce58f6b6ed">Save to DropBox Workflow</a></p>

<p>Any time I run across a file (typically a PDF) on my phone that I want to save to DropBox, I use this. I could do the “Open in…” thing, but I know where I want it to go in DropBox before I even start - my DropBox inbox. This workflow takes the file and drops it into my inbox. It’s faster than everything else I’ve tried.</p>

<h2 id="share-title--twitter">Share Title &amp; Twitter</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/44904f69761047ae8fb3d8a741ff08d6">Share Title &amp; Twitter Workflow</a></p>

<p>I have another <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/workflow-to-share-articles-with-twitter-handle/">one similar to this</a> that shares an article with a Twitter handle and asks for a comment about the article. If I don’t have a specific thought about an article but still want to share it, I use this instead. It puts the title of the article in quotes, adds a link to the article, and searches the page for a Twitter handle to include at the end of the tweet.</p>

<h2 id="instatweet">InstaTweet</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/7702a22e5dfe426da5a60f59d519ba10">InstaTweet Workflow</a></p>

<p>When I want to share a photo on Instagram and Twitter I know I can select Twitter from Instagram, but I prefer to embed them directly. This workflow allows me to select the photo, add a caption, and send it both places at once.</p>

<h2 id="article-to-pdf">Article to PDF</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/2ec2ca89dbad4c4db754788f6fccae9d">Article to PDF Workflow</a></p>

<p>This is a small piece of my research storage mechanism. To save an article  for a project I’m working on, I run this workflow which saves it as a PDF in my DropBox inbox. These are processed during my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/gaining-perspective-daily-review/">Daily Review</a> and are often moved to project folders.</p>

<h2 id="take-pic-to-dropbox">Take Pic to DropBox</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/c348878f30b24163afc1d4cbdce15b87">Take Pic to DropBox Workflow</a></p>

<p>This is similar to the Article to PDF workflow, but it opens the camera. I take a picture and it is immediately sent to my DropBox inbox. This is really handy if I want to save a picture of a restaurant menu or a bag of coffee. When I process these, I move them to their respective locations in my file structure for reference.</p>

<h2 id="send-pic-to-dropbox">Send Pic to DropBox</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/ec13b1062c5d47a1813a348ed659c27c">Send Pic to DropBox Workflow</a></p>

<p>Just like the previous workflow, this adds a picture to my DropBox inbox but allows me to select pictures from my photo library. There are times when I remember taking a picture that I want to use for a project. This helps me get them into DropBox quickly and easily.</p>

<h2 id="screenshot-to-dropbox">Screenshot to DropBox</h2>

<p><a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/43d066eb6d194620b1ed4f9134d96810">Screenshot to DropBox Workflow</a></p>

<p>I’m building a lot of websites lately and part of my process involves looking for web design inspiration. This means I’m taking a lot of screenshots of other websites. I keep this workflow in my Today View so I can take the screenshot, swipe down, and send it to DropBox right away.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3qtrfi/favorite_workflows/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[11: Using Evernote for GTD]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/11/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[evernote]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[gtd]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/11/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Before I got into OmniFocus, I used Evernote for GTD. I had a few different structures, but I think I ended with a simple setup that worked well for me before I outgrew it.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-Evernote-for-GTD.jpg" /><p>Before I got into OmniFocus, I used Evernote for GTD. I had a few different structures, but I think I ended with a simple setup that worked well for me before I outgrew it.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/9/">9: Really? Journaling?</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.thesecretweapon.org/">The Secret Weapon - Evernote + GTD</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/toomanyinks/status/653891995308457984">Twitter conversation re: Moleskine</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.penaddict.com/">Brad Dowdy - The Pen Addict</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006CQSRDS">Rhodia Black Webnotebook 5.5 inch x 8.3 inch Dot Grid</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mattvanderpol.com/">Matt Vanderpol - Online Craftsman</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/10/">10: Why I Don’t Use Ads</a></p>

<p><a href="http://decknetwork.net/">A non-tracking solution for running ads - The Deck</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3qej76/11_using_evernote_for_gtd/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Stop Being Productive]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/stop-being-productive/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/stop-being-productive/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[There are a lot of productivity bloggers and podcasters out there. And we’re all looking for ways to get better, faster, and create higher quality products. That’s pretty obvious when you read our articles.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Stop-Being-Productive.jpg" /><p>There are a lot of productivity bloggers and podcasters out there. And we’re all looking for ways to get better, faster, and create higher quality products. That’s pretty obvious when you read our articles.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But if you were able to see my side of the screen you would see my daily fight to be productive. I want to waste a day on YouTube every day. I could do that. I would hate myself for it, but I want to do it anyway. It’s a struggle that I think we all fight at some level.</p>

<p>I review my weekly goals every morning. That’s what matters to me. I want to get my work done so I can spend more time with my family. And I want to spend time on projects that I find important. That single step is easily the most vital component to a productive day for me.</p>

<p>I can do that routine day after day and I <em>will</em> do it day after day. It’s the only way I have a chance of accomplishing anything. And if I’m honest and open with you, I would admit that there are many days I fail.</p>

<p>I have days when I’m doing good to get through my email. I have no idea why, but I  really don’t want to do anything that’s on my lists. I have deadlines coming but I’m doing research for a project that I won’t even consider starting for another year. I’m great at procrastiworking.</p>

<h1 id="but-stop">But stop</h1>

<p>Here’s the thing. We can all find ways to do work in <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/lost-in-transition/">transitional times</a> and maximize every minute of every day in our calendars. But, I’m tired. I just want to blow some time on Twitter. Is that okay?</p>

<p><em>I think that’s perfectly fine</em>. I do it. I don’t recommend doing it a lot and I try to limit the amount of time I blow, but I think it’s important to stop being productive once in a while. Or maybe it’s best to stop being productive multiple times a week or day. It just depends on what you’ve been doing, how tired you are, and how much you have coming up.</p>

<p>I’ve been working really long hours trying to get <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus/">my book</a> finished. It’s tiring and at the end of each day I struggle to think straight. When the girls go down for bed I blow a little time reading articles or cruising Twitter-land. I’m unable to do any work at that time. I don’t even want to look at my lists. I just need to stop.</p>

<h1 id="and-do-what">And do what?</h1>

<p>When you stop, don’t always blow it on YouTube. The number one way I stop is by playing with my girls. They need me more than I need to catch up on Instagram. I try to stop for a while after work every day. I don’t check my lists and I do my best to set my phone down. I’ve been on the computer all day and I have a cycle of catching up on inboxes every 30 minutes or so. When I’ve done that all day my brain expects me to continue feeding it with new things whether I’m working or not. It doesn’t care that I need a break.</p>

<p>But I do care. I don’t want to continue feeding that addiction. It’s hard, but sometimes it’s best to just stop being productive.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3pw5uk/stop_being_productive/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[10: Why I Don't Use Ads]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/10/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[ads]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/10/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I’ve avoided ads in my creative work from the beginning. But there’s a lot of pressure to use them as a way to make an income. In this episode, I explain why I don’t plan to change.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Why-I-Dont-Use-Ads.jpg" /><p>I’ve avoided ads in my creative work from the beginning. But there’s a lot of pressure to use them as a way to make an income. In this episode, I explain why I don’t plan to change.</p>

<!--more-->
<p><a href="http://decknetwork.net/">The DECK</a> - an exception to the tracking ads out there.</p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/">Joe Buhlig - leverage the digital and welcome real life</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a> - use the hashtag #question to ask a question.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3ph51p/10_why_i_dont_use_ads/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[From WordPress and Google to Jekyll and Piwik]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/from-wordpress-google-to-jekyll-piwik/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[jekyll]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[piwik]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/from-wordpress-google-to-jekyll-piwik/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[This website has run on WordPress and Google Analytics from day one and they’ve both treated me pretty well. But I’ve started to see a need for more flexibility in the site, so it’s time for a big change.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/From-Wordpress-Google-to-Jekyll-Piwik.jpg" /><p>This website has run on WordPress and Google Analytics from day one and they’ve both treated me pretty well. But I’ve started to see a need for more flexibility in the site, so it’s time for a big change.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>This is mostly a back-end change that shouldn’t affect the UI much. There are a few small UI changes I’m making, but that’s to make the site cleaner. The more I’ve gotten into web development and design the pickier I’ve become with my site. Ultimately, I’m looking for a simplified user experience for you and more respect for your privacy.</p>

<h2 id="why-wordpress-and-google">Why WordPress and Google?</h2>

<p>For about a year and a half I ran the site on <a href="https://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> through <a href="http://www.bluehost.com/">Bluehost</a> with Google Analytics.  It was easy and quick for me at the time. WordPress has a good, long track record so I fell in line to get my site up quickly. I didn’t want to worry about technicalities - I needed to spend my time creating.</p>

<p>The standard for analytics has been Google Analytics for some time. Google has a reputation for having some of the best if not <em>the</em> best reports and tracking for your website. When I started I knew very little about tracking. I was just looking for a way to see what kind of traffic I was getting and almost everyone recommended GA. Sometimes I’m okay with taking the easy road if it means shipping something quickly. I can evaluate the nuances later. And I can always do the research and migration process after the launch if I need to - which is what I’ve done here.</p>

<h2 id="why-jekyll">Why Jekyll?</h2>

<p>As a replacement for WordPress, I’ve decided to create a static site using <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. I ran across Jekyll through blog posts from <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">Brett Terpstra</a>. I then spent a couple of hours researching and reviewing websites built with Jekyll. I was blown away by the load speeds involved.</p>

<p>I started looking at some of the numbers on my site and found that the average page was loading in about eight seconds. All of the tests I was doing on my machine came in around four seconds, but that didn’t take into account the various devices that people use. That extra four seconds meant my site was way too slow. <em>Eight seconds?</em> Sites built with Jekyll are typically loading in less than one second.</p>

<p>I’ve been wanting to get into Ruby and Rails lately. Since Jekyll is built on Ruby and I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/7/">learn by using a language</a>, it made for a good project. Jekyll seems to be one of the most common static site generators as well. There’s a lot of support and plugins for it already, so I felt comfortable joining that community.</p>

<p>Moving to a static site allows me the flexibility to build one-off pages and posts in a highly customized way. Since I’m becoming more particular about how things look and how you interact with them, it only makes sense. Jekyll seems to fit the bill quite well.</p>

<h2 id="why-piwik">Why Piwik?</h2>

<p>I want to step away from the data collection that Google does on you. I don’t want to share your data against your will and I don’t want to put you into their system simply because you wanted to read my articles. I understand that you might be okay with this, but I’m learning that I’m not necessarily okay with this myself. There’s a big backlash against ads and tracking right now and although I’m not wanting to jump on that bandwagon, it is something that I’ve been thinking a lot about lately.</p>

<p>And although tracking and ads are okay in some scenarios, I’ve found that I’m uneasy about the tracking that goes alongside Google Analytics. That might be unwarranted and unfounded, but I don’t want to leave it when it makes me uncomfortable. A great example of this is <a href="http://www.marco.org/">Marco Arment</a> and his ad-blocking iOS app. He had a great app and it worked well, but it <a href="http://www.marco.org/2015/09/18/just-doesnt-feel-good">didn’t feel right</a> for him. So he pulled it and Apple issued refunds. Google Analytics on this website falls in the same category for me. It might be okay, but I’m not comfortable with it.</p>

<p>I still have a need to understand the analytics for my site so I started looking for alternatives and ran across <a href="http://piwik.org/">Piwik</a>. It allows me to collect the numbers that I’m looking for, but the data stays local. There is no master server that the numbers go back to. Your data never leaves the site. I have a database (that only I have access to) that stores the information and it sits on the same server that this website sits on. The data is anonymous and never goes anywhere. It allows me to get those numbers and not sacrifice your privacy in the process. I think that’s a great trade-off.</p>

<h2 id="hosting">Hosting?</h2>

<p>In the process of making the shift to a static site, I’m also launching a <a href="http://tools.joebuhlig.com/">new sub-domain</a> that will be running on Rails. I was previously running my hosting through Bluehost, but while setting up a Rails application, I found that Bluehost is not very easy to use for anything other than one-click installations. So I’m also moving my host over to <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> (<a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=b0f9f06b6067">affiliate</a>).</p>

<h2 id="when">When?</h2>

<p>Today. I spent the last few weeks working on the static site. There are still some bugs I’m working out, but for the most part it’s all here. Let me know what you think!</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/joebuhlig/comments/3oz7bz/from_wordpress_and_google_to_jekyll_and_piwik/">Discuss this on Reddit.</a></p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[9: Really? Journaling?]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/9/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[journaling]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/9/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I can’t believe I’ve started journaling every day. I’ve always equated journaling with writing in a diary, which is not for me. But the effects of not journaling caught me off-guard.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Really-Journaling.png" /><p>I can’t believe I’ve started journaling every day. I’ve always equated journaling with writing in a diary, which is not for me. But the effects of not journaling caught me off-guard.</p>

<!--more-->

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Moleskine-Classic-Notebook-Large-Notebooks/dp/8883701127/ref=pd_bxgy_14_img_z">Moleskine Classic Notebook, Large, Ruled, Black, Hard Cover (5 x 8.25)</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lamy-Safari-Fountain-Pen-Charcoal/dp/B0002T401Y">Lamy Safari Fountain Pen - Charcoal - Fine</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a>
Use the hashtag #question to ask a question.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Using Drafts]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[drafts]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[setups]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/using-drafts/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Drafts is one of those apps that I cannot go without. The funny thing is that my tech-resistant wife is now dependent on it as well. And you can be sure that I am pretty excited about her use of it.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Using-Drafts.jpg" /><p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id905337691?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4">Drafts</a> is one of those apps that I cannot go without. The funny thing is that my tech-resistant wife is now dependent on it as well. And you can be sure that I am pretty excited about <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/5/">her use of it</a>.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Drafts can be intimidating if you’re not used to dreaming up ways to connect apps on your phone. So it’s helpful to use other people’s ideas as a baseline for building your own methods. Here are a some of my favorite ways to use Drafts:</p>

<h2 id="omnifocus-with-note">OmniFocus with note</h2>

<p><a href="x-drafts4://x-callback-url/import_action?v=2&amp;tintColor=%5B%0A%20%200.451%2C%0A%20%200.29%2C%0A%20%200.553%0A%5D&amp;shouldConfirm=0&amp;logLevel=1&amp;uuid=BDE52DB2-95AF-4AD4-8734-17068C3E8C9F&amp;disposition=2&amp;actionSteps=%5B%0A%20%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%22urlTemplate%22%20%3A%20%22omnifocus%3A%5C%2F%5C%2F%5C%2Fadd%3Fname%3D%7B%7B%5B%5Btitle%5D%5D%7D%7D%26note%3D%7B%7B%5B%5Bbody%5D%5D%7D%7D%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22encodeTags%22%20%3A%20false%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22actionStepType%22%20%3A%20%22URL%22%0A%20%20%7D%0A%5D&amp;description=First%20line%20saves%20to%20the%20title%20of%20a%20OmniFocus%20task%2C%20while%20the%20rest%20of%20the%20Draft%20is%20added%20to%20Notes%20section.%20The%20original%20draft%20is%20then%20archived%20automatically.%20&amp;modifiedAt=2015-07-20%2012%3A13%3A49%20%2B0000&amp;name=OmniFocus%20with%20Note&amp;iconImageName=action_clipboard">Install OmniFocus with Note Drafts Action</a></p>

<p>My primary use of Drafts is to capture tasks that will end up in OmniFocus. It’s not uncommon to see the Drafts badge at six or higher. Those are typically tasks that will be moved to OmniFocus but I needed to capture them quickly.</p>

<h2 id="save-url-as-pdf-in-dropbox">Save URL as PDF in DropBox</h2>

<p><a href="x-drafts4://x-callback-url/import_action?v=2&amp;tintColor=%5B%0A%0A%5D&amp;shouldConfirm=0&amp;logLevel=1&amp;uuid=D65D2C58-A84A-4517-8015-1BE97D43C6B5&amp;disposition=2&amp;actionSteps=%5B%0A%20%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%22writeType%22%20%3A%20%22create%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22fileTemplate%22%20%3A%20%22%5B%5Bbody%5D%5D%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22actionStepType%22%20%3A%20%22Dropbox%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22folderTemplate%22%20%3A%20%22%5C%2FArticle_Import%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22fileExtTemplate%22%20%3A%20%22txt%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22fileNameTemplate%22%20%3A%20%22%5B%5Btitle%5D%5D%22%0A%20%20%7D%0A%5D&amp;description=&amp;modifiedAt=2015-09-28%2012%3A02%3A35%20%2B0000&amp;name=Save%20URL%20as%20PDF&amp;iconImageName=action_dropbox">Install Save URL as PDF Drafts Action</a></p>

<p>When I run across an article I’m interested in but I’m not sure what I want to do with it I’ll dump it into Drafts. When I’m emptying my Drafts inbox during my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/gaining-perspective-daily-review/">Daily Review</a> and run across one of these that I want to save as research, I use this action. It creates a text file in DropBox with the title of the article as the title of the file and puts the URL in the body of the file. My Mac will then turn that text file into a PDF that I can use for later.</p>

<h2 id="omnifocus-list">OmniFocus list</h2>

<p><a href="x-drafts4://x-callback-url/import_action?v=2&amp;tintColor=%5B%0A%20%200.451%2C%0A%20%200.29%2C%0A%20%200.553%0A%5D&amp;shouldConfirm=0&amp;logLevel=1&amp;uuid=9B95D317-17CC-4336-809D-2410C52B7AF2&amp;disposition=2&amp;actionSteps=%5B%0A%20%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%22listName%22%20%3A%20%22Omnifocus%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22noteDelimiter%22%20%3A%20%22%7C%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22actionStepType%22%20%3A%20%22List%20in%20Reminders%22%0A%20%20%7D%0A%5D&amp;description=&amp;modifiedAt=2015-09-28%2015%3A57%3A57%20%2B0000&amp;name=OmniFocus&amp;iconImageName=action_reminder">Install OmniFocus List Drafts Action</a></p>

<p>Close behind the <em>OmniFocus with Note</em> action is the <em>OmniFocus List</em> action. It works pretty much the same way as the first except I can brain-dump a list of items all at once. Each line in the draft will become a new task in OmniFocus.</p>

<h2 id="today-extension">Today extension</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/Drafts_Today_Clip.png" /></p>

<p>If I run across a quote that I want to embed in a blog post or share with someone, I can copy it and send it Drafts with the “+clip” action in the Today View. It lands in my Drafts inbox for triage later, but sometimes I go and action it right then.</p>

<h2 id="omnifocus-action-key">OmniFocus action key</h2>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-small" src="/assets/posts_extra/OmniFocus_Keyboard_Action.png" /></p>

<p>If I want to be really quick and send ideas to OmniFocus immediately, I can invoke the action key. It sits right on top of the keyboard so as soon as I’m done typing I can hit that to send it to OmniFocus immediately and start typing the next task without any delay. This one feature has me using Drafts for brainstorming sessions.</p>

<h2 id="siri-to-drafts">Siri to Drafts</h2>

<p>I have my default reminders list set to a list called “Drafts.” Drafts is set up to pull items from this list into my Drafts inbox. This allows me to ask Siri to remind me of something and it will automatically end up in my Drafts inbox.</p>

<h2 id="omnifocus-somedaymaybes">OmniFocus Someday/Maybes</h2>

<p>I’ve written about these in the past but I have a dedicated list of actions that take drafts and dump them into Someday/Maybe lists in OmniFocus without the need for any triage in my OmniFocus inbox. You can see how I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/using-omnifocus-for-somedaymaybe-lists/">set up the actions here</a> and how I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/omnifocus-auto-parser/">automatically parse them here</a>.</p>

<p>And because I’m proud of her getting into digital capture methods, here’s the one my wife uses all the time:</p>

<h2 id="email-yourself-a-task">Email yourself a task</h2>

<p><a href="x-drafts4://x-callback-url/import_action?v=2&amp;tintColor=%5B%0A%20%200.031%2C%0A%20%200.455%2C%0A%20%200.627%0A%5D&amp;shouldConfirm=0&amp;logLevel=2&amp;uuid=EA743F3F-8612-4615-88E4-6DAF1E0B344D&amp;disposition=2&amp;actionSteps=%5B%0A%20%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%22sendInBackground%22%20%3A%20true%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22bccRecipientString%22%20%3A%20%22%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22toRecipientString%22%20%3A%20%22example%40example.com%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22subject%22%20%3A%20%22%5B%5Btitle%5D%5D%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22replyTo%22%20%3A%20%22%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22sendAsHTML%22%20%3A%20false%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22sendInBackgroundPrefix%22%20%3A%20%22%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22body%22%20%3A%20%22%5B%5Bbody%5D%5D%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22actionStepType%22%20%3A%20%22Email%22%2C%0A%20%20%20%20%22ccRecipientString%22%20%3A%20%22%22%0A%20%20%7D%0A%5D&amp;description=Open%20Mail.app%20email%20window%20with%20first%20line%20of%20draft%20as%20subject%2C%20and%20the%20remainder%20of%20the%20draft%20as%20the%20body.&amp;modifiedAt=2015-10-08%2015%3A06%3A19%20%2B0000&amp;name=Email%20To%20Do&amp;iconImageName=action_email_filled">Install Email Yourself Drafts Action</a></p>

<p>Becky knows that having items sitting in her email inbox drives her crazy. She doesn’t like seeing new emails that she needs to act on. And she knows that if she emails a task to herself she will move it out of her inbox and into her paper system as soon as possible. Her email inbox is the one digital place that she checks regularly. So it’s nice for her to be able to email tasks to herself since she knows she’ll act on them. She uses drafts with an action key above her keyboard to type the task and immediately send it to her email. This would drive me insane, but it has been very helpful for her.</p>

<p>Ultimately, I use Drafts to get things out of my head. Anytime I see something online or I have an idea, I add it to Drafts first. Sometimes I can make the decision about what I want to do with it right then and will action it off immediately. But most of time I find myself leaving it in Drafts until my <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/gaining-perspective-daily-review/">Daily Review</a>. Drafts is my primary tool for keeping my head clear and my mind focused.</p>

]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>