<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
>

<channel>
<title>Joe Buhlig</title>
<atom:link href="http://joebuhlig.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://joebuhlig.com</link>
<description>leverage the digital and welcome real life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:39:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>http://jekyllrb.com/</generator>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Leaving Pocket For Instapaper]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[instapaper]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[pocket]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I follow specific websites less and less. I’m more inclined to follow people and services on Twitter and Medium that act as sources of curated articles. This gives me the ability to find sites I normally would have glossed over and still read my favorite writers.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/leaving-pocket-for-instapaper.jpeg" /><p>I follow specific websites less and less. I’m more inclined to follow people and services on Twitter and <a href="https://medium.com/@JoeBuhlig">Medium</a> that act as sources of curated articles. This gives me the ability to find sites I normally would have glossed over and still read my favorite writers.
<!--more--></p>

<p>But regardless of where I find these articles, I still need a way to save them for later. I rarely have time to read an article the moment I discover it. In the past I’ve used Pocket, but I have now moved to <a href="https://www.instapaper.com">Instapaper</a>.</p>

<p>Originally, I chose Pocket for its IFTTT integration. I had built a number of recipes that acted on the tagging ability of Pocket. But over time I slowly turned these off one by one, mostly due to my move away from tagging articles.</p>

<p>I still would’ve stayed with Pocket if they had simply left the URLs of the articles alone. When I’m finished with an article, I either archive it or share it. But if you share it through Pocket, they insist on shortening the URL with their custom link. The only way around it that I have found is to have <a href="https://workflow.is/">Workflow</a> expand the the link before sharing. When I see links shared by others, I use the top level domain (TLD) of the link as part of my decision about whether or not I want to read it. So I don’t want my own links preventing that ability.</p>

<p>Coupled with the link shortening is the difficulty in sharing quotes from Pocket. It is similarly complicated to do so without the Pocket custom link. Contrast this with Instapaper, where it works perfectly without the need for Workflow actions to expand the link and format the text. Instapaper uses the link you originally saved and gets out of the way.</p>

<p>The reading experience is also far better on Instapaper. They give a lot of options to customize the reading view. And since these are apps designed for reading, I feel this is paramount. The experience in Pocket is not bad, I simply prefer the environment created and allowed by Instapaper.</p>

<p>When I realized I was no longer using IFTTT with Pocket it gave me the freedom to explore other options. And because I have been watching Instapaper for a long time hoping their IFTTT integration would progress, it was the perfect time to switch. I no longer needed Instapaper to adopt a deeper relationship with IFTTT, so I could make the transition with zero compromises.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Updates For Working With OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/updates-for-working-with-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/updates-for-working-with-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[It’s been about nine months since I released Working With OmniFocus. A lot has happened in that time and my systems around OmniFocus have morphed quite a bit. Throw in a pile of learning accrued from other projects and I have decided to make some significant changes to the book....]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/base/WorkingWithOmniFocus-Small.png" /><p>It’s been about nine months since I released <em>Working With OmniFocus</em>. A lot has happened in that time and my systems around OmniFocus have morphed quite a bit. Throw in a pile of learning accrued from other projects and I have decided to make some significant changes to the book.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="video">Video</h2>

<p>Easily the most prominent change will be the medium through which the content is delivered. Words on page work well, but when software is involved video can be a better route to follow. The ability to visually demonstrate a concept and how it works can dramatically increased the comprehension level of the viewer. So in the near future <em>Working With OmniFocus</em> will no longer be a book, but a repository of over 60 screencasts explaining and visualizing the idea at hand.</p>

<h2 id="location">Location</h2>

<p>I originally built a custom Ruby and Rails application to host the sales page and associated mechanisms for the book. That works well but gets to be a lot of maintenance that I’d rather not have. So <em>Working With OmniFocus</em> is moving to a new home on the web: <a href="https://workingwithomnifocus.com">workingwithomnifocus.com</a>. Obviously, this is currently under development and will continue to change over the next few weeks.</p>

<h2 id="dynamic">Dynamic</h2>

<p>One of the major difficulties in writing a book about software is the static nature of a book compared to the continual development of the software. It makes it difficult to keep the book up to date. By moving to web-based video and breaking the content into smaller pieces, it allows me to tweak the content as the program changes.</p>

<h2 id="pricing">Pricing</h2>

<p>I hate pricing. Throw in discounts, launch promotions, and levels of access and it’s a nightmare to me. I have avoided much of this by sticking with a single price and I’m not leaving that mindset. In this case, the content will be more advanced and have more depth so I know the price will need to increase over the price of the book. I don’t currently have an answer on what it will cost, but I do know that those who have purchased the book (and those who <a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">purchase it before the relaunch</a>) will receive $20 off the videos.</p>

<h2 id="affiliates">Affiliates</h2>

<p>The current affiliate program for the book has been a big success for me and I plan to continue to run one for the videos. But since I’m rebuilding the site, the mechanism will be different and will require you to sign up again for the new program. I know this is inconvenient but it will be better for all of us in the long run.</p>

<h2 id="book">Book?</h2>

<p>I’m not planning to update the book itself and the ability to purchase it by itself will go away. I will, however, make it available to those who purchase the video series with the caveat that my processes mentioned in the book are out of date.</p>

<h2 id="overall">Overall</h2>

<p>I’m really excited about these changes.  I will be able to explain the mindsets and demonstrate the app mechanisms in much more detail than was ever possible through the book. I’m devoting most of my current working time to these edits and plan to deliver it in mid to late August.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[4: The Obstacle Is The Way by Ryan Holiday [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/4-the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/4-the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[We all deal with something painful in our lives. And although they are hard to talk about, it’s these obstacles that strengthen us for the future.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>We all deal with something painful in our lives. And although they are hard to talk about, it’s these obstacles that strengthen us for the future.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[TextExpander And OmniFocus]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/textexpander-and-omnifocus/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[textexpander]]></category>

    <category><![CDATA[omnifocus]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/textexpander-and-omnifocus/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[TextExpander and OmniFocus are two of the first tools I install on any new device, so it’s no surprise that the two work well together. You may expect some kind of Applescripting or shell magic, but I keep this extremely simple and only use true text expansion with OmniFocus. I...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/textexpander-and-omnifocus.jpeg" /><p>TextExpander and OmniFocus are <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/first-apps-on-a-new-mac/">two of the first tools</a> I install on any new device, so it’s no surprise that the two work well together. You may expect some kind of Applescripting or shell magic, but I keep this extremely simple and only use true text expansion with OmniFocus. I run the scripts manually or behind the scenes with Hazel.
<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>xwait = “Waiting for “</strong></p>

<p>This is easily the most commonly used snippet I have for OmniFocus. Any time I need to create a new Waiting For task, I always type <em>xwait</em> and keep going. It’s not a huge savings in one instance but multiply this by the average 20 uses a day and it really adds up.</p>

<p><strong>xresp = “Waiting for response from “</strong></p>

<p>Similar to the first, I use this one a lot. I receive and send a ton of email. Any time I send one that warrants a response, a new task is created and this is where the naming starts.</p>

<p><strong>xplan = “Plan project for “</strong></p>

<p>Most of the time when I decide to take on a new project, I don’t have time right then to plan it out. So I use this to create a task for the planning process.</p>

<p><strong>xpfm = “Plan for meeting re: “</strong></p>

<p>I don’t use this as much as I used to, but this helps me create a new task as a reminder to review meeting materials and get resources together for a call.</p>

<p><strong>xlook = “Look into “</strong></p>

<p>I do a ton of research to help me get better at a project or learn how a new process works. I always start these tasks with “Look into” as an indicator to Google, read, or learn about the item.</p>

<p><strong>xdwc = “ (Delete when complete)”</strong></p>

<p>I stole this one from <a href="http://www.usingomnifocus.com">Kourosh</a>. I sometimes have repeating tasks that are creative in some form or don’t have a clear definition of “completed.” I augment the end of the task title with “(Delete when complete)” so I know to delete the task instead of check it off when I’m done with it. That will keep it from repeating when it’s done and allow the project to move on.</p>

<p><strong>x5tom = “5am tomorrow”</strong></p>

<p>Occasionally, I need to push a task off until tomorrow. When I do, I use this in the Defer Date field to push it out one day. I could hit the “+1 day” button but this is habit.</p>

<p>Overall, this is extremely basic compared to what is possible. But this does all I need,  there’s no point overcomplicating it.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[My Current Home Screen]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/my-current-home-screen/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/my-current-home-screen/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[When I consolidated a handful of my inboxes into my email it made me rethink my home screen. I had previously kept it slim but this takes it a step further and creates significant resistance to activities better left undone.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/my-current-home-screen.png" /><p>When I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-overwhelm-inbox/">consolidated a handful of my inboxes</a> into my email it made me rethink my home screen. I had previously kept it slim but this takes it a step further and creates significant resistance to activities better left undone.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The biggest time wasters on my phone and the ones I have consolidated are social media, RSS feeds, and email. Once those were all funneled into email, they didn’t need to be on my phone at all. That meant Feedly, Google+, Pinterest, and LinkedIn all disappeared.</p>

<p>The big one here was Feedly. I normally used it as a triage tool, sending articles I wanted to read to Pocket. But I’ve always disliked their need to auto-shorten links when I share an article. It was bad enough that I built <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/workflow-to-share-articles-with-twitter-handle/">Workflow actions to overcome it</a>. The main reason I originally used Pocket was the IFTTT integration. This inbox consolidation process made me comb through my recipes and realize I wasn’t using IFTTT with Pocket anymore. I had slowly turned off all the connections with it. Goodbye, Pocket. Hello, <a href="https://www.instapaper.com">Instapaper</a>. I’ve wanted to switch for a while anyway.</p>

<p>Once I deleted a few apps, I started thinking through how I use my phone. If the app isn’t on the front screen, I swipe down and search for it. If I’m going to launch apps with Spotlight, why keep multiple folders of them? I combined them into a single folder in order to bury the apps that are most tempting, but still keep them around for their Share Sheet functions. These are primarily Twitter and Instagram.</p>

<p>I’ve been using my phone this way for about a month now and it has seriously helped me limit my phone usage. It’s geared toward getting work done as opposed to blowing time. If I’m going to blow time, I’m <a href="http://bookworm.fm">better off reading</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[43: Big Project Decisions]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/43/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[projects]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/43/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have a lot going on with a number of new projects taking off. But with new doors opening, a few doors need to be closed.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Big-Project-Decisions.jpg" /><p>I have a lot going on with a number of new projects taking off. But with new doors opening, a few doors need to be closed.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="https://workingwithideas.co/">Working With Ideas</a></p>

<p><a href="http://bookworm.fm/">Bookworm – Podcast Book Club</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bookwormfm">@bookwormfm</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mikeschmitz.me/">Mike Schmitz</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">Working With OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentialism-Disciplined-Pursuit-Greg-Mckeown-ebook/dp/B00G1J1D28/ref=sr_1_1_ha?tag=joebuhlig-20">Essentialism by Greg McKeown</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[3: The War Of Art by Steven Pressfield [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/3-the-war-of-art-by-steven-pressfield/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/3-the-war-of-art-by-steven-pressfield/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Whether it’s writing or building a business, we all struggle to put in the work to create. Mike and Joe discuss going pro with their art and overcoming resistance.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Whether it’s writing or building a business, we all struggle to put in the work to create. Mike and Joe discuss going pro with their art and overcoming resistance.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Working With Ideas: Now Open]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/working-with-ideas-now-open/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[course]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/working-with-ideas-now-open/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Our ability to come up with ideas is like a muscle. If we work on it and develop the right habits, we get stronger and have more options available to us. But it’s difficult to build muscle if you don’t understand “how” the muscle works and the mechanics behind its...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/introducing-working-with-ideas.jpeg" /><p>Our ability to come up with ideas is like a muscle. If we work on it and develop the right habits, we get stronger and have more options available to us. But it’s difficult to build muscle if you don’t understand “how” the muscle works and the mechanics behind its improvement. Getting ideas is challenging until you learn what they are and how they work.
<!--more--></p>

<p>That’s what <a href="https://workingwithideas.co/"><em>Working With Ideas</em></a> is all about: how do you create an idea and what do you do once you have it?  And I’m excited to say <a href="https://workingwithideas.co/"><em>Working With Ideas is now open</em></a>!</p>

<p>For two weeks, the course will be $25 off its regular price, so get in early to take advantage of the launch price. You can learn more and get a free sample by <a href="https://workingwithideas.co/">going to the course homepage</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Mindsets Before Tools]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/mindsets-before-tools/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[mindsets]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/mindsets-before-tools/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Every time I come across an article that compares applications or declares an app to be the best at something, I cringe. Very few of them explain the scenarios necessary to make their conclusion valid.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/mindsets-before-tools.jpeg" /><p>Every time I come across an article that compares applications or declares an app to be the best at something, I cringe. Very few of them explain the scenarios necessary to make their conclusion valid.
<!--more--></p>

<p>We all operate differently, and we all have different skill sets and ways of thinking about the tools we use. We have varying needs and that means there is no absolute on the best tool for a task. This is why I always say, “I don’t know” when asked what task manager you should use. I have no clue what your circumstances are and what you need from a list manager.</p>

<p>This is precisely why many people (myself included) recommend using tools you already know when taking on a habit or system. It eliminates the need to learn a new tool and a new structure at the same time. But it’s more than that. The new structure will push you to develop a new mindset. Over time, you will begin to think about the items within your process in a more nuanced way as your ideas and rationale behind it progress.</p>

<p>Tools can get in the way of developing this nuanced thinking. You may start searching for an app to solve procrastination when you actually need to name your tasks differently. You need to understand yourself, how you operate, and what you need before deciding a new tool is the solution. And you can only take on a new tool successfully when you know what it offers that will suit your mindset. <em>That’s</em> when the articles comparing software are helpful.</p>

<p>It is only when you can sit down and spell out how a new tool will help that you understand your mindset well enough to warrant a potential change.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[2: The Willpower Instinct by Kelly McGonigal [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/2-the-willpower-instinct-by-kelly-mcgonigal/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/2-the-willpower-instinct-by-kelly-mcgonigal/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Whether it’s overcoming an addiction to email or sticking to a diet, The Willpower Instinct is excellent at helping you develop the self-control to accomplish your goals.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Whether it’s overcoming an addiction to email or sticking to a diet, The Willpower Instinct is excellent at helping you develop the self-control to accomplish your goals.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[1: Getting Things Done by David Allen [Bookworm]]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/1-getting-things-done-by-david-allen/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/1-getting-things-done-by-david-allen/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Welcome to Bookworm! To kick things off, we’ve reread a book we both rely on heavily in our lives, Getting Things Done by David Allen. This is the best discussion either of us have had about GTD in a long time.
]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Welcome to Bookworm! To kick things off, we’ve reread a book we both rely on heavily in our lives, Getting Things Done by David Allen. This is the best discussion either of us have had about GTD in a long time.
<!--more--></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[A New Podcast: Bookworm]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/a-new-podcast-bookworm/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[bookworm]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/a-new-podcast-bookworm/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[Almost 2 months ago I embarked on a journey of reading a book every two weeks. Although there are a lot of personal benefits to doing this, it is primarily for a new podcast I’m doing with my good friend, Mike Schmitz.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/bookwormlogo.png" /><p>Almost 2 months ago I embarked on a journey of reading a book every two weeks. Although there are a lot of personal benefits to doing this, it is primarily for a new podcast I’m doing with my good friend, <a href="http://mikeschmitz.me/">Mike Schmitz</a>.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Mike and I have done a couple shows together in the past (<a href="http://www.asianefficiency.com/podcast/057-joe-buhlig/">The Productivity Show</a> and <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/33/">Whaddya Know Joe</a>) and we each independently came to the conclusion that we wanted start a new show together. After a single call, Bookworm was born and recording commenced.</p>

<p>Bookworm is all about taking action on the words we read. Mike and I read a book, then talk about what it means for our lives. We can read all the books in the world but it’s for naught if we don’t do something with that knowledge.</p>

<p>Today we are revealing our work to the world. You can check it out it at <a href="http://bookworm.fm/">bookworm.fm</a> and find it <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/bookworm/id1132102092">on iTunes here</a>. We also have a Twitter handle for the show, <a href="https://twitter.com/bookwormfm">@bookwormfm</a>.</p>

<p>If you are a reader (or you’re not and want a summary), <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/bookworm/id1132102092">subscribe now</a>. We’re super pumped about it and excited to talk books with you!</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[My Podcasting Setup]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/my-podcasting-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[podcasting]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/my-podcasting-setup/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[I have detailed my writing process quite a bit lately, but that made me realize I have never pulled all the pieces of my podcasting setup together. Let’s change that.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/my-podcasting-setup.jpeg" /><p>I have detailed <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/the-science-and-experience-of-analog-writing/">my writing process</a> quite a bit lately, but that made me realize I have never pulled all the pieces of my podcasting setup together. Let’s change that.
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="equipment">Equipment</h2>

<p>I did a lot of research on beginners microphones before I started podcasting and although there are better ones out there, I landed on the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-Podcaster-USB-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B000JM46FY/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Podcaster</a>. I have a dream of upgrading to a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Supercardioid-Condenser-Microphone-Applications/dp/B0002BACBO/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Beta 87</a> at some point, but this does a great job for now. Altogether here’s what I’m using:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-Podcaster-USB-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B000JM46FY/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Podcaster</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/RODE-Swivel-Mount-Studio-Microphone/dp/B001D7UYBO/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Boom Stand</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-PSM-1-Shockmount-Podcaster/dp/B000WA8KYG/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Shockmount</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SM6-Shock-Mount-Integrated-Shield/dp/B004DE1K5S/ref=sr_1_1?tag=joebuhlig-20">Rode Popfilter</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/V-MODA-Crossfade-Over-Ear-Noise-Isolating-Headphone/dp/B003BYRGLI/ref=sr_1_8?tag=joebuhlig-20">V-MODA Crossfade Headphones</a></li>
</ul>

<p><img class="center-image post-image-medium" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts_extra/my-podcasting-setup/rode-podcaster.jpeg" /></p>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>I have been a subscriber to the <a href="http://www.adobe.com/creativecloud.html">Adobe Creative Cloud</a> for a while now and really enjoy the power of their tools. They aren’t for everyone, but if you have access to it <a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/audition.html">Audition CC</a> does a great job of editing and recording. When I’m recording with someone else, I use the traditional set of software that most podcasters use:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/audition.html">Adobe Audition CC</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://mutemymic.com/">MuteMyMic</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.skype.com/en/">Skype</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/">Skype Call Recorder</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="hosting">Hosting</h2>

<p>In my opinion, the gold standard for hosting your files is <a href="https://www.libsyn.com/">Libsyn</a>. It just works and I’ve never had an issue with them. My feed is a custom XML file generated with <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. If you are a Jekyll user and want to run a podcast, you can get the <a href="https://github.com/joebuhlig/Jekyll-Podcast-Feed">source code for this here</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[Time For Books]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/time-for-books/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/time-for-books/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[In order to read a book every two weeks (and sometimes every week) I have had to make reading a practice that is incorporated throughout my day. Having a single time for reading isn’t enough and it has become a ritual I like to incorporate as many places as I...]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/time-for-books.jpeg" /><p>In order to read a book every two weeks (and sometimes every week) I have had to make reading a practice that is incorporated throughout my day. Having a single time for reading isn’t enough and it has become a ritual I like to incorporate as many places as I can.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Each day is different, but I know I can count on a handful of repeated situations that allow me to read consistently.</p>

<h2 id="early-mornings">Early Mornings</h2>

<p>Every morning, I <a href="http://joebuhlig.com/why-getting-up-early/">get up at five</a>, grab a shower, and make a hot breakfast for myself. This early breakfast always consists of two eggs fried in a cast iron skillet and a banana. While the skillet is warming up and the eggs are cooking, I read. When they are finished cooking, I read while I eat. This is easily the most reliable time I have for reading. It’s a relaxed, ritualistic, and energizing time that is perfect for creating motivation for the day ahead.</p>

<h2 id="transitions">Transitions</h2>

<p>Whether it’s a few extra minutes before a meeting or a quick break between tasks, the transitional periods throughout the day serve as excellent times to grab a book. It may only be a single page, but one page here and there can add up quickly. The beauty of reclaiming these transitional times comes from what it replaces: social media and email checks. Instead of losing 10 minutes to cruising Twitter, I finish a chapter in my book.</p>

<h2 id="waiting">Waiting</h2>

<p>I have started taking a book with me whenever I leave the house. I’m early to most meetings and often find myself waiting for others to show up. Having a book with me means I can get a few more pages read instead of perusing blog articles or email on my phone.</p>

<h2 id="eob-ritual">EOB Ritual</h2>

<p>At the end of my workday, I go through an End Of Business ritual that helps me unwind and clear my head for spending time with my family. I have tried various tactics during this time, but I have found that learning is the best at hitting the brakes on my mental race car. And what better way to learn than to read? So I’ve made it a habit of reading for about 15 minutes before calling it a day.</p>

<h2 id="bedtime">Bedtime</h2>

<p>The least reliable of my reading times is likely the most consistent for others. I am sporadic at reading before bed, but it is another time that is easy to take advantage of and turn a few pages in a book.</p>

<h2 id="the-pattern">The Pattern?</h2>

<p>When I reflect on each of these scenarios I notice a recurring theme. In every instance, I have historically focused my eyes on a screen instead of a book. It’s easy to check my phone for a few minutes before bed or while I am eating breakfast. But if I pay attention to how I feel afterwards, I always prefer the feeling of accomplishment after having read a book to the feeling of inadequacy that comes from checking a screen.</p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>

<item>
    <title><![CDATA[42: Deciding On A Medium]]></title>
    <link>http://joebuhlig.com/42/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[joe_buhlig]]></dc:creator>

    <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>


    <category><![CDATA[mediums]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joebuhlig.com/42/</guid>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[If you create content in any form and have dabbled in multiple mediums, you’re left with a decision about which method of consumption is best for the topic you want to present.

]]>
    </description>
    <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<img class="featured-image" src="http://joebuhlig.com/assets/posts/Deciding-On-A-Medium.jpg" /><p>If you create content in any form and have dabbled in multiple mediums, you’re left with a decision about which method of consumption is best for the topic you want to present.
<!--more--></p>

<p><a href="http://joebuhlig.com/patron/">Become a Patron</a></p>

<p><a href="https://tools.joebuhlig.com/working-with-omnifocus/">My Book - Working With OmniFocus</a></p>

<p><a href="http://pre.workingwithideas.co">My Video Course - Working With Ideas</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/whaddyaknowjoe">@WhaddyaKnowJoe</a></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBuhlig">@JoeBuhlig</a></p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/whaddya-know-joe/id1035426948">Subscribe on iTunes</a></p>
]]>
    </content:encoded>
</item>


</channel>

</rss>